Chapter 1338: Insect Ancestor

Among all of the spatial rifts, there was one through which a vast snowfield was visible.

Standing in the snowstorm was a white-haired man with a pair of long feelers on his forehead, and he was barely discernible from the snow around him.

A smile appeared on the man's face as he rose up into the air, following which a burst of indistinct white light erupted out of his hands before surging into the spatial rift.

Immediately thereafter, the burst of white light expanded drastically, forcibly expanding the rift from only dozens of feet in size to over a thousand feet, and the man flew through it into the Extraheavensphere.

In the instant that he did so, a burst of white light appeared over his body to ward off the oncoming spatial storms, and he immediately flew over to the golden beetle before falling to one knee as he greeted in an excited voice, "Shuang Bai welcomes the return of his queen."

As soon as his voice trailed off, a young woman in a white sheer dress stepped out of another spatial rift with several hundred humanoid ant beings behind her.

Outside the spatial rift were countless more humanoid ant soldiers clad in suits of black armor, forming a formidable and well-disciplined army.

"Given how lazy you are, I thought Qing Feng would be the one to get here first, but you've surprised me," the young woman said with a smile as she turned to the white-haired man.

In response, Bai Shuang merely gave a curt nod as he said, "Long time no see, Yi Jiao."

"You're still all by yourself and as cold and unapproachable as ever. Having said that, you've certainly made some significant progress in your cultivation base," Yi Qiu remarked in a surprised manner.

During Qu Lin's battle against the Heavenly Court, most of the eight most powerful subordinates under her command had perished, and she recalled that Shuang Bai had suffered extremely severe injuries at the time.

"I already failed to protect our queen once, so I naturally had to do everything in my power to ensure that I can pull my weight upon her return," Shuang Bai replied.

Right at this moment, a barely audible voice suddenly rang out from Shuang Bai's shoulder.

"How long has it been since we were last together?"

Yi Jiao and Shuang Bai were both quite startled to hear this, but they quickly relaxed once they recognized the voice.

A faint buzzing sound rang out as a tiny cuckoo wasp rose up from Shuang Bai's shoulder, then transformed into a tall man in a suit of azure leather armor.

The man appeared to have been around forty years of age with a head of curly, shoulder-length hair that spilled down behind him in an unkempt fashion. There was a weary look on his face, as well as a messy stubble, giving him the appearance of a hungover drunkard.

His most noteworthy feature was his eyes as there was a circle of golden patterns around each of his pupils, presenting a mesmerizing sight to behold.

The armorclad ant soldiers behind Yi Jiao immediately stepped forward to surround the man, only to be instructed to stand down.

"Looks like you've honed your laws of concealment even further, Qing Feng. Neither of us was able to sense you at all. When did you get here?" Shuang Bai asked.

"I immediately came here after sensing our queen's call," Qing Feng replied.

"Has our queen given you any instructions?" Yi Jiao asked.

"No. She hasn't spoken to me at all since I arrived," Qing Feng replied.

As soon as his voice trailed off, a projection of a woman drifted out of the golden beetle, and it was none other than Jin Tong.

"We pay our respects to the esteemed Insect Ancestor!" Qing Feng's trio exclaimed in an ecstatic manner as they fell to their knees.

"I'm going to attempt to return to my Dao Ancestor status today, and I want all of you to protect me if any enemies of mine choose to attack at this critical juncture," Jin Tong said.

"We will defend you with our lives!" the trio replied with ecstatic and determined looks in their eyes.

Jin Tong nodded in response, then faded back into the golden beetle's body.

All of a sudden, the golden light emanating from the golden beetle's body became blindingly bright, and bursts of very special law power fluctuations began to sweep through the surrounding air.

Those law power fluctuations surged into the surrounding spatial rifts, and the spirit insects that were converging from all of the immortal regions instantly erupted into a frenzy, tearing their way out of the spatial rifts with renewed urgency.

At this point, all of the Great Encompassment Stage Gold Devouring Immortals in existence had already been devoured by Jin Tong, so all of the Gold Devouring Beetles that were flying out of the spatial rifts were at the High Zenith Stage or below.

"Xuanyuan Jie's not just going to sit back and watch, so we have to be prepared," Qing Feng said.

"We have to stop him this time, even if it costs us our lives!" Shuang Bai said with a cold look of resolve in his eyes.

"I'll get everyone into formation, you two keep an eye on the spatial rifts to make sure no enemies sneak in," Yi Jiao said.

"I'll go get rid of those pesky Heavenly Devils over there," Qing Feng said as he turned his gaze to the massive, black cloud in the distance, and the weary look on his face abruptly faded away as he spoke, following which he instantly vanished from the spot.

"He's become even more powerful than before," Yi Jiao murmured to herself with a look of mixed emotions in her eyes.

Out of the three of them, she had been the one that had sustained the least severe injuries during the previous showdown against Xuanyuan Jie, yet right now, she also possessed the lowliest cultivation base of the three.

Shuang Bai could see the guilt and dejection in her eyes, and he consoled, "Don't worry about it. You've always been more proficient in the art of formations and arrays, so stick to your strengths."

Yi Jiao nodded in response, then flew up into the air until she was directly in front of the golden beetle, and all of the ant soldiers behind her hurriedly followed along.

After some instructions were issued, all of the ant soldiers dispersed and mingled themselves into the mighty spirit insect army that had gathered around the golden beetle.

Before long, the chaotic insect tide had been organized into groups by Yi Jiao and were standing at attention like a well-trained army.

As more and more spirit insects flew in from the different immortal regions, an enormous spirit insect array began to take shape.

Meanwhile, a cloud of glacial, white mist surged out of Shuang Bai's body in all directions along with his spiritual sense as he kept a close eye on all of the surrounding spatial rifts.

......

As time passed, the insect army became more and more enormous, and all of them either possessed powerful innate abilities or formidable cultivation bases, allowing them to withstand the spatial pressure in the Extraheavensphere to arrive by Jin Tong's side.

Under Yi Jiao's command, all of these insects formed a massive array that resembled a giant scorpion, with one pincer that was white and giving off fearsome glacial qi, while the other was dark green and burning with green flames.

On the tip of the scorpion's raised tail was a curved stinger that was giving off a sharp gleam.

At this point, the golden light around Jin Tong had become so dense and opaque that it was no longer possible to see her within it. The ball of golden light resembled a bright jewel that was sitting on the giant scorpion's back, releasing bursts of formidable suction force in all directions.

Right at this moment, a thunderous sound resembling that of a giant gong being struck rang out from within the ball of light, and a projection of Jin Tong emerged to hover above it.

She began to chant an incantation while spreading her arms open as if she were embracing the world, and a golden vortex appeared in front of her chest before connecting to the ball of golden light down below like a funnel.

Immediately thereafter, the surrounding spatial rifts began to tremble violently, and countless Gold Devouring Beetles came flying out of all of them in a frenzy, forming a series of golden waterfalls that plunged into the vortex.

It was as if an incandescent golden sun had appeared in the Extraheavensphere, illuminating the entire area within a radius of millions of kilometers.

Yi Jiao was standing on the giant scorpion's head, and she turned back to observe this breathtaking spectacle with irrepressible excitement on her face, and she was so moved that tears had even begun welling up in her eyes.

Shuang Bai also appeared beside her from a cloud of white mist, then murmured to himself, "We've waited for what felt like an eternity, but this day has finally come."

Yi Jiao turned to him and asked, "Where's Qing Feng? Is he still not back?"

"Extrarealm Heavenly Devils are not so easy to deal with, but he should be back soon," Shuang Bai replied.

Yi Jiao was just about to respond when she suddenly turned an alarmed gaze toward the largest of the surrounding spatial rifts, while Shuang Bai had already vanished from her side and was racing toward the same spatial rift.

However, before he was able to get there, a mountain that was around a thousand feet tall had already flown out of the rift to appear in the Extraheavensphere.

As opposed to recklessly opposing the oncoming mountain herself, she rose up into the air while instructing the giant scorpion down below to raise its massive pincers in a defensive posture.

Chapter 1339: Insect Army VS Heavenly Court

High up in the sky, Shuang Bai clasped his hands together into a seal before thrusting it toward the mountain.

A cloud of glacial mist took shape before him, then formed a massive, white palm that fell upon the mountain.

A resounding boom rang out as the mountain exploded violently into countless snowflake-like white particles.

However, that was far from the end of the ordeal. All of a sudden, a pair of enormous, green, jade-like hands extended out of the massive spatial rift, gripping onto its edges before forcefully pulling them apart.

A burst of thunderous rumbling rang out as the spatial rift was completely torn apart by the pair of green hands, expanding it into a spatial passageway that was close to a hundred thousand kilometers in size.

Immediately thereafter, a giant head poked its way out of the spatial passageway before looking around, then erupted into booming laughter.

"Found you!"

Immediately thereafter, the enormous figure suddenly pulled back, following which a gargantuan cliff slowly emerged from the spatial passageway.

"Xuanyuan Jie!"

A grim look appeared on Shuang Bai's face as he watched the cliff slowly emerge from the spatial passageway.

It was a long and thin continent that was tens of thousands of kilometers in size and laden with hundreds of thousands of hostile, armorclad Heavenly Court cultivators, led by none other than Xuanyuan Jie.

"Long time no see, Yi Jiao, Shuang Bai. I recall there was a guy called Qing Feng that also survived, wasn't there? Where did he go? I don't think you cowardly little bugs would ever dare to show your faces again," Xuanyuan Jie chuckled.

"Don't get cocky, Xuanyuan Jie! Once our queen returns to her Dao Ancestor status, the Heavenly Court will have one fewer Dao Ancestor!" Yi Jiao yelled.

"What a joke! She couldn't do anything to me even back when she was a Dao Ancestor. Right now, she's not even a Dao Ancestor, so what could she possibly do? I'm going to capture all of you here and present you as a gift during the Bodhi Banquet!" Xuanyuan Jie declared as he cast his gaze toward the ball of golden light that Jin Tong was situated in.

Shuang Bai wasted no time with words as he plummeted toward the cliff like a shooting star.

A layer of blue light emerged over his body, and gusts of fierce wind began howling around him as countless incredibly thin silken threads were sent racing toward the cliff amid a ferocious snowstorm.

In the blink of an eye, the entire cliff was inundated by the massive snowstorm, and countless silken threads within it hurtled directly toward Xuanyuan Jie.

However, before they were able to reach him, a burly man wielding a pair of spears and clad in a suit of silver armor stepped forward to position himself in front of Xuanyuan Jie.

A silver spirit domain erupted out of his body, and a massive, shield-like mirror of silver light appeared within it.

As the snowstorm swept over the silver mirror, a burst of radiant, silver light instantly appeared over its surface, and the snowstorm was reflected, sending it sweeping toward Shuang Bai instead.

A hint of concern flashed through Yi Jiao's eyes as Shuang Bai was inundated by the snowstorm.

The spear-wielding cultivator's name was Yin Wushuang, and he was a peak-Great Encompassment cultivator under Xuanyuan Jie. He was a cultivator of the laws of silver, a branch of metal law powers, and he was a very formidable combatant.

However, right at this moment, a layer of frost suddenly appeared over the silver mirror without any warning, following which it exploded with a loud crack.

Countless silken threads shot out of the flurry of crystalline powder that the mirror had exploded into, intertwining in mid-air to form a white spear that pierced directly toward Yin Wushuang's throat.

A surprised look appeared on his face as he raised one of his spears horizontally to protect himself while thrusting the other one forward.

It looked as if there were nothing directly in front of him, but in the instant that he thrust his spear forward, a dull thud rang out as Shuang Bai abruptly appeared.

Blood was trickling down from the corner of his lips, and the silver spear had already pierced through his chest.

A cold sneer appeared on Yin Wushuang's face upon seeing this, but in the next instant, Shuang Bai's body disintegrated into countless silken threads, and he hadn't been harmed at all.

Yin Wushuang's brows furrowed slightly as a torrent of what appeared to have been molten silver erupted out of his spear, spilling over Shuang Bai's body to instantly encase him and root him to the spot.

However, Shuang Bai remained completely unfazed as he made a hand seal, and countless translucent white threads abruptly shot out from beneath Yin Wushuang's suit of silver armor, instantly tearing his body to shreds.

Having freed himself from Yin Wushuang's entrapment, Shuang Bai immediately released his spirit domain, and a massive, snowy mountain appeared within it in the blink of an eye before crashing down toward the cliff below.

As the snow mountain descended, the snow on its surface came tumbling down upon Xuanyuan Jie in an almighty avalanche.

Shuang Bai was naturally well aware that he was no match for Xuanyuan Jie, and he was only doing this to try and buy as much time for Jin Tong as possible.

Meanwhile, Yin Wushuang's body had disintegrated into a puddle of molten silver that was in the process of reforming.

"Useless!" an azure-robed elderly man standing behind Xuanyuan Jie scoffed upon seeing this, then stepped forward as he swept a sleeve through the air.

The opening of his sleeve instantly swelled several hundredfold in size, and bursts of tremendous suction force erupted out of it to redirect the tumbling avalanche, and after no more than twenty seconds, the avalanche and the entire mountain had been sucked into his sleeve.

Right at this moment, a loud commotion rang out in the distance, and a series of extremely profound, vortex-like patterns began to appear over the ball of golden light on the giant scorpion array's back, while a terrifying, all-devouring aura began to emanate from within.

Yi Jiao was ecstatic to see this, while all of the Heavenly Court cultivators displayed looks of alarm and horror in the face of this terrifying aura.

A grim look appeared on Xuanyuan Jie's face as he ordered, "Everyone, attack at once!"

As soon as his voice trailed off, a burst of white light suddenly appeared over the center of the continent upon which the Heavenly Court cultivators were standing.

Shuang Bai had snuck there unnoticed, and he thrust his palms into the ground as his entire body disintegrated into countless translucent threads that vanished into the earth.

A layer of frost instantly spread the entire continent, and Yi Jiao clasped a hand into a fist in elation upon seeing.

However, the situation quickly took a turn for the worse.

A burst of earthy yellow light rose up over the entire continent alongside a wave of formidable earth law power fluctuations, and the entire continent began to ripple like a wave.

Immediately thereafter, a patch of flat ground at the center of the continent suddenly rose up to form a giant, rocky hand, held within which was none other than Shuang Bai.

"Shuang Bai!" Yi Jiao yelled in an alarmed manner.

Not only was Shuang Bai being held firmly in the rocky hand, his entire body was bound by a series of dark yellow chains that contained formidable earth law powers. They were only around as thick as an infant's arm, but they were as heavy as mountains, rendering him completely immobilized.

At the same time, his law powers were suppressed by this burst of earth law powers, and the layer of frost over the entire continent quickly faded away.

A woman in a purple dress standing behind Xuanyuan Jie took a glance at Yi Jiao, then said, "Leave the rest to us, esteemed patriarch. Yi Jiao on her own isn't enough to pose any threat."

"Make it quick," Xuanyuan Jie said in an expressionless manner.

Yin Wushuang, the azure-robed elderly man, and the woman in the purple dress immediately sprang into action, leading the army of Heavenly Court soldiers on a charge against the insect army.

An anxious look appeared on Yi Jiao's face as she took a glance at the devilish cloud in the distance. Shuang Bai had been captured, while Qing Feng still wasn't back, leaving just her and her scorpion array, which certainly wasn't going to be enough to keep the Heavenly Court's forces at bay.

So be it, I'll just have to resist for as long as I can.

A look of resolve appeared on Yi Jiao's face as she let loose a sharp screech, one that was immediately echoed by the scorpion array behind her.

All the while, the swarms of spirit insects that were still on their way here began to frantically fly into the Extraheavenspehere through the spatial rifts with renewed urgency.

The two fearsome armies clashed violently, and a battle of epic proportions instantly commenced.

The spirit insects held a numbers advantage, but the quality of the Heavenly Court cultivators more than made up for this disadvantage.

Yin Wushuang thrust his spears through the air to release two giant pillars of silver light, instantly killing tens of thousands of spirit insects, while the azure-robed elderly man swept a sleeve through the air to suck in over a hundred thousand spirit insects in the blink of an eye.

Meanwhile, the woman in the purple dress swept a sleeve through the air to conjure up a sea of purple flames, which instantly reduced hundreds of thousands of spirit insects to ashes.

The three of them left the rest of the Heavenly Court cultivators behind as they charged directly toward Jin Tong.

Chapter 1340: I Am Han Li

Yi Jiao had been keenly observing the trio this entire time, and she immediately flew onto the head of the scorpion array, following which her lower body reverted back into its ant queen form before fusing as one with the giant scorpion below.

Specks of light began to rise up from all of the spirit insects in the array, and an almighty aura that transcended beyond the peak-Great Encompassment Stage began to emanate from within.

They were burning through their own life force to provide energy to the array!

Yi Jiao's eyes began to glow with white light, and it seemed that she had completely fused as one with the array, losing her sense of self in the process. With a sweep of her hands, the two scorpion pincers lashed out at once.

A burst of formidable glacial qi swept through the air, instantly sealing the azure-robed elderly man in ice, while a vast wave of green flames surged toward the woman in the purple dress, clashing violently against her wave of purple flames.

The green flames seemed to have possessed some type of sticky quality, quickly fusing as one with the purple flames and devouring them before continuing on toward the woman in the purple dress.

The wall of ice and the sea of flames resembled a pair of impermeable gates that stood before Jin Tong.

Meanwhile, Yin Wushuang was flying through the air from above, and he wisely decided not to try and force his way through after taking a glance at the curved stinger of the giant scorpion down below.

It was clear that the scorpion array was far more powerful than the three of them had anticipated.

Xuanyuan Jie's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this.

He didn't want to have to get involved as using law powers would speed up his assimilation with the Heavenly Dao, but if the battle dragged on for too long and Qu Lin was allowed to recover her status as a Dao Ancestor, then that would make things even more troublesome.

"Get out of the way!" he yelled as he suddenly took a step forward, and a burst of earthy yellow light appeared over his clenched fist before forming an enormous, yellow vortex.

Right at this moment, Qing Feng appeared behind him without any warning with a dark green corkscrew spike in his hands, which he thrust viciously toward the back of Xuanyuan Jie's head.

He had already eradicated the Extrarealm Heavenly Devils in the distance, but he had refrained from scattering the devilish cloud so that he could use it as cover in preparation for this sneak attack.

The corkscrew spike in his hands was his bonded treasure, and it was an extremely rare third tier immortal treasure. If his attack were to land as intended, then he would surely be able to inflict an injury upon Xuanyuan Jie.

However, right at this moment, the yellow vortex around Xuanyuan Jie's fist suddenly vanished, while a metallic gleam appeared over the back of his head.

An alarmed look appeared on Qing Feng's face upon seeing this, and he hurriedly sprang back through the air, abandoning his sneak attack on Xuanyuan Jie as he landed beside the giant, rocky hand that Shuang Bai was trapped in.

With a slash of his corkscrew spike, the law chains around Shuang Bai were severed, following Qing Feng grabbed onto him by the collar and tugged him out of the grasp of the giant hand.

Xuanyuan Jie made no effort to stop him from saving Shuang Bai. Instead, a look of approval appeared on his face as he said, "Your concealment law powers are quite impressive. Even I didn't notice you at first, but your mistake was setting foot on this continent."

A look of realization appeared on Qing Feng's face upon hearing this.

Given his mastery of the laws of concealment, he could remain undetected even by a Dao Ancestor like Xuanyuan Jie as long as he remained in the air, upon but as the Earth Dao Ancestor, it naturally stood to reason that he was able to detect Qing Feng as soon as he set foot on the ground.

Hence, he had no choice but to abandon his plan of assassinating Xuanyuan Jie to rescue Shuang Bai instead.

"I have no time for the two of you now, but once I've killed your master, I can spare your lives and allow you to serve me," Xuanyuan Jie said, then swept a sleeve through the air, and the entire continent instantly began trembling violently as massive waves of yellow earth converged toward Qing Feng and Shuang Bai from all directions.

Even with the wave of earth still thousands of feet away, Qing Feng and Shuang Bai found themselves slowed down significantly by a burst of restrictive force, and they were quickly inundated.

Xuanyuan Jie paid no further heed to them as he turned his attention back to the scorpion array while charging up power in his fist again.

Layers of earthy yellow light that were imbued with tremendous earth law powers began to surface over his upper body, causing the entire surrounding space to tremble.

Immediately thereafter, he let loose a thunderous roar as he thrust his fist forward, and the yellow vortex of earth law powers that had taken shape around his fist instantly swelled to around a hundred times its original size, racing toward Jin Tong as an almighty storm.

All of the Heavenly Court cultivators hurriedly took evasive measures upon seeing this, while the insect army continued to advance, meeting the yellow storm head-on.

In the blink of an eye, millions of spirit insects were erased from existence upon entering the storm.

Shuang Bai and Qing Feng were unable to free themselves from the waves of earth, and their expressions changed drastically upon seeing this.

Yi Jiao was on the receiving end of the attack, so she had a much clearer sense of just how unfathomably fearsome it was, and a sense of despair welled up in her heart as she steeled her resolve in preparation to face the oncoming storm.

A defiant roar erupted from between her lips as the white light in her eyes grew brighter and brighter. She had set her own law powers alight, and all of the spirit insects in the scorpion array were also burning through their life force with renewed urgency.

It was only now that the scorpion array finally displayed its full power, and all of the spirit insects within had already vanished, leaving only specks of bright light in their place.

The azure and white light radiating from the scorpion's pincers also became brighter than ever, and a sea of fire and ice was sent sweeping toward the yellow vortex.

An ear-splitting boom rang out as the opposing bursts of law powers clashed, causing the entire space to warp before collapsing to form a gargantuan black hole, which sucked in all of the white frost and green flames.

In that instant, what little light there was in the Extraheavensphere was devoured by the black hole, plunging the entire surrounding area into absolute darkness.

Only after close to twenty seconds had passed did the black hole gradually fade away, and the veil of darkness was lifted.

At this point, the scorpion array was already nowhere to be seen, and all of the spirit insects within had disintegrated into nothingness. All that remained was Yi Jiao, who was still hovering before Jin Tong with only half of her body intact.

"I did it..." she exclaimed with blood trickling down from the corner of her lips, and in spite of the terrible physical condition that she was in, her eyes were glowing with elation.

However, in the next instant, her elation was dashed as a gargantuan, yellow fist projection erupted out of the space ahead, racing toward her with incredible speed.

She remained where she was, making no effort to take any evasive measures. Seeing as she was unable to protect her master, the only thing that she could do now was perish with her.

Yi Jiao closed her eyes in acceptance of her fate. She had already run away once, and she had no intention of doing it again.

The entire space was beginning to collapse upon itself in layers in the face of the vast sea of earth law powers sweeping through the air, and Qing Feng and Shuang Bai could only look on in despair and desperation from afar.

However, right at this moment, a High Zenith Stage Gold Devouring Immortal suddenly flew out of a spatial rift above Yi Jiao, and sitting on its back was none other than Han Li.

As soon as he arrived in the Extraheavensphere, he immediately sprang up into the air in an agile manner, then descended in front of Yi Jiao before sweeping a sleeve through the air.

A massive projection of his Mantra Treasured Axis instantly took shape, and all of the Time Dao Runes on its surface lit up as it released a huge pillar of light that crashed toward the yellow fist projection.

The two clashed violently, but it was a completely silent clash. It was as if the fist projection had struck a ball of cotton, and even though it hadn't been harmed in the slightest, it was gradually being slowed down somehow.

Immediately thereafter, Han Li released his seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, which plunged tip-first into the giant fist projection like a flight of golden dragons.

An earth-shattering boom rang out as countless arcs of golden lightning exploded in unison, tearing the fist projection into countless pieces.

Yi Jiao's eyes sprang open in astonishment upon sensing this, only to be greeted by the sight of a completely unfamiliar human cultivator.

"Who are you?" Xuanyuan Jie asked, his voice booming from the distant continent.

"I am Han Li!" Han Li declared with his hands clasped behind his back.

As soon as his voice trailed off, the golden axis projection flew back to his side before hovering behind him, while his seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords circled around him in a protective formation.

"Han Li? What a pleasant surprise! I'm not sure if I should praise you for your courage or denounce you for your stupidity!" Xuanyuan Jie harrumphed coldly.

Clearly, he was already aware of Han Li's existence.

"You're Xuanyuan Jie, right? You were the one who forced Jin Tong to scatter her own body all those years ago, is that right?" Han Li asked.

Chapter 1341: Power of the Great Dao

"Jin Tong? You mean Qu Lin? Who is she to you?" Xuanyuan Jie asked in a surprised manner.

"She is my spirit pet," Han Li replied.

"How dare you refer to our Insect Ancestor as your spirit pet!" Yi Jiao immediately protested in a furious manner.

"Cut the chit-chat and focus on your own recovery. I can only handle Xuanyuan Jie, so you'll have to keep all of the other Heavenly Court cultivators at bay," Han Li said.

Yi Jiao was rendered speechless as she detected the rising aura emanating from Han Li's body.

Who is he? How could he possess such formidable time law power fluctuations?

"Forget it, I don't even know why I bothered to ask. In any case, now that you're here, I'll just have to get rid of you as well as a little added bonus," Xuanyuan Jie sneered.

Han Li offered no response as he swept a sleeve through the air, conjuring a giant time spirit domain that encompassed the entire surrounding area in a radius of hundreds of thousands of kilometers.

All of the Heavenly Court cultivators were instantly slowed down to a crawl.

In addition to Yin Wushuang's trio, there was a small handful of them that were still able to move relatively freely, but they were also far slower than before.

Xuanyuan Jie maintained an expressionless facade, but internally, he was stunned by Han Li's power.

What the hell is Gu Huojin doing, allowing this bastard to cultivate the laws of time to this extent?

Additionally, this only made him more determined to kill Han Li here.

With a sweep of his sleeve, the entire floating continent began to race toward Han Li like a battleship.

In response, Han Li made a hand seal, and his seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords immediately shot forth toward Xuanyuan Jie as streaks of swordlight.

Xuanyuan Jie brought his palms together before thrusting them forward, and two bursts of yellow light appeared before him. In the instant that all of the flying swords pierced into the yellow light, they were immediately diverted away, as if they had just slid over a smooth, icy surface.

All of a sudden, Han Li launched himself toward Xuanyuan Jie at an extraordinary speed, enhanced by his Reversal True Axis ability.

Xuanyuan Jie was ecstatic to see this. A direct clash played right into his hands, and he was more than happy to see Han Li trying to fight fire with fire.

However, in the instant that the two of them were about to clash, a flurry of lightning suddenly flashed over Han Li's body, and he instantly vanished from the spot.

In the next instant, he abruptly reappeared, standing atop one of the Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords that had just been diverted away by Xuanyuan Jie earlier.

Xuanyuan Jie immediately swung around as a wary look surfaced in his eyes.

He could tell that Han Li seemed to have just employed some type of instantaneous teleportation ability that was related to his flying swords, rather than through using his time law powers.

Upon arriving on the continent behind Xuanyuan Jie, Han Li joined his middle and index fingers before slashing them through the air, and a burst of golden light that was imbued with time law powers instantly swept through the air, forming a golden wave that swept over most of the continent.

The waves of earth surging over the continent were instantly suppressed by this burst of time law powers, allowing Shuang Bai and Qing Feng to free themselves.

"Go and protect Qu Lin. Leave Xuanyuan Jie to me," Han Li said.

Qing Feng and Shuang Bai exchanged a glance with one another, and they were still a little displeased by Han Li's flippant remark about their Insect Ancestor being a mere spirit pet of his, but given the urgency of the situation, they naturally prioritized Jin Tong's protection first.

With that, the two of them were reunited with Yi Jiao, and fierce battle ensued between them and Yin Wushuang's trio.

As for the rest of the Heavenly Court cultivators, the vast majority of them were still rooted to the spot by Han Li's spirit domain.

"What makes you think a mere Great Encompassment cultivator like yourself can stand up against me?" Xuanyuan Jie scoffed as he swept a sleeve through the air, and a burst of yellow light instantly rose up over the entire continent beneath Han Li's feet.

The yellow light was giving off immense suction force that rooted him firmly to the spot, following which Xuanyuan Jie raised a fist to the heavens before bringing it down in a swift and forceful motion.

A thunderous commotion instantly rang out from deep within the Extraheavensphere, and Han Li looked up to see thousands of asteroids of different sizes crashing down toward him, drawn down by some type of immense power.

The descending asteroids were creating so much friction with the surrounding space that they erupted into crimson flames, resembling a storm of shooting stars under the backdrop of the dark sky.

All of these shooting stars were enhanced by Xuanyuan Jie's earth law powers, granting them tremendous power.

Han Li's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this, and he channeled his Heavenly Baleful Purgatory Arts as all of his profound acupoints lit up, following which he was able to forcibly tug his leg out of the yellow light emanating from the ground below.

Xuanyuan Jie was rather surprised to see this, but he immediately reacted as he joined his palms together.

Two mountains instantly rose up over the floating continent on either side of Han Li, then came rumbling toward him from either side.

Han Li had only just freed one of his legs when he was crushed between the two mountains with a deafening boom, and the entire continent trembled violently as the pair of mountains crumbled in unison.

A look of disappointment appeared in Yi Jiao's eyes upon seeing this.

She didn't know who Han Li was to Jin Tong, but it was clear that he had come to her, and his demise most likely meant that the end was near.

Immediately thereafter, a series of gaping spatial rifts appeared over the sky above the continent, and the storm of asteroids came crashing down amid a thunderous commotion.

The entire continent was inundated by the storm of fiery asteroids, which fell continuously without rest for close to twenty seconds.

After the dust settled, it was revealed that all of the mountains and landmarks on the continent had been razed to the ground, leaving it riddled with countless charred craters, some of which were still alight with scorching flames.

Xuanyuan Jie took a pleased glance at his own handiwork, yet right as he was about to turn his attention to Jin Tong, his gaze suddenly snapped back to the point where the two mountains had previously collided.

The ground there trembled violently as a massive figure slowly stood up from the scorched earth, spreading its six arms to dust itself off before casting its three pairs of eyes toward Xuanyuan Jie.

"That barely tickled. It's time for you to get a taste of my fists now," Han Li's three heads declared in unison as he channeled his Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra while adopting a fist stance, raising his six fists in a menacing display.

At the same time, five different types of time law powers began to rapidly gather around him before fusing together.

Xuanyuan Jie could sense that Han Li was preparing some type of extremely formidable attack, one that he didn't dare to take lightly, and he immediately joined his palms in front of his own chest before closing his eyes.

As soon as he did so, rays of yellow light instantly began to radiate from his entire body before fading away into the surrounding air.

At the same time, he began to give off a very peculiar aura.

Even though his body was still hovering in the same spot as before and was fully visible, Han Li was struck by the false feeling that he wasn't there at all.

This was Xuanyuan Jie's Dao Ancestor Body, a manifestation of his Great Dao.

Is this what happens after one becomes integrated with the Heavenly Dao? Han Li thought to himself with a hint of awe in his eyes.

However, this was not the time to be overawed. The five types of time law powers around him had already fully combined, and a series of black lines had also begun to surface over his body.

All of his time law treasure manifestations appeared on his back, and they were radiating bright, golden light.

With a thunderous roar, Han Li lashed out with his six giant fists in unison, conjuring up countless black and golden fist projections that hurtled through the air.

The barrage of fist projections appeared before Xuanyuan Jie almost instantaneously, but right as they were about to strike him, his eyes abruptly sprang open, and his pupils had disappeared, leaving behind only solid panels of earthy yellow light that appeared a little hollow, but contained boundless power.

"The might of the Great Dao is not something that you can oppose with brute strength alone!" Xuanyuan Jie roared as he slowly thrust a palm forward, and the entire surrounding space instantly shuddered violently.

A vortex emerged over the palm of his hand with boundless yellow light surging out of it, forming a massive, golden wall that was sent racing toward Han Li.

Chapter 1342: Unfazed

Han Li's Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fist struck the golden wall with tremendous power before instantly exploding, sending incredibly fearsome shockwaves sweeping through the air in all directions.

The golden wall shuddered as countless massive cracks appeared over its surface, but it didn't shatter. Instead, it reflected the destructive shockwaves to send them sweeping back at Han Li.

Having just unleashed his Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fist, Han Li wasn't in time to take any evasive measures, and he was sent flying back through the air.

Behind the golden wall, Xuanyuan Jie wasn't faring that well, either. His entire body was basked in the time law power fluctuations from the detonated Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fist, instantly rooting him to the spot as a result.

Right at this moment, the seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords that had made their way behind him at some point transformed into seventy-two delicate, jade-like children that raced through the air on their own to form a sword array.

Immediately thereafter, they reverted back into a series of giant flying swords, each of which was around a thousand feet in length, and a rumbling thunderclap rang out as a gargantuan heavenly gate appeared within the inky darkness.

The heavenly gate was surrounded by constantly churning golden clouds, and even though the gates were tightly shut, there was still an extremely formidable aura of lightning emanating from within.

Yin Wushuang was astonished to see this from afar.

How is this possible? He's a cultivator of time law powers, how is he able to command such formidable lightning law powers solely through the use of a sword array?

Unbeknownst to him, every single one of Han Li's Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Sword was a third tier immortal treasure that had absorbed the law powers of the Lightning Kui's eye.

A third tier immortal treasure was something that was out of reach even for the average Great Encompassment cultivator, so these seventy-two flying swords were the equivalent of seventy-two Great Encompassment cultivators combining their powers in a collaborative effort!

Even as Han Li was still flying back through the air, the heavenly gate slowly opened at his behest, and an almighty waterfall of golden lightning came gushing out from within, while countless lightning wyrms of different colors raced toward the gates with lightning beads clasped in their mouths.

A chorus of deafening thunderclaps rang out as countless gaping spatial rifts appeared in the face of the heavenly gate's unmatched power, and Han Li steadied himself before bringing his hands down in a forceful motion.

The restrictive forces within the heavenly gates instantly faded away, and as a result, the countless lightning wyrms inside were no longer restrained as they came bursting out of the sea of golden lightning in a frenzy.

In the blink of an eye, the entire area was inundated by a vast and fearsome sea of lightning.

"Protect the Insect Ancestor!" Qing Feng yelled, and the three of them immediately disengaged themselves from their battles against Yin Wushuang's trio to rush to Jin Tong's aid.

At this point, the golden vortex around her had already vanished, and there were also no longer any Gold Devouring Beetles flying in through the surrounding spatial rifts, indicating that all of the Gold Devouring Beetles across all of the immortal regions had already returned to her.

However, for some reason, she was still unable to overcome the final hurdle to reclaim her status as a Dao Ancestor.

Meanwhile, Yin Wushuang's trio hurriedly sprang back in retreat, clearly very fearful of the spreading sea of lightning.

All of the Heavenly Court cultivators that were still able to move also fled in all directions in a blind panic, while those who were not so fortunate were quickly inundated.

Countless lightning wyrms of different colors were swimming through the sea of lightning, converging toward Xuanyuan Jie with unstoppable might.

The lightning beads clasped within their mouths were imbued with the purest lightning true intent between heaven and earth, and a look of fierce killing intent flashed through Xuanyuan Jie's eyes upon seeing this.

"If I don't kill you here, you'll surely grow into a threat just as potent as the Reincarnation Palace Master someday!"

As soon as his voice trailed off, he clasped his hands into a seal as he began chanting an incantation.

The entire Extraheavensphere seemed to have begun resonating with Xuanyuan Jie's incantation, and all of the space within a radius of hundreds of thousands of kilometers abruptly fell still for an instant while a burst of loud rumbling rang out from all directions.

Han Li immediately sprang up into the air with an alarmed expression, right as the floating continent beneath him completely exploded, disintegrating into a vast body of earth law powers that came together to form a river of yellow light.

With a swing of Xuanyuan Jie's fist, the entire yellow river was sent sweeping toward the oncoming sea of lightning.

Countless lightning wyrms raced headfirst into the yellow river before exploding into enormous lightning vortexes that erupted in all directions, and the darkness of the Extraheavensphere was illuminated once again.

High up in the sky, lightning vortexes of all types of different colors stirred up the river of earth law powers into a frenzy, while enormous whips of lightning lashed out in all directions, annihilating the surrounding space.

All of the remaining Heavenly Court cultivators hurriedly flew into the spatial rifts that led to the immortal regions for self-preservation.

The shockwaves resulting from this clash were so formidable that even the space around Jin Tong was beginning to shatter, and Yi Jiao's trio had combined their powers to create a spherical light barrier to try and ward off the shockwaves, but the light barrier clearly wasn't going to be able to last much longer, either.

Meanwhile, Han Li abruptly vanished from the spot before reappearing beside one of his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, and with a sweep of his sleeves, all five of his time law treasures flew out of his body.

All of a sudden, an entire world seemed to have taken shape within the Extraheavensphere, complete with celestial bodies and a lush mountain range with a river flowing through it.

The Five Elemental Illusory World had encompassed the entire surrounding space within a radius of millions of kilometers, and the pressure on Yi Jiao's trio was significantly lessened, but the three of them were still supporting the spherical light barrier with all their might, not daring to let their guards down.

"You've successfully infuriated me, Han Li. Let me show you the true might of a Dao Ancestor!" Xuanyuan Jie declared in a rumbling voice that echoed like thunder.

"I look forward to it," Han Li replied with a relaxed smile.

A sense of intense admiration welled up Yi Jiao's heart as she witnessed the faint smile on Han Li's face from afar.

In her eyes, the gulf between a Great Encompassment cultivator and a Dao Ancestor was simply insurmountable, particularly when the Dao Ancestor in question was one that was so formidable that he had even outmatched the Insect Ancestor of old.

Countless years had passed since then, and Xuanyuan Jie's powers had become even more unfathomable.

In Yi Jiao's eyes, Han Li's fate was already sealed from the moment he decided to challenge Xuanyuan Jie, and the fact that he was able to smile in spite of this was a reflection of his courageous heart and noble spirit.

In reality, Han Li's palms were currently sweating profusely.

He was only putting on this composed display in order to further infuriate Xuanyuan Jie as only by bringing out Xuanyuan Jie's full power could he hope to defeat him.

Some time later, the sea of lightning and river of yellow light faded away, leaving behind gaping black holes that refused to close.

Xuanyuan Jie began to advance through the air, and with each step that he took, a wave of golden light would spread beneath his foot, accompanied by a deafening boom.

At this moment, his eyes were completely hollow and devoid of emotion, and two strange-looking runes could be seen within them.

Layers upon layers of energy fluctuations that were invisible to the naked eyes were spreading through the air with every single step, proliferating outward to what appeared to have been infinity and beyond.

Han Li knew that those energy fluctuations were imbued with the true meaning of earth.

In this instant, it was as if Xuanyuan Jie's body had become one with the earth, while his will had become one with the Heavenly Dao.

All of a sudden, Xuanyuan Jie stopped in his tracks, and a burst of immense suction force erupted out of his body, acting upon the entire surrounding Extraheavensphere.

He spread his arms open as a layer of golden light began to ripple over his entire body, and there was no sense of humanity left in his aura. Instead, he resembled an ancient deity that had existed for as long as heaven and earth had been in existence.

However, as opposed to dismay, a hint of excitement appeared in Han Li's eyes upon seeing this.

This is it!

Chapter 1343: Assimilation

All of a sudden, the seventy-two sword spirit children flew back through the air to surround Jin Tong and Yi Jiao's trio at Han Li's behest.

Immediately thereafter, a giant lightning array took shape, and the four of them vanished amid a flash of lightning.

Having teleported them to safety, Han Li sat down in mid-air with his legs crossed, then began channeling his Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra with all his might.

The golden moon above his head was giving off dazzling radiance, while the stars formed by his Time Severing Torch were also eager not to be outshone.

The river of time formed by the Clear Time Vial began to swirl around him, and the mountain range of Illusory Dawn Sand expanded rapidly while the lush forest formed by the Eastern Vicissitudes Divine Tree grew in a frenzy.

The flow of time within Han Li's spirit domain was instantly accelerated by a hundredfold, and as a result, the rate at which earth law powers were surging into Xuanyuan Jie's body from the surrounding space also sped up drastically.

Bursts of dull rumbling began to ring out incessantly from down below, and Han Li looked down to discover that a continent from some immortal region had risen up into the air, passing through the Ethersphere, the Astralsphere, and the Extraheavensphere as it ascended toward Xuanyuan Jie.

As the continent passed through the Ethersphere, countless streaks of light could be seen fleeing from it, but by the time it entered the Astralsphere, those streaks of light had become far sparser and fewer in number.

By the time it entered the Extraheavensphere, the entire continent began to disintegrate just like the floating continent from earlier, leaving behind only a vast body of earth law powers that converged toward Xuanyuan Jie.

As more and more earth law powers gathered around him, his aura became purer and purer, and he strayed further and further away from humanity and closer and closer to the Heavenly Dao.

He began to instinctively resist this influx of power, but his affinity with earth law powers had become so great that it continued to surge into his body irrespective of his wishes.

"Here, have some more!" Han Li roared as he injected his time law powers into his spirit domain with no reservation.

One time law thread after another vanished into thin air, disintegrating into pure time law powers that fused into the surrounding space.

The flow of time was accelerated drastically once again, and in the blink of an eye, all of the earth law powers that had entered Han Li's spirit domain were devoured by Xuanyuan Jie.

Even the countless asteroids within the Extraheavensphere had begun to disintegrate, further contributing to the influx of earth law powers surging into Xuanyuan Jie's body.

Finally, the moment that Han Li had been waiting for arrived.

An all-encompassing vortex with its boundaries completely out of sight appeared behind Xuanyuan Jie. It represented the most essential power of the earth under the heavens, and it flowed out like a hot spring to envelop Xuanyuan Jie.

A hint of clarity finally returned to Xuanyuan Jie's hollow eyes, but it was already too late, and the Heavenly Dao had already begun claiming him.

"Stop!" he yelled in a desperate voice as he tried to struggle free from the gargantuan vortex, but to no avail.

Meanwhile, Han Li was also suffering immensely. He was burning through his time law powers at an alarming rate, and he was already beginning to feel symptoms of severe overexertion.

However, his resolve didn't waver in the slightest.

He knew that this still wasn't enough for Xuanyuan Jie to be assimilated by the Heavenly Dao.

Only by continuing to accelerate the flow of time and exhausting every last ounce of his time law powers was there a sliver of a chance that he could support the Heavenly Dao assimilation process to completion.

"Han Li, your Great Dao conflicts with that of the Time Dao Ancestor, so a showdown between the two of you is inevitable. If you stop now, I can help you!" Xuanyuan Jie desperately implored as a sense of despair began to set in.

"You think I'd believe you?" Han Li scoffed in an emotionless manner.

"No! I can swear an unbreakable vow!" Xuanyuan Jie yelled as the desperation in his voice crescendoed to a peak.

Han Li's resolve wavered for a split second upon hearing this.

If he could have one of the essential five elemental Dao Ancestors on his side, then he would be much better equipped to oppose the Heavenly Court. However, he quickly abandoned this thought as he had no confidence that a vow would be enough to control Dao Ancestor.

Thus, he continued to burn through his own time law powers in order to accelerate Xuanyuan Jie's demise.

Once it became clear to Xuanyuan Jie that Han Li wasn't going to be convinced, his desperate pleas turned to vicious curses, and his despair turned to vindictive joy once he realized that Han Li didn't possess sufficient time law powers to drive him to his doom.

"You can't keep this up for long, Han Li! I'll remain alive as long as I'm not completely assimilated by the Heavenly Dao, and once you've exhausted all of your power, I'll grind your body down bit by bit in the most torturous fashion possible, then use your nascent soul to ignite a soul lamp!"

His deranged voice was echoing throughout the entire Extraheavensphere, but Han Li wasn't even able to make out what he was saying anymore.

He had overexerted himself to such an extent that his vision had turned into a complete blur, and his Five Elemental Illusory World was also on the verge of collapse.

Right at this moment, a voice suddenly rang out within Han Li's consciousness.

"Should I lend you some power?"

"Senior Vial Spirit? No, who are you?" Han Li asked in an alarmed manner.

"I am you, and you are me," the voice replied.

"You're my self corpse soul!" Han Li exclaimed in realization.

Ever since he had reached the pinnacle of the Great Encompassment Stage, he had been searching extensively for his self corpse soul, and with his body pushed to the extreme, it had finally been awakened.

"Are you going to try and claim my body now? Given the current circumstances, even if you manage to take over, you and I will die here anyway," Han Li sighed.

"I have no such intentions. As your self corpse soul, I am more similar to you than any other entity in this world, and your thoughts and intentions mirror my own," the self corpse soul replied.

In the next instant, Han Li felt his completely depleted law power reserves beginning to regenerate, and the self corpse soul really was lending him its power.

In the blink of an eye, Han Li had recovered close to half of his time law powers, but by then, Xuanyuan Jie had already been given a window of respite, during which he was able to forcibly sever his connection with the Heavenly Dao.

At this point, half of his body had already vanished, while the remaining half was beginning to display signs of petrification, leaving him in a state that was only slightly better than that of the Clairvoyance Dao Ancestor, Chen Tuan.

"Han Li!" Xuanyuan Jie roared with intense fury and resentment brewing in his voice.

However, before he had a chance to do anything, a streak of golden light suddenly appeared behind him without any warning.

Within the streak of golden light was Jin Tong's enormous Gold Devouring Beetle form, and she opened her mouth to reveal a huge, golden vortex, emanating from within which were bursts of extremely formidable law power fluctuations.

Xuanyuan Jie immediately attempted to flee in an alarmed manner, but Han Li beat him to the punch, flying over to his side in a flash before slamming a palm down onto the top of his head.

Rays of golden light that were imbued with time law powers surged out of the palm of his hand, instantly stopping Xuanyuan Jie cold in his tracks.

The palm strike itself posed no threat to Xuanyuan Jie, but this split second of immobilization made it impossible for him to escape from Jin Tong, and he was devoured whole in a flash.

"No!"

A thunderous, indignant cry rang out, only to be abruptly cut off as Jin Tong closed her mouth.

A burst of thunderous rumbling then rang out from within her belly, and it seemed as if Xuanyuan Jie were desperately attempting to force his way out, but she remained unfazed as she quickly reverted back to her human form.

She had undergone another drastic transformation since Han Li last saw her, and both her body and aura had become far more mature than before.

There was a calm and composed look on her face, and it was as if there were a pair of swirling vortexes in her eyes, giving off a transcendent aura.

"Your aura..." Han Li began in a concerned manner.

"It's still yet to be consolidated, but it'll stabilize over time," Jin Tong reassured.

"I thought that your ascension to become a Dao Ancestor would be accompanied by some spectacular phenomena, but it's surprisingly peaceful," Han Li remarked.

"Right now, I should be devouring this part of the Extraheavensphere, but I've just devoured Xuanyuan Jie instead, and it's going to take me quite some time to digest his power," Jin Tong explained.

After a brief silence, she continued, "You saved me again."

Han Li's brows furrowed slightly upon hearing this, and he reprimanded, "Why didn't you tell me that you were preparing for a breakthrough? How could you be so reckless?"

Yi Jiao's trio had just arrived on the scene, and they were all stunned to hear this. Never had they heard anyone dare to speak to their Insect Ancestor in such a reprimanding tone.

However, it was clear that the two of them shared quite a close bond, so Yi Jiao's trio decided not to interrupt their reunion, instead sitting down in mid-air with their legs crossed to rest and recuperate.

Jin Tong's brows furrowed slightly as she opened her mouth to say something, but remained silent in the end.

Right at this moment, her expression suddenly changed slightly as she pressed a hand over her own abdomen.

"What's wrong?" Han Li hurriedly asked.

"Xuanyuan Jie is fighting the devouring law powers in my body," Jin Tong replied.

"Do you need my help?" Han Li asked.

"If he were still outside, then perhaps I would struggle a little to deal with him, but now that he's already in my stomach, his demise is only a matter of time. It's just that his essential earth law powers will be a little difficult to deal with," Jin Tong replied.

Han Li took a glance at their surroundings, then said, "Our battle against Xuanyuan Jie has to have already attracted a great deal of attention, so we can't stay here for much longer. Suppress him for now, and I'll take you somewhere else for your seclusion."

Jin Tong hesitated momentarily upon hearing this, then nodded in response.

Han Li flew over to Yi Jiao's trio as he said, "You three can leave as well. I'm going to take Jin Tong somewhere safe to cultivate in seclusion."

Yi Jiao's trio turned to Jin Tong in an inquisitive manner, and only after receiving confirmation that they were to leave did they reluctantly do so.

After that, Han Li recovered his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, then sat down with his legs crossed before taking several pills to aid in his recovery.

Chapter 1344: Inevitable

Inside a floating, golden palace somewhere in the Heavenly Court.

There were countless bursts of energy swirling around the palace, pulverizing everything in the surrounding area to give the entire space a rather ethereal appearance.

The golden palace was very vibrant in color, but it possessed no aura of opulence. Instead, it resembled an antiquated daoist temple.

The palace gates were tightly shut, and dull thumps were ringing out within it incessantly, while the entire palace occasionally trembled, further exacerbating the unrest in the nearby space.

Right at this moment, the commotion in the golden palace abruptly subsided, and its gates swung open as none other than Gu Huojin flew out from within.

Beyond the gates was a vast, golden space with no end in sight, and there also seemed to have been no ground, as if this were someplace in the heavens.

Hovering within the golden space were numerous orbs the size of houses, and they were flashing with lights of different colors as if they were stars in the sky.

The gates quickly swung shut, following which Gu Huojin swept a sleeve through the air to summon a yellow scroll, on each end of which was engraved an ornate, golden dragon.

The pair of miniature dragons sprang to life at his behest, biting onto the two ends of the scroll before unfurling it to reveal a list of names that were giving off lights of different colors and degrees of brightness.

Near the top of the list was a name that had turned completely gray, and it belonged to none other than Xuanyuan Jie.

"Someone has managed to slay Xuanyuan Jie," Gu Huojin remarked to himself as two beams of golden light shot out of his eyes toward Xuanyuan Jie's name on the scroll.

Countless bursts of yellow light instantly descended from the scroll while Xuanyuan Jie's name swelled to countless times its original size to form a spatial passageway.

In the blink of an eye, a vast area was presented to Gu Huojin, and it was the precise area of the Extraheavensphere that Han Li and Jin Tong were situated in.

"Oh? It seems like the Insect Ancestor has already returned, and there's someone else of interest with her as well," Gu Huojin remarked as his gaze fell upon Jin Tong and Han Li.

All of a sudden, Han Li's eyes sprang open as he scoured his gaze over his surroundings, following which he swept both sleeves through the air like lightning.

Ten golden sword projections instantly shot out of his left sleeve at an indescribable speed, looking as if they were capable of transcending time and space as they vanished into thin air.

Meanwhile, a burst of golden light erupted out of his right sleeve to sweep up the nearby Jin Tong.

Right at this moment, the flow of time in the nearby space was cast into a state of complete disarray as a giant golden palm that was dozens of kilometers in size appeared before swooping down upon Han Li and Jin Tong.

A burst of time law powers erupted out of the golden palm, and everything beneath it instantly fell completely still.

Thankfully, Han Li's lightning teleportation allowed him and Jin Tong to flee before the time law powers from the giant palm had a chance to act upon them, and the two of them vanished amid a flash of golden lightning.

The giant, golden palm came crashing down with unmatched power, completely destroying all of the space, time, and matter down below.

Enormous waves of golden light swept through the air in all directions, pulverizing everything in a radius of millions of kilometers, but strangely enough, all of the destruction took place in complete silence.

A golden lightning sword appeared out of thin air above a desert in the primordial land somewhere near the Dragon Abyss Immortal Region.

Immediately thereafter, Han Li and Jin Tong appeared beneath the lightning sword amid a burst of spatial fluctuations.

That was the same palm strike that Master Miro met his demise to. Looks like Gu Huojin is onto me...

Even though Han Li had already anticipated that this day would come, he still couldn't help but feel a little anxious.

However, for some reason, this anxiety was also tinged with a hint of excitement.

"What was that just now?" Jin Tong asked in an alarmed manner.

"It was Gu Huojin. Looks like Xuanyuan Jie's death drew his attention," Han Li replied, and Jin Tong's expression changed slightly upon hearing this.

Standing in front of the golden palace in the Heavenly Court, a surprised look appeared on Gu Huojin's face as he remarked, "That was incredibly fast, not much slower than Shi Kongyu's instantaneous teleportation, in fact."

However, the scene depicted on the yellow scroll then began to rapidly change, and before long, Han Li and Jin Tong's location were revealed once again.

Gu Huojin made a hand seal, then thrust a palm forward.

Meanwhile, Han Li inspected his surroundings momentarily before conjuring up another golden lightning array.

He had made an active effort to erase any residual aura of his and Jin Tong's during his teleportation just now, and he had also teleported the two of them over a vast distance, almost spanning an entire large immortal region, so even Gu Huojin's spiritual sense definitely wouldn't have been able to detect them.

Even so, he still wanted to teleport once more as a safety precaution.

Right at this moment, another giant, golden palm appeared overhead before descending from above, and it was crashing down even faster than the previous one.

A stunned look appeared on Han Li's face upon seeing this, and he hurriedly stowed his flying sword away before unleashing his lightning sword teleportation technique again, allowing him and Jin Tong to get away again just barely in the nick of time.

Immediately thereafter, the two of them appeared beneath another one of his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, this one over a mountain range in the Heavenly River Immortal Region, an immortal region near the Dragon Abyss Immortal Region.

From there, Han Li immediately teleported himself and Jin Tong away once again without pause, and at the same time, he swept a sleeve through the air to release around two dozen Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, all of which vanished into the nearby space.

Han Li and Jin Tong appeared amid a flash of lightning on the edge of the Heavenly River Immortal Region, only for him to immediately teleport them away again.

After around a dozen consecutive bouts of teleportation, the two of them crossed several immortal regions, only stopping upon reaching an immortal region that was filled with decayed earth and nauseating miasma.

Surely this should be far enough, he thought to himself, only for another giant, golden palm to come descending upon him once again, this one even faster than the previous two.

A grim look appeared on Han Li's face as he prepared to teleport away again, only for countless rays of golden light to suddenly appear around him, instantly severing his spiritual connection with all of his flying swords.

An alarmed look appeared on Han Li's face, but he remained composed as he made a rapid string of hand seals, and a wave of golden light surged out of his body, instantly forming a golden spirit domain that was dozens of kilometers in size.

His five time law treasures also appeared within the spirit domain before transforming into a miniature world, and he was only just barely able to do all of this before the golden palm fell upon him from above.

Countless golden ripples were surging out of the giant palm, causing everything in the surrounding area to fall completely still.

Han Li's spirit domain was the only thing that remained unaffected, as if it belonged to a different world.

The golden palm crashed down upon the spirit domain, and the latter trembled violently as it was slammed into the ground like an asteroid.

The entire continent below shattered violently as vast volumes of molten lava came gushing out from underground, and a series of huge cracks appeared over the spirit domain, but it remained stubbornly intact.

Han Li threw up an involuntary mouthful of blood as his spirit domain was crushed into the earth, while a surprised look flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes once again in the Heavenly Court, seemingly taken aback by the fact that his attack had been kept at bay.

With a sweep of his sleeve, a bell-shaped design appeared over the palm of the giant, golden hand, and it instantly swelled to around twice its original size as it closed itself tightly around Han Li's spirit domain, threatening to crush it to a pulp.

The cracks all over the spirit domain instantly began to widen, and Han Li hurriedly scrambled to fortify it.

A resounding boom rang out as a massive, golden heavenly gate appeared within the spirit domain.

During his battle again Feng Qingshui and Chen Ruyan, many innocent lives had been lost as a result of collateral damage, despite his best efforts at preventing such tragedies.

This time, Han Li didn't want to repeat the tragedy, so he refrained from opening heavenly gates connected to other realms and immortal regions to draw upon the time law powers within them.

This act of selfless kindness granted him a burst of invisible, karmic power, and in that instant, he was struck by a sense of enlightenment as the Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra became clearer to him than ever before.

He quickly capitalized on this spark of inspiration as he made a hand seal, and five bursts of golden light emerged from the heavenly gate, corresponding with the five elements of the Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra.

The heavenly gates slowly swung open, and a boundless expanse of golden light surged out from within before fusing with the spirit domain.

This time, the Heavenly Dao was granting even more of its power to Han Li than last time, and the cracks in his spirit domain were instantly stabilized.

Han Li was ecstatic to see this, and the five bursts of golden light shot out of his spirit domain at his behest, then came together to form the Immortal Golden Cloud, which rose up toward the golden palm outside.

At the same time, Jin Tong took on her Gold Devouring Immortal form as she opened her mouth to release countless streaks of translucent, golden light, which came together to form a huge pillar of light that struck the golden hand with tremendous power.

The golden palm was kept at bay by Han Li and Jin Tong's collective power, and as more and more golden light flowed in through the heavenly gate, the cracks in the spirit domain began to rapidly close.

Chapter 1345: Decisive Move

Han Li's mind was racing as he scrambled to think of a way out of this predicament while maintaining his spirit domain.

He was perfectly capable of eradicating the restrictive time law powers in the surrounding area, but his top priority at the moment was to find out how Gu Huojin was able to track him. Otherwise, he would never be able to truly get away.

Given his cautious nature, he was confident that he hadn't left behind anything for Gu Huojin to track him by, and as long as that wasn't the case, then he wasn't the problem.

All of a sudden, a thought occurred to him as he turned to Jin Tong and yelled, "Jin Tong, force out the law powers in your body that belong to Xuanyuan Jie!"

Jin Tong faltered slightly upon hearing this, following which a look of realization flashed through her eyes, and she immediately did as she was told, sitting down with her legs crossed to focus on expelling Xuanyuan Jie's law powers from her body.

Without Jin Tong's help, Han Li was forced to face the full brunt of Gu Huojin's power on his own, and dozens of Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords flew out of his body before scattering themselves all over his spirit domain.

The flying swords transformed into dozens of giant pillars of lightning that propped up the golden hand, and only then was Han Li able to stop it in its descent.

Gu Huojin's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this, yet before he had a chance to do anything, the palace behind him suddenly began trembling and swaying.

A dismayed look appeared on his face as he swept both sleeves through the air, and streaks of golden light appeared around the palace before rapidly intertwining with one another, instantly forming a golden yin yang diagram that encompassed the entire palace.

The tremors running through the palace instantly began to subside, but at the same time, Han Li was also given a brief window of respite.

After taking a moment to catch his breath, he turned his gaze to Jin Tong, and a concerned look quickly appeared in his eyes.

Even though Jin Tong was currently also a Dao Ancestor, her law powers were still inferior to those of a long-established Dao Ancestor like Xuanyuan Jie, so his law powers were proving rather difficult to expel for her.

In order to assist her, Han Li swept a sleeve through the air, and numerous streaks of golden light shot out of his spirit domain before landing on the ground near Jin Tong to form a golden array that was very similar to the Celestial Time Array.

As soon as the array commenced operation, it began resonating with the spirit domain around it, instantly accelerating the flow of time within the array by close to ten thousandfold.

In the Heavenly Court, Gu Huojin continued to make hand seals with one hand to suppress the unrest in the palace while extending the index finger of his other hand to draw a circle, and a massive, golden ring instantly appeared around Han Li's spirit domain.

At the same time, a restrictive band of golden light also appeared around Han Li's waist, and he felt as if an incredibly heavy mountain had fallen upon him, making it almost impossible to move his limbs.

A hint of fury and indignation surfaced in his eyes as he looked up into the sky, and a series of black patterns spread rapidly over his entire body.

In the blink of an eye, he transformed into an almighty devilish deity that stood over a hundred thousand feet tall, with twelve heads and thirty-six arms.

However, the band of golden light refused to relent, and it remained intact as it released bursts of tremendous restrictive force in an attempt to keep the devilish deity contained.

The devilish deity let loose a low roar as the black spirit patterns on its body began to glow with blinding radiance, and bursts of tremendous physical power erupted out of its body alongside incredibly fearsome time law powers.

The golden ring instantly began trembling, and Han Li was able to force it away until a small gap appeared between it and his body.

He immediately pounced on this opportunity as he grabbed onto the ring with all thirty-six of his hands before wrenching it apart forcefully, and the ring was finally overwhelmed as it exploded into countless specks of golden light.

The golden ring around the time spirit domain also quickly dissipated, while Han Li sprang up toward the golden palm above.

A series of golden patterns appeared over his thirty-six arms, and they began glowing intently as all of his time law treasures converged toward him before vanishing into his back, forming five golden designs that were arranged in a circle.

The golden spirit patterns on his arms lit up even further as he lashed out at the golden palm, unleashing thirty-six Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fists at once.

Thirty-six radiant, golden suns appeared beneath the giant palm before exploding violently, sending countless waves of golden light sweeping in all directions as the entire sky collapsed and buckled.

The waves of golden light quickly swept over the entire immortal region, causing several continents to collapse, while boundless volumes of molten lava and dirt erupted into the heavens.

The nearby space also became severely fractured, while Gu Huojin's restrictive time law powers were eradicated.

Han Li immediately prepared to channel his lightning sword teleportation ability upon seeing this, but right at this moment, a massive, golden hand suddenly descended from above, and it was the same one from before, except it had been slightly reduced in size.

A stunned look appeared on Han Li's face upon seeing this. He had retaliated with all his might just now, yet the golden hand had remained largely unaffected.

There was no time for him to teleport himself and Jin Tong away, so he had to abandon his plans and turn his attention back to warding off the golden palm.

Right at this moment, Jin Tong's eyes abruptly sprang open, and she opened her mouth to release a ball of yellow light that contained earth law powers of an unimaginable degree of purity.

The ball of yellow light rose up into the heavens, then dissipated before fusing into the surrounding space, and the golden hand that was swooping down upon Han Li stopped in its tracks, then hesitated momentarily before making a grab for the dissipating yellow light instead.

Han Li faltered slightly upon seeing this, then immediately returned to the task at hand, and he and Jin Tong vanished amid a flash of lighting.

As the two of them reappeared above a lush forest, Han Li could sense that some type of intangible pressure had been lifted from his shoulders when it had previously followed them everywhere they went.

However, as a safety precaution, he teleported several times in succession before finally coming to a rest.

"Looks like we've finally shaken him off," Jin Tong said in a relieved manner, and her relief was very much mirrored by Han Li.

Following that brief clash from earlier, he had come to realize just how massive the gulf in power between him and Gu Huojin was, and he felt very fortunate to have been able to escape safely on this occasion.

"Master, I still need to consolidate my cultivation base, so I want to find a place to cultivate in seclusion before going after Gu Huojin. What about you?" Jin Tong asked.

"There's no need to refer to me as master now that you're a Dao Ancestor. Just refer to me as fellow daoist," Han Li said.

A hesitant look appeared on Jin Tong's face upon hearing this.

"At our cultivation base, what's the point in obsessing over names and titles? Besides, when have I ever truly treated you like a spirit pet?" Han Li asked with a faint smile.

"In that case, please pardon me. What are your plans from here onward, Fellow Daoist Han?" Jin Tong asked with a smile.

"I also plan to go into a bout of seclusion," Han Li replied.

Now that his self corpse soul had emerged, it had to be addressed, and on top of that, Gu Huojin had already set his sights on him, so he had to attain more power in order to better protect himself.

"That's perfect! In that case, we can go into seclusion together, and I'll be able to benefit from your space of accelerated time again," Jin Tong said in an elated manner.

"Sure thing," Han Li replied with a nod.

A hesitant look then appeared on Jin Tong's face as she asked, "If I'm not mistaken, you're planning to go into seclusion in order to sever your self corpse soul so you can elevate your cultivation base to become a pseudo-Dao Ancestor, right?"

"That is indeed my plan. Is there something wrong?" Han Li asked.

"That will certainly grant you more power, but it'll also mean that there's no chance Gu Huojin will allow you to live," Jin Tong warned in a grim manner.

"At this point, that ship has already sailed. Even if I abandon my cultivation now, it's not like he would be willing to spare me," Han Li replied in a nonchalant manner.

"That's true," Jin Tong mused with a wry smile.

"It's only a matter of time before I have to face Gu Huojin in a battle of life and death, and with his and the Heavenly Court preoccupied with the Reincarnation Palace, this is the perfect time for me to hone my powers," Han Li said with a faint smile.

Jin Tong could see that his mind was already made up, and she didn't speak any further on the subject.

Han Li took a glance at his surroundings, and he discovered that they were in quite a large immortal region, one that even his spiritual sense wasn't able to fully encompass.

The immortal region primarily consisted of a desert environment, but the world's origin qi here was quite abundant, particularly energy of the earth attribute.

Furthermore, the deserts in the immortal region were dotted with fortress-like cities that were very unique and distinctive.

"Looks like we've arrived in the Yellow Sand Immortal Region," Han Li remarked with a hint of surprise on his face.

The Yellow Sand Immortal Region was one of the five hundred medium-sized immortal regions, and it was renowned for being home to many earth-attribute materials.

Coincidentally, the Yellow Sand Immortal Region was also very close to the Black Soil Immortal Region and the Northern Glacial Immortal Region.

Chapter 1346: What is Self?

"Why do you look so surprised?" Jin Tong asked in a perplexed manner.

"It's nothing. If we're going to go into seclusion, then no immortal region will be safe, so let's go to the Extraheavensphere," Han Li said, then swept a sleeve through the air to release a burst of golden light that enveloped them both before quickly racing his way up to the Extraheavensphere.

Even after arriving in the Extraheavensphere, he continued to fly onward for a long while before finally coming to a rest.

He released his spiritual sense to inspect his surroundings and ensure that it was safe, following which he dug out a cave abode into a giant asteroid.

After doing all of that, he opened the Flower Branch domain before stepping inside with Jin Tong.

They were immediately approached by a concerned Nangong Wan, who asked, "Are you alright? I sensed some very powerful aura fluctuations outside just now."

She then caught sight of Jin Tong, and a warm smile appeared on her face as she said, "You must be Jin Tong! The last time we met, you were still yet to attain a human form, but you've grown up into such a fine beauty!"

She approached Jin Tong and latched onto her hand as she spoke, but Jin Tong was clearly not very comfortable with the warm reception, and she greeted with a curt nod, "Mistress Nangong."

"There's no need to refer to me as mistress. My husband may be your master, but that has nothing to do with me, and given the vast disparity in our cultivation bases, it's only right that you refer to me by name," Nangong Wan said with a smile.

Seeing as she had already begun referring to Han Li as fellow daoist, Jin Tong raised no argument as she extended a curtsey and greeted Nangong Wan as Fellow Daoist Nangong instead.

Nangong Wan returned the curtsey with a smile, then turned back to Han Li as she repeated, "What happened outside just now?"

"I got into a conflict with some people, but it's all taken care of now, so there's nothing for you to worry about," Han Li replied in a nonchalant manner.

Jin Tong rolled her eyes internally upon hearing this.

Han Li had brushed off the two battles as if they were nothing more than minor scuffles, but he had just gone up against an Essential Dao Ancestor and the most powerful cultivator under the heavens back to back.

Not long ago, the two of them had almost met their demise at the hands of Gu Huojin, but of course, Jin Tong knew that he was intentionally downplaying everything to assuage Nangong Wan's concerns.

Judging from the look in her eyes, she clearly wasn't convinced, but she didn't ask any further questions.

"Wan'er, we've found a place to go into seclusion, so we're going to be cultivating for some time..."

Han Li gave Nangong Wan a brief rundown of his plan, and her eyes instantly lit up as she smiled and said, "That's perfect! I've always wanted to see that space of accelerated time of yours in action!"

Han Li duly obliged, releasing his spirit domain before activating the Celestial Time Array, and the flow of time in the Flower Branch Domain was instantly sped up by over a hundred thousandfold.

His mastery over the laws of time had improved significantly once again compared with before, so the space of accelerated time had also become more potent.

"This is incredible! Time really does live up to its name as one of the three paramount laws!" Nangong Wan exclaimed with an amazed expression.

"Not just anyone with mastery over the laws of time can pull this off. When it comes to the True Immortal Realm, I wouldn't dare to proclaim that I'm the foremost master of the laws of time, but I can certainly comfortably rank second. As for Gu Huojin, he may be above me, but even he may not have what it takes to create a space of accelerated time like this," Han Li said in a joking manner.

Jin Tong was very surprised to see such an unserious side to Han Li, while Nangong Wan rolled her eyes at him in an exasperated manner.

"Please excuse me, fellow daoists, I'm going to go cultivate now," Jin Tong hurriedly said before flying deeper into the Flower Branch domain, while Han Li and Nangong Wan flew into the bamboo pavilion hand in hand.

"Is this going to be a very important stint of seclusion?" Nangong Wan asked.

"That's right," Han Li replied with a serious nod.

"In that case, don't worry about me, just focus on your own cultivation," Nangong Wan said.

Han Li nodded in response, then flipped a hand over to produce a storage tool.

"I don't know how long I'll be in seclusion for. There are some pills, Immortal Origin Stones, and other cultivation resources in here, so you can also take this time to cultivate."

Nangong Wan accepted the storage tool, then cautioned Han Li to be safe before departing from the pavilion.

Following her departure, Han Li began setting up the array required for his corpse soul severance technique before setting down the final Earthly Deity Avatar in the array.

After that, he set up multiple layers of restrictions around the pavilion, then sat down with his legs crossed to meditate.

......

In front of the nameless palace in the Heavenly Court, Gu Huo Jin was observing a yellow bead in his hand.

The bead was giving off incredibly formidable earth law powers, and he was inspecting it with a pleased smile.

However, his expression then immediately stiffened, following which he closed his eyes as if he were sensing something.

Moments later, he reopened his eyes, and his brows were slightly furrowed as he murmured to himself, "He's gone without a trace... No matter. I've already reached the final step, so it hardly matters whether he gets away or not..."

......

Inside the Flower Branch domain.

After three days and three nights of meditation, Han Li had primed himself into the best possible physical and mental condition.

He took a moment to reexamine the array around him, then closed his eyes and turned his attention to his consciousness.

There was another Han Li sitting inside his consciousness, and he looked up with a calm smile as he said, "You've finally come to see me."

He was completely identical to Han Li in appearance, attire, and demeanor, and even their auras were indistinguishable from one another.

Han Li's brows furrowed ever so slightly, and his intuition told him that this corpse soul severance was going to be far more difficult than the previous two.

Han Li strode over to his self corpse soul before sitting down across from him.

"Have you come here to sever me?" the self corpse soul asked, and it was as if he were talking about something completely unrelated to himself.

At the same time, he conjured up a stone table between the two of them, upon which were two cups of tea.

"That's right," Han Li replied, then picked up one of the cups of tea before taking a sip.

"In that case, do you know what a self corpse soul is and how you're supposed to sever me?" the self corpse soul asked.

Han Li was stumped by this question.

He knew very little about how one was supposed to sever a self corpse soul, and even the concept of a self corpse soul was one that was quite ambiguous to him.

He had tried to acquire information pertaining to self corpse souls through various avenues, but with very limited luck.

After all, the self corpse soul was the final corpse soul to be severed for Great Encompassment cultivators, so the only people with knowledge on the subject were Dao Ancestors or peak-Great Encompassment cultivators.

"I am your self, which means that in order to sever me, you must kill yourself," the self corpse soul explained.

"I'm surprised you're willing to tell me this," Han Li said.

"Once you're ready to sever me, you'll naturally come to realize this, so there's no need to hide it from you, but before you reach that point, even if you're armed with this knowledge, you won't be able to sever me anyway," the self corpse soul replied with a smile.

"You seem very confident," Han Li remarked as his eyes narrowed slightly.

"Would you be willing to kill your companions in order to sever me? For example, Jin Tong?" the self corpse soul suddenly asked.

"Why would severing my self corpse soul require me to kill my friends?" Han Li asked as he raised an eyebrow.

The self corpse soul ignored the question as he continued, "What about killing your wife?"

Han Li's expression darkened slightly as he offered no response.

"How about your parents?" the self corpse soul continued.

"I think I should start off by killing you!" Han Li declared as he rose to his feet before throwing a punch at his self corpse soul, sending a mountainous, golden fist crashing down upon him.

The self corpse soul shook his head with a faint sigh, then reached a hand out of his sleeve to stop the golden fist cold in its tracks.

Han Li lashed out with his other fist upon seeing this while simultaneously conjuring up his time spirit domain, and the self corpse soul did the same.

Han Li's other fist struck the self corpse soul's spirit domain, and its power was completely nullified.

The two spirit domains were also evenly matched, with neither one able to get the better of the other.

"You and I are equal in both cultivation base and abilities, so I suggest you save your energy. If you want to sever me, then go and understand what the concept of self is first," the self corpse soul said with a faint smile.

Han Li paid no heed to him as he swept a sleeve through the air, sending dozens of streaks of lightning swordlight racing toward the self corpse soul.

The self corpse soul's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this, and an identical number of lightning sword projections appeared beside him to meet the oncoming attack.

A fierce battle ensued between the two, and just as the self corpse soul had said, the two of them were completely evenly matched.

Around half a month flew by in a flash, and their battle finally concluded when both of them were too exhausted to continue.

Han Li gave a cold harrumph before departing from his consciousness, and he was struck by a sense of intense fatigue as soon as his consciousness returned to his body.

The battle against his self corpse soul had been extremely taxing on his soul, and he quickly closed his eyes to rest and recuperate.

Chapter 1347: Repetition

Around half a month later, Han Li reappeared in his own consciousness.

"Welcome back, Fellow Daoist Han. Here for a rematch?" the self corpse soul asked with a smile, and it had clearly also made a full recovery.

"That's right, but before that, I have something to ask you," Han Li replied.

"Go ahead," the self corpse soul prompted.

"Last time, you said that in order to sever you, I have to kill my friends, my wife, and my parents. Why is that?" Han Li asked.

"That's something that you'll have to find out for yourself," the self corpse soul replied with a smile.

Clearly, he knew the answer, but wasn't planning to reveal it.

Han Li was silent for a moment, then sprang forward as he thrust a fist through the air, conjuring up a mountainous, golden fist projection that was imbued with devastating power.

The self corpse soul remained unfazed as he thrust a palm forward in response, releasing waves upon waves of palm projections to oppose the oncoming attack.

The golden fist projection tore through hundreds of palm projections in succession before it was finally eradicated, immediately following which Han Li appeared behind the self corpse soul amid a flash of lightning before lashing out with both fists at once.

Two Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fists instantly came crashing down upon the self corpse soul, but once again, the self corpse soul was completely unflustered as a burst of golden light surged out of his body before forming a tornado-like light barrier around him.

The two Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fists struck the light barrier and were instantly sent flying back as if they had just bounced off a soft wall, while the golden light barrier shuddered violently before fading away.

"I see what you're doing. You're trying to hone your control over your law powers by fighting me, right? You've been progressing too rapidly in your cultivation base, and as a result, your control over your newfound law powers is lagging behind. That's something that you'll have to address if you want to be able to oppose Gu Huojin, and I'll admit that fighting me is a good way to achieve this objective," the self corpse soul chuckled.

Han Li offered no response.

This was indeed one of his objectives, while his other objective was to try and gather more information about self corpse souls through interacting with his own.

Regardless of how tight-lipped the self corpse soul remained, Han Li was confident that he would be able to gather some information through their battles.

With that in mind, Han Li continued to lash out in an aimless fashion, while the self corpse soul warded off his attacks with ease.

"While that's a sound plan, you better be careful in your execution. If you're slain by me during one of our battles, then this body will be mine. Honestly, that's not going to change much anyway. After all, you and I are one and the same," the self corpse soul said with a smile.

The battle raged on for several days, only drawing to a conclusion once both of them were completely exhausted.

Several days later, Han Li returned, and this cycle repeated itself over and over again.

Before long, ten thousand years had flown by.

Inside Han Li's consciousness, two blurry, golden figures were clashing over and over again, both moving far too quickly to be tracked with the naked eye.

All types of fist projections, palm projections, sword qi, and other attacks were racing through the air, and all of a sudden, a resounding boom rang out, following which both combatants sprang back in retreat.

Golden light was flashing radiantly over Han Li's body as he thrust a fist through the air, and numerous golden fist projections erupted out of his entire body, not just his fist.

Every single fist projection was a Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fist, and they varied in length and thickness, intertwining with one another to form an enormous net that descended from above, leaving no room for retreat or evasion.

The self corpse soul made no attempt at evasion as he pointed a finger at the vast net of fist projections, and everything around him turned a dull, gray color as a burst of unmatched power was unleashed, clashing against the net of fist projections.

All of the fist projections were instantly destroyed, while Han Li and his self corpse soul were both sent flying back once again, and as usual, neither one was able to get the better of the other.

The battle intent had already drained from Han Li's eyes, and he didn't make any further moves.

"You don't want to continue?" the self corpse soul asked.

"There's not much point in continuing, so I'll be taking my leave now," Han Li replied, then vanished from the spot.

The two of them had fought countless battles against each other over the past ten thousand years, and their relationship had changed in subtle ways during that time.

Not only were they equal in power, even their personalities were identical, and they had developed a friendly rivalry over the years.

After Han Li's consciousness returned to his body, he closed his eyes in a weary manner and took some time to rest and recuperate.

After making a recovery, he didn't re-enter his own consciousness to challenge his self corpse soul again. His mastery over his time law powers had reached a limit, and it wasn't going to improve through further battles.

With that in mind, he flipped a hand over to produce a black, leather bound book that had the appearance of an ancient artifact.

This was a book that he had managed to secure by chance through a trade in the Reincarnation Palace, and it was said to have been a journal kept by a descendant of a Dao Ancestor, containing some stories of said Dao Ancestor.

Of course, Han Li was most interested in the part of the journal that described the Dao Ancestor's self corpse soul severance.

Even though that part of the journal only spanned several hundred words, it had provided him with some inspiration and led him to think of some things that he had never considered before.

According to the journal, the Dao Ancestor had spent over a thousand years searching for the true meaning of self. In the process, he had returned to the original site of the first sect that he had joined in his cultivation journey, and he had sat there in meditation for a hundred days.

In Han Li's eyes, that was perhaps an attempt made by the Dao Ancestor to return to his earliest self, back when he first embarked on the path of cultivation.

Over the past ten thousand years, he had also exchanged some insights and ideas with Jin Tong, but Jin Tong hadn't had to sever any corpse souls in this lifetime, so she wasn't able to provide him with much assistance.

Han Li quickly read through the entire book, then closed it before rising to his feet.

It seemed that he had arrived at some type of decision, and he stepped out of the pavilion.

Nangong Wan had also constructed a pavilion outside for her own seclusion.

Thanks to the resources bestowed upon her by Han Li and the incredible abundance of the world's origin qi in the Flower Branch domain, she had already reached the pinnacle of the True Immortal Stage, leaving her on the cusp of the Golden Immortal Stage.

Han Li called out to her through voice transmission, and she immediately awakened from her cultivation before stepping outside to meet him.

"Have you concluded your seclusion? Did you make much progress?"

"I'm afraid my progress has been very limited. I'm planning to go out on a trip. Would you care to accompany me?" Han Li asked as he latched onto her hand.

"Sure. I've never had a chance to explore the True Immortal Realm since my ascension," Nangong Wan replied in an elated manner.

"Once I leave the Flower Branch domain, this space of accelerated time will disappear. Would you like to accompany us, Fellow Daoist Jin?" Han Li asked.

"I'll leave you two to enjoy your excursion without my pesky presence," Jin Tong replied from afar.

Han Li respected Jin Tong's wishes, withdrawing his spirit domain before emerging from the Flower Branch domain with Nangong Wan.

The latter had never seen the Extraheavensphere before, and she began looking around with an amazed expression.

With a sweep of his sleeve, Han Li released a burst of golden light that picked up Nangong Wan, and he began telling her about the Extraheavensphere while flying onward.

After flying for close to a half a month, he embarked on a descent, and they quickly reached the ground.

They had descended upon a turbulent, black sea, and the world's origin qi in the surrounding environment was rather sparse.

Nestled in the waves in the distance was a small island with many residents, and the entire island was enshrouded within layers of advanced restrictions.

"What is this place?" Nangong Wan asked in a curious manner.

"This place is the Black Wind Sea, and that island is called Dark Veil Island. This is where I ended up the second time I ascended to the True Immortal Realm," Han Li replied as a reminiscent look appeared on his face.

Han Li had already told Nangong Wan about Black Wind Island in the past, and at the moment, she was carefully scouring her gaze over the island, comparing it with the details that Han Li had divulged to her in the past.

Han Li descended onto the surface of the sea near Dark Veil Island, then began looking around as if he were searching for something, while Nangong Wan stood silently off to the side to avoid distracting him.

Han Li walked around the island for a long while before returning to Nangong Wan's side, and the two of them promptly departed.

He flew along at a rather slow pace, seemingly thinking about something the entire time, and occasionally, he would point out to her some places along the way that were of significance to him.

Several days later, the two of them arrived at Black Wind Island.

No introduction was required as Nangong Wan was able to identify the island from the symbols within Black Wind City.

"This is the city that's home to the teleportation arrays leading to the outside world, right?" Nangong Wan asked.

Chapter 1348: Encountering an Acquaintance

"That's right. This place hasn't changed much at all over the years," Han Li mused.

It seemed that the Gray Realm invasion hadn't had much of an impact on this city.

As the two of them entered the city, Han Li began to inspect the surrounding streets with keen interest.

"What are you looking for?" Nangong Wan asked.

"Right now, I'm faced with the hurdle of having to sever my self corpse soul, and the key to that is my mental state. Hence, I'm planning to retrace my steps and visit all of the places I've been since my ascension to reminisce about the past and hone my mental state," Han Li explained.

These were all very foreign concepts to Nangong Wan, but she nodded in response, trusting that Han Li knew what he was doing.

The two of them stayed in Black Wind City for two days, during which Han Li gave her a tour of the city while pointing out the places of interest.

After leaving Black Wind City, they crossed through the Soul Stirring Winds to arrive on the Primordial Wave Continent.

Close to a year later, the two of them retraced Han Li's journey to the Blaze Dragon Dao on the Ancient Cloud Continent.

This was the first sect that Han Li had officially joined following his ascension to the True Immortal Realm, and he had stayed and cultivated here for a very long time.

To his surprise, the current Blaze Dragon Dao was a far cry from its heyday. There were very few disciples left in the sect, and the entire place was looking rather drab and dilapidated.

After briefly scouring the sect with his spiritual sense, Han Li quickly determined the reason for its decline.

The Northern Glacial Immortal Region was a small immortal region to begin with, and even though the Blaze Dragon Dao had once been a top-tier sect in the immortal region, it had suffered a heavy blow in the wake of the Baili Yan incident. Shortly thereafter, almost all of the Blaze Dragon Dao cultivators who had entered the Infernal Frost Immortal Palace had perished, and that was the beginning of the Blaze Dragon Dao's decline.

Of course, the Vast Flow Palace and the Dawn Fall Sect had also been negatively impacted.

After that, the three sects had been dealt another heavy blow by the Gray Realm's invasion of the Northern Glacial Immortal Region, and that was what had reduced the Blaze Dragon Dao to its current, pitiful state.

Han Li heaved an internal sigh as he cast a concealment technique upon himself and Nangong Wan before making his way to the Crimson Dawn Peak, where he had previously stayed.

The Crimson Dawn Peak looked much the same as when he had left it, and it seemed that no one else had stayed here after him.

Han Li sat down on the summit of the Crimson Dawn Peak and reminisced over the time that he had spent cultivating in the Blaze Dragon Dao, including his resolve to pursue the laws of time, his urgent desire to find Daoist Xie, and the constant fear that he felt of being tracked down by his enemies.

He reminisced about those emotions over and over again, and as he did so, the memories from that time became clearer and clearer.

His past self was like a mirror that reflected his truest self.

As he continued to reminisce, he developed a clearer and clearer understanding of his own heart, and he gradually came to glean the true meaning of self.

He sat for half a month straight, and all the while, Nangong Wan remained by his side in silence.

On this day, as the final ray of light from the dying sun faded away, Han Li rose to his feet with a faint smile on his face.

Nangong Wan could sense that something about his disposition had changed, but she couldn't put her finger on exactly what had changed.

Looks like cultivation for Great Encompassment cultivators really does primarily involve cultivation of the heart, she thought to herself.

"Let's go," Han Li said, and the two of them promptly departed.

......

On the border of the Northern Glacial Immortal Region, Primordial Origin City stood like a prowling, giant beast.

Outside the city was a vast, yellow desert that stretched as far as the eyes could see, and Han Li and Nangong Wan were sitting in the air above, observing the city and the desert below.

......

Two streaks of light were flying through the primordial land between the Northern Glacial Immortal Region and the Black Mountain Immortal Region at a leisurely pace, seemingly on a sightseeing tour.

......

Black Mountain Immortal Region, Floating Cloud Mountain Range, Leisure Valley.

Due to its close proximity to the Northern Glacial Immortal Region, the Black Mountain Immortal Region had been heavily impacted by the Gray Realm invasion.

At the moment, the Leisure Valley was completely deserted, and even Mo Wuxue and Yu Ziqi, who had chosen to remain here, were nowhere to be found.

Han Li and Nangong Wan were seated at the stone platform where everyone had frequently gathered in the past, drinking some wine together.

......

Black Soil Immortal Region, Illusory Smoke Swamp.

Han Li and Nangong Wan were drifting their way over the swamp, and all of the mist in the air instantly parted in their presence.

"This is where the entrance to the True Mantra Sect ruins is, right? I don't see any mist that conjures up illusions," Nangong Wan said.

"That type of mist only appears at certain times," Han Li explained.

His appearance remained unchanged, but his disposition had changed drastically, and there was an aura of sharpness about him, one that seemed to be able to sever anything.

An indescribable sense of pressure was emanating from his body, causing all of the living beings within a radius of hundreds of kilometers to hide in the swamp in a fearful manner.

"Do you think we'll still be able to enter the True Mantra Sect ruins now? I'm very curious to see what it looks like," Nangong Wan said.

"The True Mantra Sect ruins have already been devoured by a spatial rift, so I don't think it'll ever be seen again," Han Li replied with a shake of his head.

"In that case, where do we go from here? The Gray Realm? How are we supposed to get there now that the True Mantra Sect ruins have vanished?" Nangong Wan asked.

"We'll skip the Gray Realm," Han Li replied.

He was only able to travel to the Gray Realm all those years ago through a spatial passageway in the True Mantra Sect ruins. The Gray Realm was a very distant realm, and now that the spatial passageway was inaccessible, it would be quite difficult to get there, even at his cultivation base.

Not only that, but the Devil Realm was also off limits.

With the demise of Daoist Xie, the entire Devil Realm had fallen into the hands of the Devilish Monarch. If he were to go there now and be discovered by the Devilish Monarch, then he would be landing himself in a great deal of trouble.

Following this period of reminiscence and mental cultivation, his understanding of the concept of self had deepened significantly, and by his estimates, his chances of a successful corpse soul severance were already quite high.

Hence, he was considering whether it was time to make an attempt.

Right at this moment, a streak of light appeared on the horizon before flying toward them.

Han Li wasn't all that surprised to see this.

The Illusory Smoke Swamp was quite abundant in the world's origin qi, and it was home to many spirit materials, so there were often cultivators venturing into the swamp to search for treasures.

Han Li didn't want to meet with any strangers for fear that it would impact his mental state, and he was just about to depart with Nangong Wan when a look of surprise suddenly appeared on his face.

Immediately thereafter, he began flying directly toward the streak of light with Nangong Wan in tow.

The cultivator within the streak of light was rather alarmed by this, and he hurriedly stopped in his tracks, revealing himself to be a white-robed elderly man.

The streak of golden light faded away to reveal Han Li and Nangong Wan, and a stunned look appeared on the elderly man's face as he exclaimed, "Li Feiyu!"

"Long time no see, Fellow Daoist Hu Yan. I didn't think we would ever meet again," Han Li said with a smile.

The elderly man was none other than Daoist Hu Yan.

"Likewise!" Daoist Hu Yan exclaimed. "You must've made some very significant strides in your cultivation, I can't see through your cultivation base at all! What's your current cultivation base?"

"I've been very fortunate and stumbled upon some opportunities over the years that allowed me to advance in my cultivation. On the contrary, it looks like your cultivation base has regressed. Have you encountered some problems with your cultivation?" Han Li asked.

At the moment, Daoist Hu Yan was only at the mid-True Immortal Stage.

"It's not a big deal. At their core, things like wealth and cultivation base are no more significant than the dirt upon which we stand," Daoist Hu Yan chuckled, and he truly seemed unbothered.

"You're still as wise and insightful as ever, Fellow Daoist Hu Yan," Han Li praised with a smile.

"Wise my arse! I've just drunk too much wine and become so permanently inebriated that I don't care about anything anymore," Daoist Hu Yan chortled.

Meanwhile, Nangong Wan was observing this interaction with a hint of surprise in her eyes.

In her memories, Han Li had always been quite serious and stoic, and it was very rare to see him engage in such a relaxed and casual conversation with anyone.

Furthermore, she could tell that the two of them were on very good terms with one another.

"Who's this beautiful companion of yours?" Daoist Hu Yan asked with a meaningful look in his eyes.

"This is Wan'er, my dao partner. Wan'er, this is Fellow Daoist Hu Yan, someone who has helped me greatly in the past," Han Li introduced.

"Greetings, Fellow Daoist Hu Yan. My name is Nangong Wan. Thank you for looking after my husband," Nangong Wan said as she extended a curtsey.

"It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance, Celestial Maiden Nangong," Daoist Hu Yan said as he cupped his fist in a salute while making faces at Han Li.

"How about we find a place to have a drink together, Fellow Daoist Hu Yan?" Han Li proposed with a smile.

"Yes, please! If you don't mind, we can share a drink in my humble abode," Daoist Hu Yan said with a beaming smile.

"That sounds great! I hope your wine brewing skills haven't regressed over the years," Han Li jibed.

Daoist Hu Yan was one of his few close friends, so he was eager to catch up with him.

Daoist Hu Yan was so ecstatic that it looked as if he were on the verge of breaking into dance, and he declared, "My cultivation base may have regressed, but I can assure you that my wine brewing skills are as sharp as ever! Come with me!"

Chapter 1349: Still the Same Hu Yan

With Daoist Hu Yan leading the way, Han Li and Nangong Wan were taken to a mountain range with many giant peaks that stretched all the way up into the clouds. However, the world's origin qi in the environment was quite sparse, and there weren't many demon beasts in the area, either, making the entire place feel rather barren and lifeless.

With nothing to be gained, the area was naturally very rarely frequented by any cultivators.

As soon as Daoist Hu Yan entered this mountain range, he immediately became much more relaxed. Occasionally, he would recite some poetry for his own entertainment or point out some noteworthy landmarks in the mountain range to Han Li and Nangong Wan.

Initially, Han Li wasn't paying much attention, but he noticed that Nangong Wan was listening with keen interest, and she would point out some discoveries of her own from time to time, thoroughly impressing Daoist Hu Yan in the process.

Thus, he also became more involved in the conversation, raising some viewpoints and observations of his own to spark discussions between them.

Under this jovial atmosphere, the three of them wandered through the mountain range for close to an entire day before finally descending in front of an obscure mountain.

Even from very far away, Han Li had been able to tell that this mountain was different from the rest.

It wasn't that the mountain itself was different from the other mountains. Instead, the difference was that some very advanced restrictions had been set up around it, ones that would've been undetectable to the vast majority of cultivators below the High Zenith Stage.

Daoist Hu Yan flipped a hand over to produce a white badge, which he waved through the air to send a streak of white light vanishing into the space up ahead.

A white rift appeared amid a burst of spatial fluctuations, and it was impossible to see anything within it aside from a boundless expanse of white light.

"Come in," Daoist Hu Yan invited as he stepped into the white rift, and Han Li and Nangong Wan followed suit.

In the blink of an eye, they had appeared in a peaceful valley, within which several intricate bamboo buildings had been constructed.

On one side of the valley was a bamboo forest and a small creek connected to a pond, with many spirit beasts resting around it.

On the other side were several plots of spirit farmland that were being tended to by two figures.

The two figures looked up from their work before approaching Han Li's trio, and they were none other than Yun Ni and Bai Suyuan.

The former had already reached the late-Golden Immortal Stage, while the latter had also become a Golden Immortal. Furthermore, judging from her aura fluctuations, it was clear that she was using some very profound cultivation arts.

"Long time no see, Fellow Daoist Li! Hu Yan has missed you greatly over the years. Whenever he has a drink, he always brings you up while reminiscing about your time together," Yun Ni greeted with a warm smile.

"It has indeed been far too long, Fellow Daoist Yun," Han Li said as he cupped his fist in a salute.

"I was never able to repay you for taking me to the Blaze Dragon Dao, so please accept this gesture of gratitude from me, Senior Li," Bai Suyuan said as she extended a curtsey.

"No need for formalities, Fellow Daoist Bai," Han Li said with a faint smile as he casually swept a sleeve through the air, and Bai Suyuan was involuntarily returned to an upright posture by a burst of invisible force.

She was clearly quite taken aback by this, and she took a quick glance at Han Li before turning to Nangong Wan with a smile and a contemplative look in her eyes, seemingly guessing at how she had been fortunate enough to have become Han Li's dao partner.

As for Yun Ni, she was stunned by the ease with which Han Li was able to bring a Golden Immortal like Bai Suyuan out of her curtsey. This was something that was beyond the capabilities of even the average High Zenith cultivator.

Han Li introduced Nangong Wan to Yun Ni and Bai Suyuan, and they exchanged some small talk before making their way up to the second floor of one of the bamboo buildings.

The interior of the building was quite spacious, and the furnishings were quite simple, but still elegant and refined. From the vantage point of the second floor, one was able to see the entire valley, and it was quite a pleasant sight to behold.

After everyone had taken a seat, Han Li asked Daoist Hu Yan why they had chosen to settle here.

"It's a long story. We were already residing in a peaceful location in the Northern Glacial Immortal Region, but we were forced to leave due to the Gray Realm invasion. Unfortunately, Fellow Daoist Fengyi met her demise around that time, and it was only after a great deal of hassle that we were able to make it to the Black Soil Immortal Region," Daoist Hu Yan sighed in a forlorn manner, while Yun Ni and Bai Suyuan were also looking rather dejected.

Han Li heaved an internal sigh upon hearing this.

Many immortal regions had been impacted by the Gray Realm invasion, and Bai Fengyi was but one of countless casualties that would've resulted from the invasion.

Meanwhile, the Heavenly Court remained focused on preparing for the Bodhi Banquet, and it seemed that no one really cared about what was happening in these small and insignificant immortal regions.

Perhaps in the eyes of the Heavenly Court, the cultivators of these small immortal regions were no more significant than ants.

"After we arrived on the Black Soil Immortal Region, we heard that this Illusory Smoke Swamp was home to the True Mantra Sect ruins, but after those ruins were demolished by the Heavenly Court several thousand years ago, the swamp has been largely deserted, so we decided to settle here. What do you think? It's not a bad place, right?" Daoist Hu Yan asked.

"It is indeed a fine place, tucked away from the bothers of the outside world," Han Li replied with a nod, then turned to take a glance at Nangong Wan, who just so happened to have also been looking back at him as a hint of longing flashed through her eyes.

Han Li heaved an internal sigh as he rested a hand on top of hers.

He knew that while the attainment of immortality was one of the main incentives for her ascension to the True Immortal Realm, another major motivating factor was to be reunited with him.

Even though she had never verbally expressed it to him, he could sense the weariness that she felt deep in her heart.

After cultivating arduously for so many years, one could be forgiven for thinking that reaching the True Immortal Stage was the conclusion of one's journey, but who could've imagined that it was actually just the beginning of an even longer and more arduous journey?

Thankfully, she had always been quite strong of will, and she knew that she had no choice but to continue onward if she wanted to be able to remain by Han Li's side.

During this spate of wanderlust, Han Li had been able to clearly sense the depth of Nangong Wan's feelings for him and how much she had cherished their time together, and the thought of this never failed to warm his heart.

Nangong Wan could sense what Han Li was trying to convey to her through his eyes, and she gave him a slight nod as a look of resolve surfaced in her own eyes.

It was only a fleeting shared glance, but it held more meaning than an extensive conversation.

Daoist Hu Yan began asking Han Li about his experiences since they last parted ways. The three of them had been living in seclusion ever since they arrived in the Black Soil Immortal Region, so they weren't aware that Han Li was a wanted fugitive of the Heavenly Court.

Han Li didn't want to involve them in his mess, so he told them that he had been cultivating in the Black Mountain Immortal Region this entire time, and that he had come to the Illusory Smoke Swamp in search of the True Mantra Sect ruins.

"By the way, you mentioned that the Heavenly Court destroyed the True Mantra Sect ruins here several thousand years ago. Why did they do that?" Han Li asked.

Bai Suyuan had been listening in silence this entire time, and she suddenly interjected, "This is something that I found out from a nearby sect. Apparently, several groups of people from different powers, including the Heavenly Court, came to the Black Mountain Immortal Region at the time, and they searched through the entirety of the True Mantra Sect ruins.

“It's unclear whether they found what they were looking for, but in the process, the entire place was demolished."

"That does sound like something the Heavenly Court would do," Han Li mused, then changed the subject as he asked, "Fellow Daoist Hu Yan, why has your cultivation base regressed by so much?"

Yun Ni's expression changed slightly upon hearing this, but she didn't say anything, while Bai Suyuan lowered her head.

"There's not much of a story to tell. Back when we first arrived in the Black Soil Immortal Region, I encountered an enemy of roughly the same cultivation base as myself. I was able to wound him and force him into retreat, but I also sustained severe injuries of my own that resulted in a significant regression in cultivation base," Daoist Hu Yan explained with a smile, seemingly completely unbothered by his current condition.

"I see," Han Li replied with a nod.

He could tell that Daoist Hu Yan was keeping something from him, but he didn't ask any questions as he didn't want to pry.

"That's enough questions from you, kid! Let's get back to what's important. I've collected some spirit ingredients from the Black Soil Immortal Region over the years to brew several types of wine. Let's have a taste together," Daoist Hu Yan said with a wide smile.

"Hu Yan, don't be so rude!" Yun Ni hurriedly interjected.

Han Li's unfathomable cultivation base had not escaped her notice, and she was worried that Daoist Hu Yan's flippant remarks would be met with dire consequences.

"Don't worry so much. If Fellow Daoist Li is the type of person to get hung up on such little things, then he wouldn't have been able to reach such staggering heights in such a short time," Daoist Hu Yan said with a nonchalant smile.

"Indeed, Fellow Daoist Hu Yan. We're all friends sharing a drink here, so why bother ourselves with formalities and social norms?" Han Li said with a wide smile of his own.

Yun Ni was rather taken aback to hear this, but she was naturally very pleased and relieved by Han Li's gracious reaction.

Daoist Hu Yan asked Yun Ni and Bai Suyuan to take Nangong Wan on a tour of the valley, while he dragged Han Li to a short bamboo building situated in a corner of the valley.

It was the most unremarkable bamboo building of the lot, but it was filled with all types of gourds, jars, and flagons, as well as wine cups of all types of different materials.

After entering the building, it was as if Daoist Hu Yan had transformed into an entirely different person, and he began giving Han Li an extensive introduction to his collection of wine and wine-brewing paraphernalia.

It seemed that he derived more joy from talking about his collection than he would from a major increase in cultivation base.

Only now did Han Li feel like the Daoist Hu Yan of old was back.

Chapter 1350: Inspiration

"Looks like you've made some fantastic additions to your collection over the years, Fellow Daoist Hu Yan," Han Li remarked with a smile.

"I've collected a lot of fine wine, but unfortunately, I haven't had anyone to share it with. Now that you're here, we can drink to our hearts' content!" Daoist Hu Yan declared.

Han Li naturally raised no objections to this, and the two of them sat down across the table from one another, sampling Daoist Hu Yan's prized collection while chatting about the past.

Before long, both of them were a little tipsy, and Han Li told Daoist Hu Yan about the current state of the Blaze Dragon Dao.

Daoist Hu Yan had stayed in the Blaze Dragon Dao far longer than Han Li, and he couldn't help but be saddened by this news.

"Once this storm has blown over, you can return to the Northern Glacial Immortal Region to revitalize the Blaze Dragon Dao if you're interested. Don't worry about resources, I can give you all the help you need in that department," Han Li offered.

He was indebted to the Blaze Dragon Dao as that was where he had obtained the Mantra Axis Scripture, and given his current wealth, supporting a small sect like the Blaze Dragon Dao was a piece of cake.

Daoist Hu Yan took a surprised glance at Han Li upon hearing this, then smiled as he said, "You must really have made something out of yourself if you're willing to make such a bold declaration. It's fine, just let nature run its course. If a sect is destined to fall, then there's no point in trying to forcibly reverse its fortunes."

"Your personality has remained the same, but your style of doing things has changed quite a bit," Han Li remarked in a contemplative manner.

"I've experienced many things, and in particular, suffering this regression in cultivation base has made me realize that there's no real importance to many of the things that I had clung onto stubbornly in the past," Daoist Hu Yan replied with a smile.

A thoughtful look appeared on Han Li's face upon hearing this.

"The current me is no longer the past me, and as for what the future holds, that's not something I can predict, nor is it something that I want to find out as I'm no longer fixated on the future me. There is wine in my cup right now, and that's all I want to focus on," Daoist Hu Yan said, then downed the contents of his cup in one go.

"You're right. Many things that we regard as important are actually nothing more than manifestations of our fixations of the past, the present, and the future. In reality, they hold no inherent importance," Han Li murmured as a hint of enlightenment flashed through his eyes.

Daoist Hu Yan raised an eyebrow in a perplexed manner, wondering what had suddenly come over Han Li.

"From the moment that we first set foot on the path of cultivation and began absorbing the world's origin qi, our bodies have already been severed from their mortal ties, and they're constantly changing over time.

“Essentially, we are turning into different people from one moment to the next, so there's no permanence in the concept of self. However, that does not mean that we don't exist..." Han Li continued as his eyes lit up with the glow of an epiphany.

Daoist Hu Yan shook his head and paid no further heed to Han Li as he drank three more cups of wine by himself in succession.

"Thank you, Fellow Daoist Hu Yan," Han Li said as he abruptly rose to his feet before extending a grateful bow toward Daoist Hu Yan.

"What for?" Daoist Hu Yan asked as he hurriedly sprang to his feet in an alarmed manner.

"What you said to me just now has allowed me to overcome a mental hurdle in my cultivation," Han Li replied.

Daoist Hu Yan faltered slightly upon hearing this, then burst into laughter, and he didn't ask for further elaboration.

From there onward, the two of them fully immersed themselves in drinking and reminiscing about the past, making no further mention of any subjects related to cultivation.

All of the immortal wines in Daoist Hu Yan's collection contained a great deal of immortal spiritual power, and given his current cultivation base, it didn't take long before he fell into a drunken slumber.

Han Li moved Daoist Hu Yan onto the bed with a sweep of his sleeve, then inspected his internal condition with his spiritual sense, upon which his brows furrowed slightly in befuddlement.

After that, he emerged from the room, and at this point, it was already late at night.

It was very peaceful in the valley, and it seemed that Nangong Wan, Yun Ni, and Bai Suyuan had all already retired for the night.

It had been a very long time since Han Li had been able to enjoy a moment of peace like this to himself, and he began taking a stroll through the valley.

Right at this moment, Bai Suyuan emerged from the bamboo forest up ahead, having changed into a white dress, and she called out in a gentle voice, "Senior Li."

"Why are you still up so late at night, Fellow Daoist Bai?" Han Li asked.

Bai Suyuan was silent for a moment, then asked, "Given your lofty cultivation base, I'm sure you've already managed to identify Senior Hu Yan's current ailments, right?"

"Fellow Daoist Hu Yan's essential energy is severely depleted, and it doesn't look like something that would result from an injury. I've only ever seen similar symptoms in some cultivators who have transmitted their own essential energy into others," Han Li replied.

"Your assessment is correct, Senior Li. Senior Hu Yan's cultivation base regression didn't come as a result of his injuries. Instead, it was all because of me," Bai Suyuan said in a quiet voice.

Han Li wasn't surprised to hear this, and he waited patiently for her to continue.

"Senior Hu Yan was indeed wounded in a battle not long after we arrived in the Black Mountain Immortal Region, but they were relatively inconsequential injuries that he could've recovered from with some rest and recuperation. However, I was too fixated on seeking vengeance for our clan's matriarch, Senior Bai Fengyi, that I attempted a breakthrough to the Golden Immortal Stage before I was fully ready.

“As a result, my meridians were thrown into a state of disarray, and I was on the verge of death. In order to save me, Senior Hu Yan transmitted his essential energy into my body to help me suppress my injuries and successfully reach the Golden Immortal Stage, at the expense of dire consequences for himself," Bai Suyuan explained in a forlorn manner.

"I see," Han Li sighed.

All of a sudden, Bai Suyuan stepped forward and fell to her knees before Han Li.

"Senior Hu Yan's current condition can't be treated by anyone below the High Zenith Stage. I'm sure you've already reached the High Zenith Stage, so please help him. In exchange, I'm willing to remain by your side as a servant for as long as I live," Bai Suyuan implored as tears began to well up in her eyes.

Han Li raised an eyebrow as he swept a sleeve through the air to bring Bai Suyuan back to her feet, following which he said, "Fellow Daoist Hu Yan is a close friend of mine, and he has just done me a significant favor, so I would've cured his condition even if you hadn't asked me to."

He summoned a white jade vial as he spoke, then offered it to Bai Suyuan.

An ecstatic look appeared on her face as she accepted the vial in a timid manner, and even through the vial, she was greeted by a fragrant, medicinal aroma.

"The vial contains ten Immortal Origin Enhancement Pills, which are very potent for restoring essential energy. Have Fellow Daoist Hu Yan take one every ten days, and he'll be able to recover his lost essential energy in no more than two months. As long as he works diligently in his cultivation from there, he should be able to return to his former cultivation base very soon," Han Li said.

"Thank you, Senior Li!" Bai Suyuan exclaimed in an ecstatic manner as she fell to her knees again.

"You can go now," Han Li said with a dismissive wave, then continued on his stroll.

Bai Suyuan hesitated momentarily, then extended a grateful bow toward him before departing.

Before long, Han Li had arrived at a small pergola deep in a bamboo forest, and Nangong Wan was standing inside.

"Why were you so cold to her? She was prepared to stay by your side as a servant for life as repayment," Nangong Wan said with a hint of a smile on her face.

Han Li shook his head with a smile as he latched onto her hand and said, "That vial of Immortal Origin Enhancement Pills will be enough to treat Daoist Hu Yan's condition, so the favor has been repaid. With that, our karmic ties with this place have been severed, so it's time for us to go."

Immediately thereafter, the two of them vanished from the valley amid a flash of lightning.

In the next instant, the two of them appeared in the sky above the valley, and Nangong Wan asked, "Where do we go from here?"

"The Extraheavensphere," Han Li replied as he raced up into the heavens with Nangong Wan in tow.

It didn't take long for them to reach the Extraheavensphere, following which Ham Li created another temporary cave abode in a safe area.

The two of them entered the Flower Branch domain, and Nangong Wan asked, "Are you going to continue your cultivation from before?"

Han Li nodded in response.

"I can't help you with your cultivation, but I'm sure you'll succeed," Nangong Wan said with an encouraging smile.

"Your encouragement is the biggest help you can give me," Han Li said as he wound his arms around her, then planted a gentle kiss on her forehead before making his way into his bamboo pavilion.

All of the restrictions on the floor of the pavilion were still operating as normal, and Han Li sat down with his legs crossed to meditate.

After taking a day and a night to prime himself into the best mental and physical condition, he entered his own consciousness again.

As usual, his self corpse soul was seated inside, but this time, as he raised his head to look up at Han Li, he immediately noticed that there was something different about him.

"You've made significant strides in your mental state. Looks like you're serious about severing me this time," the self corpse soul remarked.

"That's right," Han Li declared, wasting no time as he summoned his spirit domain.

To his surprise, the self corpse soul made no attempt at evasion, simply allowing Han Li's spirit domain to descend upon him.

Immediately thereafter, a burst of translucent light flashed over Han Li's glabella, and countless translucent chains instantly shot out of thin air around his self corpse soul before binding him to the spot.

The self corpse soul didn't seem concerned by this at all, and there was even a composed smile on his face.

All of a sudden, everything around Han Li descended into complete darkness, and his self corpse soul was suddenly nowhere to be seen.

Is this an illusion?

Han Li immediately channeled his Spirit Refinement Technique while simultaneously releasing his tremendous spiritual sense, which took on the form of a series of giant swords that slashed through the air surrounding space.

However, the giant spiritual sense swords were merely devoured by the surrounding space without even the slightest ripple, much to Han Li's alarm.

Given how immense his spiritual sense was, even an illusion created by the Illusory Dao Ancestor shouldn't have been impervious to his powers.

Right at this moment, the surrounding scene suddenly transformed, and he found himself in the air above a pool of viscous blood that was giving off a nauseating stench.

All of a sudden, five menacing ghostly creatures sprang out of the pool before pouncing at him.

These ghostly creatures were extremely horrific in appearance, with their bodies riddled with putrid ulcers that were constantly spewing forth blood-infused pus, and each of them had seven or eight arms, the fingers of which were tipped with sharp claws of different lengths.

It was as if they were the amalgamation of all that was horrific and hideous in this world, presenting a truly harrowing sight to behold.

Chapter 1351: Severance of Fixations

Han Li's expression remained completely unchanged at the sight of the five ghostly creatures, and five Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords shot out of his body amid a flash of lightning before racing toward the ghostly creatures as five streaks of radiant, golden light.

However, the bodies of the five ghostly creatures suddenly took on an insubstantial quality, and the Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords passed straight through them without inflicting any damage.

The five ghostly creatures were incredibly fast, and they reached Han Li in the blink of an eye before grabbing onto his body and preparing to sink their teeth into his flesh.

Han Li's first instinct was to release his spirit domain, but he caught himself as a faint smile appeared on his face, and the golden light that had begun appearing over his body suddenly faded away.

The five ghostly creatures sank their teeth into his body, sending blood splattering in all directions, while a burst of excruciating agony speared into his soul.

However, he remained standing calmly on the spot, as if he couldn't feel any pain at all, and he had even closed his eyes.

The eyes of the five ghostly creatures were glowing with excitement as they eagerly tore off chunks of flesh from Han Li's body, and before long, he had been reduced to a bare skeleton, but he remained completely unconcerned.

The five ghostly creatures grabbed onto his skeleton, yet right as they were about to wrench it apart, Han Li suddenly declared in a calm manner, "Fear is nothing more than illusion. If I am not me, then what do I have to worry?"

A faint glow began to emanate from his body as he spoke, and the five ghostly creatures clinging to his body were instantly reduced to ashes, while the pool of blood down below also vanished.

All of a sudden, Han Li was brought back to the black space with his body completely unscathed, as if the ordeal that he had just suffered had been nothing more than a dream.

However, before he even had a chance to catch his breath, his surroundings transformed once again.

This time, he appeared in a pink world, surrounded by countless stunning women. There were thin and delicate young women who fully exemplified the exuberance and beauty of youth, as well as more mature and voluptuous women who exuded a sense of ripe allure.

These women were all scantily dressed as they sang and danced around Han Li in a seductive manner, and any man could easily be forgiven for falling to their collective seduction, yet Han Li remained completely unmoved, and it was as if he couldn't even see the women around him.

Right at this moment, a young woman embraced him from behind as she breathed gently against his ear, and it was none other than Bai Suyuan.

"You captured my heart long ago, Senior Han. You also want me, but haven't acted on your desires because that would be unbefitting of someone of your status, right?" Bai Suyuan giggled in a voice that was dripping with allure.

Immediately thereafter, Yu Menghan sidled up against Han Li with desire smoldering in her eyes as she confessed, "Senior Han, I worked so hard in my cultivation to ascend to the True Immortal Realm all so that I could find you..."

Her arrival was followed by that of two more women, namely Yuan Yao and Yan Li.

"Brother Han, Big Sister Yan Li has also had feelings for you for a very long time, so you have to take responsibility for her," Yuan Yao giggled as she pressed herself tightly against his arm.

Yan Li was blushing deeply, but she also enveloped Han Li in a warm embrace.

All of the surrounding women had transformed into female cultivators that were past acquaintances of his, and they were all putting their most seductive qualities on full display.

"Relationships and women are nothing more than parting clouds. If I am not me, then why should I be attached?" Han Li declared in an expressionless manner, and all of the surrounding women transformed into a series of skeletons before disintegrating into dust, while the pink world reverted back to the black space from before.

However, in the next instant, the surrounding scenery transformed once again, and Han Li appeared in a majestic palace, seated within which were the Reincarnation Palace Master, Li Yuanjiu, Yue Mian, Bai Ze, and all of his other acquaintances from the Spirit Realm and the mortal realm.

All of them immediately rose to their feet before falling to their knees with looks of awe and veneration in their eyes as they collectively declared, "We pay our respects to the ruler of all realms, the one who stands at the pinnacle of the Great Dao!"

Han Li looked on in an emotionless manner.

"Bring them in!" a tall and imposing guard yelled, and a series of shackled figures stumbled into the palace from outside.

All of them were past enemies of Han Li's, including the likes of Qi Mozi, Shi Pokong, and Yin Chengquan.

The procession was led by none other than Gu Huojin, who was looking very disheveled, and his aura was also extremely feeble.

All of these people had already lost the flair that they once possessed. It seemed that their shackles possessed some type of restrictive power that completely sealed away their cultivation bases, reducing them to mere mortals.

All of a sudden, a hulking mountain of a man appeared behind them, wielding a gleaming cleaver, and with just a few swings of the cleaver, Gu Huojin and the others were all promptly decapitated, with their bloody heads falling to the ground at Han Li's feet.

However, once again, he remained completely unmoved.

"Why do you still not smile, Master? Could it be that there are still other enemies that you wish to see dead? Please tell me and I will find them, even if I must scour all of the realms under the heavens," the brawny guard implored as he fell to one knee.

"Power is nothing more than a pipe dream. If I am not me, then what is there to be enamored with?" Han Li declared, and the surrounding illusion dissipated again.

Han Li's expression remained unchanged, but there had been a subtle change in his mental state.

Having endured three consecutive illusions, he had severed three types of attachments, and that left him feeling a little weary, but also somehow lighter and more carefree than ever before.

Right at this moment, the surrounding scene changed once again, and he found himself standing atop a mountain of lifeless bodies, surrounded by a sea of blood.

All of the deceased were dressed in Reincarnation Palace and primordial land attire, and he was familiar with many of them.

The Reincarnation Palace Master, Gan Jiuzhen, Yue Mian, Bai Ze... All of them laid dead here with looks of horror and indignation on their stiff faces.

The entire air was filled with the suffocating stench of blood and decay, and it was all so realistic that it was indiscernible from reality.

"Han Li!"

A cold voice rang out from up ahead, and Han Li looked up to discover Gu Huojin standing in the distance.

"Do you see this? This is what happens to people who try to oppose me!" Gu Huojin sneered.

With a sweep of his sleeve, several figures appeared before him, all of whom were tightly bound. They were Nangong Wan, Violet Spirit, Jin Tong, Weeping Soul, Liu Le'er, Shi Chuankong, and Han Li's parents from the mortal realm.

Han Li's expression changed slightly upon seeing this, but he quickly composed himself again.

"These are all very important people to you, are they not? Submit to me right now and vow to serve me for the rest of eternity or all of them will be subjected to terrible deaths before your eyes!" Gu Huojin declared with a derisive sneer.

Han Li remained unmoved.

"You probably think I'm bluffing, don't you?" Gu Huojin sneered as his eyes narrowed slightly, following which he pointed a finger at Shi Chuankong, and a blade of golden light instantly pierced through his chest.

His body was split into two, and the two halves fell into a puddle of his blood.

Han Li's expression changed slightly once again, but his composure quickly returned.

Immediately thereafter, two more beams of golden light shot out of Gu Huojin's fingertips, and Jin Tong and Weeping Soul also met their demise.

An unnatural flush appeared on Han Li's face, only to instantly fade away.

"So your friends mean nothing to you. In that case, what about this little girl by the name of Liu Le'er? I heard that she's like a sister to you. Are you going to just stand there and watch her die as well?" Gu Huojin sneered as he sent a beam of golden light piercing through Liu Le'er's body.

Han Li threw up a small mouthful of blood as he swayed unsteadily on his feet, but was able to steady himself.

"All that's left are your two dao partners and your parents. Who should I kill first? How about I give you the power of choice this time. You tell me who you want to have killed first, and you can leave the one who's most precious to you for last," Gu Huojin offered.

Han Li's cheeks were brightly flushed, and his breathing had become quite labored. His composed facade had finally been shattered, but he remained silent as he gritted his teeth tightly.

"How disappointing. If you're not going to make a choice, then I'll do it for you. Killing them one by one is too much of a hassle, so I'll just get rid of all four of them at once," Gu Huojin said as his hand began to glow with golden light again.

"Stop!" Han Li suddenly yelled, and Gu Huojin immediately stopped what he was doing as a bright smile appeared on his face.

"Have you finally come around? Kneel to me now and I can spare their lives!" Gu Huojin chortled with glee.

Han Li slowly stepped forward with his cheeks a fiery complexion of red, and sweat was pouring down from his forehead as he slowly strode over to Gu Huojin.

"Kneel!" Gu Huojin yelled, and Han Li duly obliged.

Gu Huojin erupted into gleeful laughter as he reached out to make a grabbing motion with one another, and five streaks of black light appeared above Han Li before attempting to burrow their way into his body.

However, the streaks of black light were unable to pierce into his body at all, and they struck him with a loud clang, as if they had just struck a wall.

Right at this moment, Han Li raised his head, and the red coloration of his face had completely faded away, turning his complexion as fair as jade.

Gu Huojin's expression changed drastically upon seeing this, yet before he had a chance to do anything, a streak of translucent light appeared before him before slashing his body into two.

"Father, Mother, Wan'er, Violet Spirit, sorry to have allowed you to be used by that scoundrel," Han Li said, then swept a sleeve through the air, and the entire crimson space instantly collapsed.

Upon returning to the black space, Han Li stumbled slightly as a weary look appeared on his face.

He had become rather detached from the world over the course of his cultivation journey, but there were certain people that he still held very close to his heart, making his attachments to them far more difficult to sever.

Fate brings friends and family together, but fate also drives them apart. I am not me, you are not you, and they are not them, so what is there to be attached to?

As this thought surfaced in his mind, the surrounding scene transformed once again, placing him in a putrid swamp, while he had transformed into a rotten corpse laying in the swamp.

His body was overrun with maggots and flies, and sections of his skeleton had been exposed as his decaying flesh gave way in those places.

Chapter 1352: Detachment

Han Li's brows furrowed slightly at his current predicament, but he immediately closed his eyes to calm himself.

Moments later, his eyes sprang open again as he murmured to himself, "One's body is nothing more than a bunch of individual parts assembled by the threads of fate. It bears no true significance or cause for attachment."

The surrounding scene cumbled once again, returning him to the black space, but before he had a chance to rest, a new illusion appeared.

The illusions came one after another, with every single one presenting a stern trial.

Thanks to his immense willpower and the insights that he had recently gleaned, he was able to sever one attachment after another, and even though his mental fortitude was being bolstered with each trial that he overcame, he had also become exhausted to the extreme, to the point that his vision was beginning to blur around the edges.

After vanquishing one more illusion, Han Li found himself back in the black space, and at this point, he was so exhausted that he was on the verge of falling unconscious.

Right at this moment, the self corpse soul's voice suddenly rang out.

"There are countless attachments that one develops over the course of a lifetime. Your attachments arise from your heart, so as long as your heart is not at peace, there will be no end to the attachments that you must sever. In your current state, there's no way you can overcome this hurdle."

Han Li swayed unsteadily upon hearing this, and a dazed look appeared in his eyes.

"Just give up. Why continue to toil and suffer? Sometimes, giving up is the wise choice. Daoist Hu Yan gave up his path of cultivation to live in seclusion, and he's now able to enjoy life to the fullest, so why don't you do the same?"

The self corpse soul's voice had become very gentle and alluring, and Han Li's eyes began to gradually drift out of focus. His consciousness slowly began to fade away, and he was on the verge of falling into a deep sleep.

Right at this moment, it was as if a bolt of lightning had flashed through his mind, and his exhaustion was suppressed by what little remained of his willpower.

"You certainly chose the right time to make a move, striking when I'm at my most exhausted and vulnerable. If my mental fortitude had been even slightly lacking, then I would've fallen at the final hurdle!" Han Li harrumphed coldly as he swept a sleeve through the air, and the self corpse soul's voice abruptly trailed off, while the surrounding black space collapsed violently.

All of a sudden, Han Li found himself back in the Flower Branch domain.

"Finally..." he sighed in a relieved manner.

Right at this moment, a burst of vast yet gentle power surged into his soul, wiping away all of his exhaustion.

His body and soul were basked in a sense of blissful comfort, as if he were being rewarded for reaching the final destination of his cultivation journey.

It was a truly indescribable sense of achievement and joy, and as more and more power continued to surge into his body, it seemed as if there would be no end to the degree with which his own powers were going to be elevated.

His body became as light as a feather, and he drifted up into the heavens, quickly reaching extremely lofty heights.

In this instant, it was as if the entire True Immortal Realm were beneath his feet, as were the Devil Realm, the Gray Realm, and the underworld.

He felt as if he had transcended everything to become an omnipotent being, and as he continued to ascend, it was as if he were about to rise up into another world.

All of a sudden, a sense of danger tore through this blissful sensation, and Han Li hurriedly suppressed this feeling of ascension, upon which he reappeared in the Flower Branch domain.

This time, it was the true Flower Branch domain.

So the final test concerns one's attachment to power! That was a really close call. It makes sense that this is the final test, considering power is the lifelong pursuit of all cultivators, and one could easily lose their way in this final test.

Having overcome the final hurdle, Han Li's mental state had been perfected, and with a sweep of his sleeve, an orb of azure light flew out of his body before vanishing into the nearby Earthly Deity Avatar.

The space above the Flower Branch domain instantly turned golden in color as the gates of the Heavenly Dao appeared once more.

Boundless golden light surged out of the gate, imbued with the secrets of the laws of time, and all of it was injected into his body.

The world's origin qi within a radius of hundreds of thousands of kilometers was stirred up into a frenzy before converging in all directions to be injected into Han Li's body along with the golden light flowing out of the heavenly gates.

The final, one thousand eight hundredth immortal acupoint on his body instantly lit up, and blinding, golden light began radiating from his entire body, forming an incredibly bright golden halo.

Bursts of tremendous aura fluctuations surged out of the golden light, and they were only becoming more and more formidable.

These aura fluctuations were also accompanied by immense waves of spiritual sense fluctuations that erupted in all directions.

With this latest breakthrough, he had finally reached full mastery of the seventh level of the Spirit Refinement Technique as well.

......

Elsewhere in the Flower Branch domain, Jin Tong abruptly snapped out of her cultivation before vanishing from the spot.

In the next instant, he appeared in the deepest part of the domain with Nangong Wan in tow, right as a pillar of white light erupted out of Han Li's bamboo pavilion.

Bursts of tremendous spiritual sense fluctuations surged out of the pillar of light, and in response, Jin Tong's glabella lit up with golden radiance as she conjured up a translucent, golden light barrier that encompassed both of them.

The light barrier rippled unsteadily in the face of the immense spiritual sense fluctuations surging through the air, and an ecstatic look appeared on Nangong Wan's face as she asked, "Has he managed to make a breakthrough?"

"He has. It looks like not only has he made a breakthrough in his cultivation base, his Spirit Refinement Technique has also been perfected," Jin Tong replied in a stunned manner as she did everything in her power to fortify the golden light barrier.

Outside the Flower Branch domain, a vast expanse of radiant, golden light had appeared in the sky, and a pillar of even brighter white light erupted out of it into the heavens.

Inside the Reincarnation Palace branch in the underworld, a pillar of white light suddenly appeared in front of the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate without any warning before injecting itself into the plate.

The Six Paths Reincarnation Plate immediately began trembling violently as bursts of light containing countless images surged out of it before vanishing into the pillar of white light.

Gan Jiuzhen appeared before the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate with an alarmed look on her face, and not long after her arrival, the pillar of white light faded away, and it was as if nothing had happened.

According to Father, a similar phenomenon took place back when he perfected the Spirit Refinement Technique. Who is it this time? Could it be Han Li?

With that in mind, Gan Jiuzhen immediately departed with an excited gleam in her eyes, planning to report this matter to the Reincarnation Palace Master.

......

Inside the Flower Branch domain, maintaining the golden light barrier had become quite a strenuous task for Jin Tong.

Her soul was relatively weak to begin with, and the spiritual sense fluctuations surging out of the bamboo pavilion were only becoming more and more powerful.

Right at this moment, the pillar of white light in the distance suddenly flashed a few times before fading away, much to Jin Tong's relief.

Even though the pillar of white light had disappeared, the golden heavenly gate in the sky still remained, and golden light continued to surge out of it without pause.

An astonished look flashed through Jin Tong's eyes as she sensed the tremendous law powers of the Heavenly Dao within the golden light.

She had also been granted the power of the Heavenly Dao back when her Dao Ancestor status was restored, but nowhere near as much as what Han Li was receiving now.

Only after a long while did the golden light above the Flower Branch domain fade away, while Han Li slowly opened his eyes to reveal a pair of completely emotionless pupils that looked as if they were manifestations of the Heavenly Dao.

An unrivaled aura erupted out of his body, instantly reducing everything in the immediate vicinity to nothingness.

An alarmed look appeared on the Earthly Deity Avatar's avatar's face as it hurriedly conjured up a spherical golden light barrier around itself, only to have close to half of the light barrier instantly destroyed by the almighty aura surging out of Han Li's body.

The entire bamboo pavilion was erased from existence in an instant, but his tremendous aura continued to proliferate outward in all directions, destroying everything in its path.

Cracks began to appear over the entire Flower Branch domain, and it was quickly brought to the verge of collapse.

"Fellow Daoist Han!" Jin Tong exclaimed in an alarmed manner while injecting her power into the Flower Branch domain to stabilize it.

Han Li shuddered as a hint of lucidity appeared in his eyes, and he immediately suppressed his own aura.

Jin Tong heaved a long sigh of relief upon seeing this, while the golden light barrier around the Earthly Deity Avatar faded away.

"I didn't think you would be able to sever all of your attachments so quickly. You have bested me," the Earthly Deity Avatar sighed.

"Just as you said, attachments arise from the heart, so there will be no end to them if one's heart is not at peace. I am not me, so those attachments are not my own. If my attachments do not exist, then I am naturally able to see all things for what they really are," Han Li said in a calm manner.

In contrast with his kind corpse soul and wicked corpse soul, even though he had managed to sever his self corpse soul, he was still unable to see through it.

"What do you plan to do with me?" the Earthly Deity Avatar asked.

"You pose more of a threat to me than my kind corpse soul and my wicked corpse soul, so I'm afraid I cannot allow you to remain by my side," Han Li replied.

"My paltry powers hardly pose any threat to you in your current state," the Earthly Deity Avatar said with a wry smile.

Han Li paid no heed to its self-deprecation as he swept a sleeve through the air, and the Heaven Controlling Vial appeared in his grasp.

A burst of dark green light then shot out of the vial at his behest, and the space up ahead was instantly parted to form a translucent wall.

Han Li cast an incantation seal into the translucent wall, and a vortex that led to an unknown destination appeared over its surface.

"You plan to cast me into an alternate space and time? That suits me just fine," the Earthly Deity Avatar said.

Han Li swept a sleeve through the air, releasing a burst of golden light that enveloped the Earthly Deity Avatar before carrying it toward the vortex, and the Earthly Deity Avatar posed no resistance as it allowed itself to be cast into the vortex.

With another sweep of his sleeve, the translucent wall vanished, while the Heaven Controlling Vial fell back into his grasp.

Nangong Wan and Jin Tong flew over to him, and he smiled as he said, "Sorry to have made you worry."

"It's fine, I'm just glad everything went smoothly for you," Nangong Wan replied with a shake of her head.

"What do we do from here, Fellow Daoist Han?" Jin Tong asked.

Han Li offered no response as he cast his gaze up toward the heavens.

Chapter 1353: Half a Divination

Heavenly Prayer Continent, Heavenmend Sect.

The Rising Dragon Peak was enshrouded in a dense blanket of clouds, and there was a swirling vortex of black mist on the black stone altar on the mountain summit.

Inside the vortex was an elderly head that was suspended in mid-air with nothing to support it. The hair in front of its forehead had already been lost, while the hair on the back was looking very disheveled.

All of a sudden, the head's eyelids fluttered slightly before peeling back to reveal a pair of eyes, one black and one white, the latter of which was clearly blind.

The head looked up with its remaining functioning eye with great difficulty, right as a swirling, corkscrew-shaped cloud vortex descended from the heavens to land at the foot of the nearby peach tree.

The vortex then dissipated to reveal the same white-robed, middle-aged man as last time, seated on a wheelchair that looked as if it had been crafted from white jade.

"You already asked me to conduct divination for you last time, why have you come again?" the elderly head asked in a hoarse voice.

The wheelchair-bound man was none other than Gu Huojin.

"I'm feeling a little uneasy with the Bodhi Banquet coming up so soon, so I must ask you to perform another divination for me," Gu Huojin said.

"One more divination is all that separates me from full assimilation with the Heavenly Dao, and at that point, the promise that you made to me will no longer have any meaning to me," Chen Tuan said.

"This is something that concerns more than just you and me. If I succeed, I will have essentially elevated the Heavenly Dao so that it will no longer have any power over those of us who stand on the mountain summit. Are you not worried that all of our prior efforts with be for nought if you refuse to conduct this divination?" Gu Huojin asked in a calm manner.

A conflicted look appeared on Chen Tuan's face upon hearing this, and after a brief hesitation, he said, "This divination concerns too many Dao Ancestors and involves too much of the Heavenly Dao. It already goes beyond the realm of a heavenly divination, so I can only conduct half a divination. As for what outcome we get, that will be up to the heavens."

"That's fine," Gu Huojin replied with a nod.

Chen Tuan didn't waste any more time with words as he began chanting an incantation.

Due to his inability to make hand seals, the process took around twice as long as last time, but finally, a beam of translucent light shot out of his remaining functioning eye before vanishing into the space up ahead.

......

A long while later, the beam of translucent light faded away, and the vortex behind Chen Tuan suddenly began churning violently as the translucent, black threads extending out of it crawled onto his face before devouring half of his head.

With that, all that remained of him was the half of his face that contained his blind eye.

"How did it go?" Gu Huojin asked.

"From what I could see, everything remains largely the same, but an anomaly has arisen," Chen Tuan replied.

"What is the anomaly?" Gu Huojin asked as his eyes narrowed slightly.

Instead of answering the question, Chen Tuan conjured up a faint breeze, which blew past the back of his head before circling around the ancient peach tree, picking up hundreds of pink flower petals in the process.

The flower petals fell onto the ground to form a tall figure with faint time law powers emanating from within.

Gu Huojin rolled his way over to the figure on his wheelchair, then inspected it momentarily before concluding, "It's Han Li."

"The Reincarnation Palace Master's fate has also been accounted for, so this man remains the only anomaly," Chen Tuan said.

"Now that he's been exposed by your divination, he is no longer an anomaly. I'll personally get rid of him. In doing so, I'll be killing two birds with one stone as he's also the one who currently poses the most potent threat to my position," Gu Huojin said.

Even though Han Li had reached the pinnacle of the cultivation of time law powers, in his eyes, Han Li's understanding of the Heavenly Dao couldn't even begin to compare with his own, so their battle was going to be completely one-sided.

"Good. In that case, there should be no further problems down the line," Chen Tuan said.

With a casual sweep of his sleeve, Gu Huojin scattered the figure formed by the peach flower petals, and a vortex of cloud and mist began to take shape beneath him.

All of a sudden, his expression changed slightly as a faint smile appeared on his face.

"An esteemed guest has come to visit the Heavenly Court, so I'll have to go back. Looks like the task of eradicating the anomaly will have to be assigned to someone else," Gu Huojin said.

"It would be best for you to attend to the anomaly in person," Chen Tuan urged.

"Will a Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array be enough to do the job in my stead?"

After leaving that rhetorical question hanging in the air, Gu Huojin rose up into the air atop the vortex of cloud and mist before vanishing out of sight.

Chen Tuan heaved a forlorn sigh before habitually closing his blind eye.

The ancient peach tree rustled slightly, and a flurry of flowers came raining down from its branches.

......

Middle Earth Immortal Region, Eastern Victory Continent.

There were countless green islands dotted over a boundless sea, and no more than several hundred kilometers away was the easternmost coastline of the Eastern Victory Continent.

In contrast with the jagged, coral-ridden coastline of the Northern Complete Continent, the coastline of the Eastern Victory Continent primarily consisted of sandy beaches, presenting softer and milder lines, like the curvature of a woman's back.

The two islands that were closest to the coastline were also the largest of all of the islands, on each island stood a white stone pillar that was hundreds of thousands of feet tall with dense clusters of divine clouds engraved upon them.

Through the clouds above, one could make out a three-story archway, hanging above which was a huge, red plaque that read "Heaven Answer Gate" in large, golden characters.

This was the eastern heavenly gate of the Middle Earth Immortal Region, and at this moment, there were close to a million armorclad heavenly soldiers stationed here.

Situated at intervals of several dozen kilometers behind these heavenly soldiers were giant immortal generals that stood at over a million feet in height, wielding enormous axes that looked as if they could cleave the very heavens into two.

Situated several thousand kilometers away was another army of hundreds of thousand of armorclad figures, but this army was clearly far less organized and uniform than that of the Heavenly Court.

Additionally, there were many living beings of all shapes and forms standing on the surface of the sea in the distance, bobbing up and down with the waves, and a series of massive shadows could be seen slowly swimming through the depths.

Behind the army of armorclad soldiers was a fleet of spirit boats of different descriptions floating on the surface of the sea. The complex runes engraved onto the boats were all glowing radiantly as they drew upon the world's origin qi in the surrounding environment.

These spirit boats had been arranged into a line, at the center of which was a massive, dark red ship. A huge, three-story palace had been constructed on the ship, and the plaza in front of the palace was packed with people, led by none other than the Reincarnation Palace Master.

"Palace Master..."

All of the people gathered behind the Reincarnation Palace Master fell to one knee while cupping their fists in a parting salute, and the Reincarnation Palace Master instructed in a calm manner, "Proceed according to the plan."

After that, he rose up into the air as a streak of light, hurtling directly toward the eastern heavenly gate.

The Heavenly Court army stationed outside the eastern heavenly gate immediately bristled as they prepared for battle, but the Reincarnation Palace Master seemed to have no intentions of starting a conflict as he drew to a halt outside the heavenly gate, leaving the Heavenly Court's forces at a loss for what to do or what his intentions were.

"Didn't Gu Huojin invite me to the Bodhi Banquet? I'm here now, but it seems like I'm being met with a rather frosty reception," the Reincarnation Palace Master said with a calm smile.

His voice wasn't very loud, but it carried an indescribable, penetrative quality that made all of the Heavenly Court soldiers and generals feel as if a gong had been struck deep within their consciousness, causing their souls to tremble and waver.

Thankfully for them, the Reincarnation Palace Master wasn't trying to harm them with his voice. Instead, he was only making sure that his voice reached the ears of his intended targets.

In the central region of the Eastern Victory Continent was an undulating mountain range, and there was an unremarkable-looking, white daoist temple nestled in the mountain range within a lush forest.

Inside a three-story pavilion in the daoist temple was a white-robed, middle-aged man who was reading a book with keen interest.

The man was quite thin with a pair of bright and clear eyes, coupled with a pronounced nose and a pair of thin lips.

As he read through the book, he couldn't help but habitually stroke his long beard as he murmured to himself, "I wasn't expecting such a twist, but it's a pity that mortals always imagine cultivation to be something so easy. There would always be a powerful cultivation art waiting at the bottom of a cliff, or an unmatched weapon resting deep within a mountain. It makes for a good story, but it's simply too good to be true."

He set down the book and closed it as he spoke, revealing it not to be some cultivation art or secret technique. Instead, it was merely a novel by the name of "Record of a Mortal's Journey to Immortality", written by a mortal who knew nothing about cultivation with the pen name of Wang Yu.

Right at this moment, the man suddenly raised an eyebrow as he murmured to himself, "He's here..."

Chapter 1354: Solo Attendance

The thin daoist priest took a step forward as he spoke, and in the blink of an eye, he appeared outside the eastern heavenly gate.

All of the Heavenly Court's forces were instilled with a sense of great confidence at the sight of the daoist priest, and they greeted collectively in a thunderous voice that shook the heavens, "Welcome, Patriarch Qing Qiu..."

That unremarkable daoist temple was the Heaven Guard Pavilion of the Eastern Victory Continent, while the thin daoist priest was the Dao Ancestor that had been stationed here.

"Sorry for not arranging a more elaborate welcome for an esteemed guest like yourself," Daoist Master Qing Qiu said as he cupped his in a salute rather than extending a daoist salute.

"There's no need for that. It's not like I'm welcome here anyway," the Reincarnation Palace Master said with a smile.

"We had predicted that you would attack the Southern Heavenly Gate or the Western Heavenly Gate, so you've really caught me off guard here," Daoist Master Qing Qiu admitted with an awkward smile.

"That was a reasonable prediction to make. If I were planning to force my way to the Heavenly Court, then those two heavenly gates would indeed be better options to attack. However, seeing as I'm here as a guest, it's best for me to go through your Eastern Heavenly Gate," the Reincarnation Palace Master explained.

"Thankfully, I did make some preparations in advance. A carriage has already been prepared, would you like to come with me?" Daoist Master Qing Qiu offered with a smile.

"Please lead the way, Fellow Daoist Qing Qiu," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied.

Daoist Master Qing Qiu was just about to turn and lead the way when he suddenly faltered slightly before asking, "You're not bringing your entourage with you?"

"There's no need for that. I am the Heavenly Court's sole target, so I won't endanger any members of my entourage," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied with a nonchalant smile.

"You're truly a very remarkable man, Palace Master. If it weren't for the fact that we were on opposing sides, I would've invited you for a drink and a chat," Daoist Master Qing Qiu said with a smile.

"You're very welcome to visit my Reincarnation Palace for a drink anytime," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied.

"If a permanent truce can be established between your Reincarnation Palace and our Heavenly Court during this Bodhi Banquet, then I'll be sure to pay your Reincarnation Palace a visit," Daoist Master Qing Qiu promised with a smile.

The Reincarnation Palace Master offered no response to this.

The two of them arrived before the majestic Heaven Answer Gate, and with a sweep of Daoist Master Qing Qiu's sleeve, the powerful restrictions set up within the gate were withdrawn.

After the two of them entered the gate, the restrictions were reactivated.

Not far away ahead of them was a massive carriage that resembled a pavilion. It was extremely intricately and opulently crafted, and it was drawn by eight Dragon Horses with golden scales all over their bodies.

The eyes of the Dragon Horses were gleaming brightly, and there were clouds of crimson flames beneath their hooves, presenting a spectacular sight to behold.

"This is already quite a grand welcome," the Reincarnation Palace Master remarked.

"Indeed, it is. I would never have been able to enjoy this treatment had I not been accompanying you, so I have you to thank for this experience," Daoist Master Qing Qiu chuckled.

Only after the two of them entered the carriage did the Reincarnation Palace Master discover that its internal space was far more massive than it appeared from the outside.

The eight Dragon Horses broke into a gallop toward the Heavenly Palace Continent at Daoist Master Qing Qiu's behest, leaving long trails of crimson flames behind them as they quickly vanished out of sight.

Inside the carriage, a perplexed look appeared on Daoist Master Qing Qiu's face as he asked, "Please pardon my curiosity, but are you here for a battle or not? You've assembled a mighty army in front of my Eastern Heavenly Gate, yet you're attending the Bodhi Banquet on your own."

"Why don't you take a guess, Fellow Daoist Qing Qiu?" the Reincarnation Palace Master replied in an ambiguous manner.

"This conversation won't go very far if all your answers are going to be like this," Daoist Master Qing Qiu sighed.

"Where is the Bodhi Banquet being held this time, Fellow Daoist Qing Qiu?" the Reincarnation Palace Master asked.

Daoist Master Qing Qiu hesitated momentarily, then replied, "As usual, the main venue will be on the Heavenly Palace Continent, but there are too many people in attendance this time, so several sub-venues have been added on the other continents. There is one on my Eastern Victory Continent as well, so I'll have to return there to oversee proceedings after I've accompanied you to the Heavenly Palace Continent."

"I see, so the entire Middle Earth Immortal Region is serving as the venue for the Bodhi Banquet..."

......

Several days later, Dragon Abyss Immortal Region, Azure Abyss Continent.

Above a vast section of the sea was a blanket of low-hanging dark clouds that looked as if it were on the verge of meeting the surface of the sea.

Howling whirlwinds were sweeping through the area incessantly, raising enormous waves.

A streak of golden light that contained a large spirit boat was racing through the air, giving off bursts of immense immortal spiritual power fluctuations.

Standing at the front of the spirit boat was none other than Han Li.

Following the severance of one's third corpse soul, the next step was to integrate oneself into the Heavenly Dao to reach the status of Dao Ancestor.

However, standing at the end of Han Li's path was Gu Huojin, so there was no way through to the Dao Ancestor throne for him.

Hence, he was currently in a rather awkward situation. He could sense his own connection with the river of time becoming stronger and stronger, yet he was still unable to feel any affinity with the Heavenly Dao.

Standing behind him on the boat were Nangong Wan and Jin Tong, and the former asked in a puzzled manner, "Why has he still voluntarily traveled to the Heavenly Court even after I've already been rescued?"

Han Li knew that she was referring to the Reincarnation Palace Master, and he replied, "All Gan Jiuzhen told me was that he had traveled to the Heavenly Court, but hadn't revealed his reasons for doing so. I'm assuming he instructed her not to disclose his reasons to me."

"You're saying he's intentionally keeping you oblivious to his plans?" Nangong Wan asked, feeling even more befuddled than before.

"I'm just guessing as well. The Reincarnation Palace and the Heavenly Court have been clashing for countless years, and both sides are riddled with moles from the opposition, so perhaps it's better if I act independently of the Reincarnation Palace."

Nangong Wan had a rough idea of what Han Li was alluding to, and she nodded in response.

"There's no need for you to come with me, Jin Tong. With Xuanyuan Jie dead, your vengeance has been exacted. There's no telling what's going to happen on this trip, so there's no need for you to get involved," Han Li said.

"Xuanyuan Jie killed my former incarnation under orders from the Heavenly Court, so his death alone can only count as a partial exaction of vengeance," Jin Tong replied in an expressionless manner.

In reality, she was accompanying Han Li on this trip more so to repay him than for personal vengeance.

Now that she had returned to her Dao Ancestor status, not only did Han Li not have to be concerned for her safety, she was also going to serve as a powerful ally of his, so he didn't try to dissuade her any further.

In the blink of an eye, the spirit boat had already covered a distance of hundreds of thousand of kilometers, and they emerged from the stormy sea to be greeted by the sight of clear, blue skies.

Han Li cast his gaze into the distance, and an alarmed look suddenly appeared on his face as he caught sight of a pair of seabirds swooping down from above.

He immediately positioned himself in front of Nangong Wan as he yelled, "Look out!"

As soon as his voice trailed off, an enormous pillar of silver light suddenly descended from the heavens without any warning, crashing down onto the surface of the sea to send enormous waves erupting in all directions.

Immediately thereafter, four figures shot out of the pillar of silver light before positioning themselves in the south, north, east, and west to surround Han Li's trio.

The one situated to the east was a tall woman in purple with a set of extremely beautiful facial features, but there was a cold and unapproachable look on her face, and she was holding a palm-sized, round, silver mirror with a black rune glowing on its surface.

Situated across from her to the west was a brawny man with a thick beard, clad in a suit of black leather armor. There was a pair of tusks protruding out of his mouth, indicating that he was not human, and he was holding an identical silver mirror to the woman in purple.

The two figures situated in the south and the north were a hunch-backed elderly woman and a white-haired man with a childlike appearance, respectively.

The elderly woman had a set of hideous features, and her face was riddled with deep wrinkles, while a large, black blotch was present on both her forehead and under her chin.

As for the white-haired man, despite his youthful appearance, he had eyes that resembled a pair of bottomless abysses that were filled with boundless darkness, and each of them was also holding a silver mirror.

What was most astonishing of all was that their auras indicated that all four of them were Dao Ancestors.

"Get back in the Flower Branch domain for now," Han Li said as he swept a sleeve through the air to conjure up a door of silver light.

"Be careful," Nangong Wan cautioned with a concerned expression, then stepped into the domain.

In contrast, Jin Tong wasn't concerned at all as she swept a cold gaze over the four figures, then mused, "It's not every day that you get to see four Dao Ancestors in one place. Do you think they're here for you or me?"

"Now's not the time to be joking around. There's something strange about those mirrors, so we have to get out of here as soon as possible," Han Li said in a serious manner.

"In that case, I'll just have to break their mirrors..."

As soon as Jin Tong's voice trailed off, she vanished from the spot without any warning, only to instantly reappear behind the brawny man amid an eruption of radiant, golden light.

Immediately thereafter, she reached out with both hands to conjure up a golden vortex that gave off bursts of devouring force.

Chapter 1355: Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array

The brawny man seemed to have anticipated this, and he took a step back to distance himself from Jin Tong while simultaneously making a string of hand seals and chanting an incantation.

His three companions also sprang into action, and they were moving in perfect synchronicity.

A sense of foreboding welled up in Han Li's heart upon seeing this, and he hurriedly called out to Jin Tong while releasing his time spirit domain.

However, only half of his spirit domain had unfurled when a gargantuan, silver array emerged over the seabed below, encompassing an area with a radius of hundreds of thousand of kilometers.

A burst of peculiar spatial fluctuations instantly rose up from the seabed to encompass the entire surrounding area.

An alarmed look appeared on Han Li's face upon seeing this, and he hurriedly grabbed onto Jin Tong, who had just flown back to his side, then conjured up a golden lightning teleportation array.

The two of them vanished from the spot with a loud thunderclap, only to reappear no more than ten thousand feet away, still situated above the array on the seabed.

"The surrounding space has been sealed," Han Li said with slightly furrowed brows.

"We'll just have to break the seal then," Jin Tong replied with a nonchalant grin.

All of a sudden, a burst of blinding, silver light appeared from each of the four directions, and a thick pillar of silver light erupted out of the surface of the silver mirrors held by the four Dao Ancestors before racing toward the pillar of silver light that had descended from the heavens.

As the four beams of silver light entered the pillar of silver light, countless silver projections were conjured up, as if there were thousands of mirrors reflecting one another, forming a series of irregular light barriers that layered themselves on top of one another to encompass the entire sky.

In the next instant, the silver light barrier began to resonate with the seabed array, and the entire area encompassed within the array was instantly basked in dazzling, silver light.

Before Han Li and Jin Tong had a chance to do anything, their surroundings began to transform.

The bright, blue sky instantly turned into a dark night sky, while the surrounding space was peeled away layer by layer to reveal the suffocating darkness underneath.

The entire area had been plunged into boundless darkness, with no sources of light aside from what was emanating from Han Li and Jin Tong's bodies.

"Is this an illusion?" Jin Tong asked in a perplexed manner.

"It's not an illusion, it's an extremely advanced spatial secret technique. Right now, we are no longer in the Dragon Abyss Immortal Region," Han Li replied as he inspected his surroundings with his Infernal Devilish Eyes.

Only now did he come to understand why he had failed to detect that array with his spiritual sense earlier.

As it turned out, the array was never in the Dragon Abyss Immortal Region to begin with. Instead, it had been summoned there by the four Dao Ancestors before being activated by their collective power.

"It seems like our auras are the only ones present here. They did all of this just to throw us in here? There's no world's origin qi in this place, but that doesn't really have much of an impact on us anyway," Jin Tong mused in a puzzled manner.

"If you expand your spiritual sense a little further, you'll discover that this is a cage. If I'm not mistaken, they intend to imprison us here," Han Li said.

Jin Tong did as he suggested, and sure enough, she quickly made the same discovery.

A massive spatial fortress formed by some type of extremely peculiar spatial power had taken shape around them, trapping them in the center.

"Could it be that they've imprisoned us here to prevent us from getting to the Heavenly Court?" Jin Tong asked.

"I presume so. Honestly, I'm a little flattered that the Heavenly Court holds me in such high regard that they sent four Dao Ancestors to imprison a Great Encompassment cultivator like me, especially on the cusp of the Bodhi Banquet," Han Li remarked with a smile.

"You've already severed all three corpse souls and defeated two of the Heavenly Court's Dao Ancestors, one of whom was Xuanyuan Jie, one of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords. Is it really that much of a surprise that they see you as such a major threat?" Jin Tong chuckled.

Han Li heaved an internal sigh upon hearing this.

Indeed, given his current powers, it really wouldn't have been surprising even if Gu Huojin had come after him in person.

"They must be delusional if they think this place can trap us!" Jin Tong said as she rubbed her hands together, and it was clear that she was raring to go.

"Let's try and find a way out," Han Li said, and Jin Tong nodded in response before racing away as a streak of golden light.

Several seconds later, an eruption of bright, golden light appeared in the darkness millions of kilometers as a gargantuan golden beetle crashed into something with a deafening boom.

Immediately thereafter, a vast spatial barrier appeared in that direction, and a series of silver ripples ran over its surface, spreading into infinity and beyond.

With her first attack proving ineffective, Jin Tong immediately made a second attempt, this time conjuring up a sharp, corkscrew-shaped pillar of light in front of herself before crashing into the spatial barrier again.

Another earth-shattering boom rang out as Jin Tong was sent flying back through the air, while the spatial barrier remained completely unscathed.

Right as she was about to make a third attempt, Han Li intervened.

"There's something strange about this space. The spatial barrier seems to be connected to some type of vast power, so it's going to be very difficult to break our way out using brute force. Let's take a look to see if there are any weak points that can be exploited."

Jin Tong reverted back to her human form upon hearing this, and after a brief discussion, they parted ways, moving in different directions to examine the spatial barrier.

......

Outside the vast spatial barrier was a dark space similar to the Extraheavensphere, and at this moment, the four Dao Ancestors were hovering outside the spatial barrier, scrutinizing Han Li and Jin Tong intently.

From within the spatial barrier, one could see nothing but a boundless expanse of darkness, but strangely enough, looking in from the outside, it was as clear as day.

"Do you think they'll be able to break this Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array, Zi Shan?" the brawny man asked.

"Even if the four of us were trapped in there, we may not be able to break our way out, so I would think the array will be able to trap them for at least ten thousand years," the tall woman in purple replied.

"Why do you ask that, Dong Lihu? Are you not confident in the array?" the hideous elderly woman asked.

"I must admit that I'm a little apprehensive, Fellow Daoist Zhu Yan. One of them is the Devouring Dao Ancestor, while the other has cultivated the laws of time to the pinnacle of the Great Encompassment Stage and poses a potent threat even to the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords, so surely there's some cause for concern," Dong Lihu replied.

"The Ubiquitous Path Myriad Immortal Array combines the power of ten immortal regions, with dozens of Great Encompassment cultivators, hundreds of High Zenith cultivators, and thousands of Golden Immortals stationed in each immortal region. If they manage to break out of this array, I, for one, would be too ashamed to even return to the Heavenly Court," the elderly woman by the name of Zhu Yan harrumphed coldly.

She cast her gaze into the distance as she spoke, and there were ten massive gates hovering in the darkness, each of which was connected to a different immortal region.

A different piece of scenery was visible through each gate, including a mountain summit, an island on the sea, and a vast, primordial forest.

Enormous arrays had been erected in all of these locations, and at the center of each array was a massive stone pillar that stood at close to a hundred thousand feet tall, with all manners of runes engraved upon them.

The Great Encompassment, High Zenith, and Golden Immortal cultivators that Zhu Yan had mentioned were all seated around the stone pillars, focused intently on manning the arrays.

Rings of silver light were constantly rising up from the ground beneath them before rising up into the air and fusing into the stone pillars at the center of the arrays.

The world's origin qi in these ten immortal regions was being devoured by the arrays at an alarming rate, and as a result, there were many places that weren't abundant with the world's origin qi to begin with in which forests were withering away and rivers were drying up.

The Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array was unmatched in terms of the number of powerful cultivators and the sheer amount of the world's origin qi required to support it, and Han Li and Jin Tong could've never imagined that they were contending against the collective might of ten immortal regions and over ten thousand immortals, not to mention the four Dao Ancestors at the helm.

Right at this moment, the white-haired man with the childlike features suddenly said, "By the way, Fellow Daoist Zhu Yan, if I recall correctly, the orders we received from the Heavenly Court were to trap these two in the array and kill them, right?"

"You make that sound so easy, Fellow Daoist Meng Yuan. Did you not hear about Xuanyuan Jie's demise? He was one of the five elemental Essential Dao Ancestors, so his powers were most definitely beyond ours," Zhu Yan said.

"I have heard about this, but according to my sources, that was a very unconvincing victory. Not only did he have that Gold Devouring Immortal's help, Xuanyuan Jie's complacency also played a large part in his defeat," Yuan Meng countered.

"In that case, have you heard that Feng Qingshui also almost met his demise by Han Li's hands? That time, he didn't have the Gold Devouring Immortal to help him," Zhu Yan sneered.

Chapter 1356: Prestigious Gathering

"Fellow Daoist Zhu Yan is right. It's clear from their aura fluctuations that they're not going to be easy to deal with. On top of that, all of us are Dao Ancestors bound by the restrictions of the Heavenly Dao, so it's simply not worth it for us to go all-out in a battle here," Dong Lihu said.

"Gu Huojin personally issued this order, so we can't just blatantly ignore it," Meng Yuan said in a hesitant manner.

"If you insist on doing something, then why don't you go in and engage them in battle first? We'll be sure to assist you using the power of the array," Zhu Yan suggested with a smile.

Meng Yuan's eyes narrowed slightly in fury upon hearing this.

"That's enough. All we have to do is ensure that they can't travel to the Heavenly Court, there's no need for us to go above and beyond. Once the Bodhi Banquet is over, Gu Huojin can deal with them himself," Zi Shan interjected in an authoritative manner.

It was clear that she was the leader of the group, and her verdict was final.

Meng Yuan heaved an internal sigh of relief upon hearing this. Of course he didn't actually want to go up against Han Li, he had only protested against the others so he would appear in a better light.

After all, it was the others who had refused to fight, while he had been eager to follow Gu Huojin's orders, on the surface, at least.

"How unfortunate that we're stuck here while the Bodhi Banquet is being held. Looks like we won't get to taste the Bodhi Dao Fruit," Zhu Yan sighed in a disappointed manner.

This was a sobering thought for her companions as well, and it only served to further fuel their resentment toward Han Li and Jin Tong.

......

Middle Earth Immortal Region.

A mighty fleet of giant spirit boats had been assembled on the sea outside the Southern Gaze Continent's Heaven Answer Gate, and all of them were carrying large flags with the words "Reincarnation Palace" emblazoned upon them.

There were countless people on the spirit boats and hovering in the air above the sea, most of whom were wearing Reincarnation Palace attire complete with Reincarnation Palace masks of different colors.

There was a row of seven or eight figures standing side by side on the spirit boat at the forefront of the fleet, six of whom were wearing black masks, while the remaining two stood with their faces uncovered.

One of the two was a muscular young man with a head of short, silver hair. There was a black cloth over his face that concealed only his mouth and nose, and his exposed eyes were flashing with fierce killing intent.

There were also two green sabers strapped to his back, neither of which had a scabbard. The sabers were a crystalline, green color, and there was faint, green mist constantly emanating from within, as if they were breathing like a pair of living beings.

Standing beside him was none other than Wu Yang, whose brows were tightly furrowed as he asked, "Tan Lang, the palace master has already entered the Heavenly Court, right?"

"He's already gone through the eastern heavenly gate, and the Bodhi Banquet is set to commence in a few hours," the silver-haired young man replied.

"How are things going on Yan Zhuo and Xuan Yu's end?" Wu Yang asked, and it was clear that he was feeling a little uneasy.

"Lighten up a bit, they're the ones who should be nervous," Tan Lang said as he pointed a finger at the vast Heaven Answer Gate in the distance.

Wu Yang cast his gaze toward the direction that he was pointing in to discover a series of giant pillars of light of different colors rising up from the ground behind the Heaven Answer Gate, giving off bursts of formidable spatial fluctuations.

That was where the major teleportation arrays connecting the Southern Gaze Continent to other immortal regions were situated, and at the moment, there were many powerful figures from all over the True Immortal Realm arriving through the arrays, with no lack of Dao Ancestors and Great Encompassment cultivators among them.

"My Cold Jade Sabers are thirsting for their blood," Tan Lang cackled.

Beneath the black cloth over his face was a horrific scar that ran from the bottom of his ear to his mouth.

......

In addition to the eastern and southern heavenly gates, a mighty Reincarnation Palace army had been assembled outside the western heavenly gate as well, and it had already been locked in a confrontation against the Heavenly Court's forces for quite some time.

Both sides had made some provocative gestures, but no battle had broken out thus far.

Meanwhile, the northern heavenly gate was welcoming the most guests out of the four heavenly gates, with cultivators from all immortal regions constantly streaming in through the various teleportation arrays.

All nine continents in the Middle Earth Immortal Region were joyously celebrating the imminent commencement of the Bodhi Banquet, and even though some of the sects in the Middle Earth Immortal Region didn't have the privilege of attending the Bodhi Banquet, they were also taking advantage of this opportunity to hold celebratory events of their own.

All of the major trading houses were also making full use of this opportunity to hold all types of auctions and exchange events, attracting countless eager cultivators.

However, compared with the main event that was the Bodhi Banquet, these events were made to appear all too insignificant. At the moment, all of the most powerful and prestigious figures across the entire True Immortal Realm were gathered in the banquet venues across the nine continents of the immortal region.

The central region of the Heavenly Palace Continent was an enormous basin, which was home to many of the important offices of the Heavenly Court. The main venue for this edition fo the Bodhi Banquet was nestled high up in the clouds directly above this area.

Regardless of from which angle one looked up at the clouds above the basin, they would only be able to see a vast expanse of rainbow light, and if they were lucky, they would even be greeted by the sight of all types of stunning apparitions, such as soaring pegasi and dancing celestial maidens.

In reality, there was an enormous floating island that was hundreds of thousands of kilometers in area above this sea of clouds. This place was known as the Jade Pond Paradise, and it was the long-term residence of Gu Huojin.

The Jade Pond Paradise was surrounded by a ring-shaped mountain range that was filled with a vast abundance of spiritual qi, and numerous waterfalls could be seen flowing down from the mountain cliffs, presenting a stunning sight to behold.

Herds of nine-colored divine deer were sipping from the pools at the feet of the waterfalls, looking relaxed and content.

Occasionally, the cry of an ape would ring out from the nearby forest, and fleeting glimpses of immortal apes swinging from tree to tree could be caught from time to time.

High up in the sky above the forest, flocks of immortal cranes were soaring through the heavens in a leisurely manner, and their calls resembled beautiful immortal melodies.

Even higher up in the sky, countless streaks of light were converging toward the center of the Jade Pond Paradies, containing various types of carriages, spirit beast steeds, and immortals dressed in opulent clothing.

The closer one drew to the center of the Jade Pond Paradise, the more abundant the world's origin qi became, to the point that all of the dew on the immortal plants and spirit trees in the forests were manifested from pure spiritual qi.

Every morning and night, a large number of celestial maidens would be sent out to collect this dew to be used to brew the most delectable wines and elixirs.

In the central area of the Jade Pond Paradise was a clear lake that was dozens of kilometers in radius. Its surface was as smooth as a mirror, and it was named Pure Clear Lake.

Behind Pure Clear Lake was an old locust tree that very few people could confidently state the exact age of. It stood at over ten thousand feet tall, and its canopy was so vast that it encompassed close to half of the entire lake below.

At the foot of the old locust tree was a two-story pavilion that was no more than thirty feet tall, and it was where Gu Huojin cultivated.

A giant, semicircular plaza had also been constructed outside of Pure Clear Lake, and the plaza resembled a fully unfurled folding fan.

It had been entirely constructed from white spirit jade, and it was riddled with channels that were around two feet wide to draw in the water of Pure Clear Lake, dividing the entire plaza into a series of rectangular sections.

There were tens of thousands of purple jade tables placed in these rectangular areas, all of which were laden with all types of fresh spirit fruits and vegetables for the guests of the Bodhi Banquet to enjoy.

There were also slightly raised platforms situated at intervals of several thousand feet, upon which stunning celestial maidens in palace dresses danced to beautiful music.

At the center of the plaza were seven purple jade tables, all of which were currently vacant.

Not far away from this row of seven tables was a collection of close to a hundred seats, several dozens of which had already been filled.

All of these people possessed unfathomably powerful auras, and they were all patriarchs of sects that were vastly renowned across the entire True Immortal Region.

Some of them had already become legends that had already been forgotten by all but the oldest generations of cultivators under the heavens, and most of them were seated with their eyes closed in meditation.

In contrast, the young disciples standing behind them were all looking around in intrigue and curiosity, but given that they were all from major sects, they remained quite restrained and observant of proper etiquette.

However, there were also some exceptions to this norm. For example, there was a white-haired elderly woman seated at a table slightly to the right of the center of the collection of tables, and her body was swaying back and forth like tall grass in a light breeze. It seemed that she had fallen asleep, yet somehow managed to catch herself every time right before she swayed beyond the point of no return.

Seated behind her was a beautiful, white-robed woman who was also swaying back and forth in the same sleepy manner, and right at this moment, numerous tiny arcs of purple lightning suddenly appeared over her body, preparing to erupt in all directions.

Right at this moment, the white-haired elderly woman snapped wide awake, then swiveled around before pressing a hand against her disciple's forehead.

The arcs of lightning flashing over her body instantly faded, and she woke up in a dazed manner.

"Menghan, I've already told you this many times before. You can cultivate the Five Lightning True Mantra, but you can't simultaneously cultivate both my Fantastical Dream Mantra and the Five Lightning True Mantra at once. Otherwise, you could easily hurt yourself," the elderly woman said in an earnest and heartfelt manner.

The white-robed woman was none other than Yu Menghan.

After parting ways with Han Li back in Nine Origins City, she caught the eye of the matriarch of the Dream Cloud Sect, who took Yu Menghan under her wing as her final disciple.

Chapter 1357: Trapped

"Was I using the Five Lightning True Mantra in my dreams again?" Yu Menghan asked in a surprised manner.

"What am I ever going to do with you..." the elderly woman sighed, but there was a look of doting affection in her eyes.

It had been over ten million years since she had founded the Dream Cloud Sect, but she hadn't been able to find a disciple capable of fully harnessing her teachings. She had stumbled upon Yu Menghan by chance, drawn to her in a dream, and she knew from that moment onward that fate had finally brought her a worthy heir.

Over the course of her extensive cultivation journey, she had managed to reach the pinnacle of the Great Encompassment Stage, and she had always yearned to make the final breakthrough to become the Dream Dao Ancestor, but her hope had waned over time.

Her fated encounter with Yu Menghan had given her another option, and she had placed all over her hope upon her prized disciple.

As it turned out, she did indeed possess exceptional aptitude when it came to cultivating the laws of dreams, and as long as she was willing to work hard in her cultivation, she had a bright future ahead with such a capable mistress to guide her.

However, what was rather exasperating to the elderly woman was that Yu Menghan seemed to have rather stubborn ties to the past, and she was unable to set aside the Five Lightning True Mantra. Whenever she entered a state of slumber to cultivate the Fantastical Dream Mantra, she would always involuntarily cultivate the Five Lightning True Mantra on the side.

The elderly woman simply couldn't bring herself to scold her prized disciple, so in the end, she could only relent as she said, "The Bodhi Banquet is about to begin soon. Once you receive your Bodhi Dao Fruit, make sure to cherish it. It's something that could have life-altering consequences for your cultivation."

"I get one as well?" Yu Menghan asked as her eyes lit up with excitement.

"Of course not. Only those who were officially invited by the Heavenly Court or possess Bodhi Tokens are granted Bodhi Dao Fruits. However, at this stage in my cultivation, the benefits of consuming a Bodhi Dao Fruit are very limited for me, so you can have mine," the elderly woman replied with a smile.

"No, I can't do that! It's yours, Mistress!" Yu Menghan hurriedly protested.

"You don't know how precious these Bodhi Dao Fruits are, you silly girl. They're greatly cherished even by Dao Ancestors, let alone High Zenith and Great Encompassment cultivators. Of course, these dao fruits are split into different grades, and they're assigned in accordance with one's cultivation base and ties to the Heavenly Court," the elderly woman explained.

"What's the grade of your..."

Yu Menghan's voice trailed off here as she felt like this was a rather inappropriate question to ask.

"I'm entitled to a dao fruit of the highest grade, of course. Once you receive it, don't consume it right away. I'll preserve it using a secret technique, and after we return to the Dream Cloud Sect, I'll feed the fruit to you one slice at a time so you're not overwhelmed by its power," the elderly woman said with a doting smile.

Right at this moment, a male voice rang out from nearby.

"How generous of you, Fellow Daoist Meng Po. These Bodhi Dao Fruits were refined by Gu Huojin himself over extensive periods of time while incorporating many types of law powers. Just as you said, they're highly sought after even among Dao Ancestors, yet you're giving yours to your disciple?"

The elderly woman didn't even bother turning to see who it was that had spoken as she snapped, "I'll give my dao fruit to whoever I want. Mind your own business, you old fart!"

Yu Menghan turned to discover that the one who had spoken was a tall, gray-robed elderly man.

His rather ragged gray robe presented a stark contrast with the opulent attire worn by everyone else, and despite Meng Po's abrasive response, the man remained unbothered as he smiled and said, "For those who have yet to attain the Great Dao, consuming the Bodhi Dao Fruit will help them under the Great Dao, while for those who have already reached the pinnacle, consuming the Bodhi Dao Fruit will help them stave off the assimilation of the Heavenly Dao..."

"Shut your mouth, Cang Wu! I told you to mind your own business!" Meng Po snapped in a disgruntled manner, and the gray-robed elderly man immediately fell into a sheepish silence.

"Is this senior telling the truth, Mistress?" Yu Menghan asked.

Since becoming Meng Po's disciple, she had accrued an immense amount of knowledge and experience and even become privy to some of the secrets of the True Immortal Realm. Hence, after hearing what True Lord Cang Wu had to say, she quickly came to realize that these Bodhi Dao Fruits were even more precious than she had imagined.

"Of course he's telling the truth. Otherwise, why would a Dao Ancestor like him have pledged his subordination to the Heavenly Court? Of course, everyone is fearful of Gu Huojin, but ultimately, he was roped in by the benefits offered to him by the Heavenly Court," Meng Po replied through voice transmission.

Upon hearing confirmation from Meng Po, Yu Menghan decided there and then that she was absolutely not going to consume this Bodhi Dao Fruit.

At the same time, she knew that True Lord Cang Wu had intentionally revealed this to her in the hopes that Meng Po would consume her dao fruit, and with that in mind, she communicated to him through voice transmission, "Thank you for revealing this to me, Senior."

True Lord Cang Wu faltered slightly upon hearing this, then turned to Meng Po with a smile as he remarked, "You've found yourself a fine disciple, Meng Po."

He then strode over to a table not far away from Meng Po's before sitting down with his eyes closed.

Yu Menghan swept her gaze over the lively and bustling scenes around her, and for som reason, a hint of sorrow welled up in her heart as the image of Han Li surfaced in her mind.

I wonder where he is right now...

......

Inside the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array.

Han Li was hovering in the pitch-black space with seventy-two sword spirit children flying around him, forming the Almighty Sword Array.

Golden lightning was flashing incessantly as the seventy-two children reverted back into golden flying swords, and the sword qi emanating from the flying swords combined to form a golden heavenly gate.

Compared with the normal heavenly gate conjured up by the Almighty Sword Array, this one was far less impressive and had a rather illusory appearance, but the lightning law powers that it contained were still extremely formidable, much to the astonishment of the four Dao Ancestors looking on from outside the array.

"How is this possible? He's clearly a cultivator of the laws of time, yet his bonded flying swords are imbued with incredibly fearsome lightning law powers!" Zhu Ya exclaimed.

Her three companions exchanged a bewildered glance with one another, and none of them were able to give her an answer.

Right at this moment, the heavenly gate in the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array suddenly sprang open, and countless golden lightning wyrms came flooding out from within, rushing toward the edge of the array in a frenzy.

A resounding explosion rang out as the mighty flight of golden lightning wyrms crashed into the array before exploding like balls of golden fire.

Incredibly fearsome shockwaves swept through the entire space encompassed within the array, while arcs of golden lightning sprang through the air in all directions.

Han Li flashed rapidly through the air, evading the shockwaves that were sweeping through the space around him while looking on with tightly furrowed brows.

Not only had this array completely sealed this space away, trapping himself and Jin Tong within it, even the shockwaves from their attacks weren't able to escape, instead bouncing back and forth within this space until they dissipated on their own.

Hundreds of thousands of kilometers away, Jin Tong was lashing out repeatedly at another section of the spatial barrier with her fists, causing the nearby space to rumble like thunder.

At the same time, dozens of mountain ranges within the ten immortal regions connected to the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array were trembling violently, while dozens of volcanoes were erupting in unison, and waves of unprecedented magnitudes were sweeping over vast sections of the sea.

All of the cultivators in the ten arrays were also having to bear the power of Han Li and Jin Tong's attacks, and the Great Encompassment cultivators were able to hold their own just fine, while the High Zenith cultivators were clearly struggling.

As for the Golden Immortals, they were faring even worse, and many of them had fallen unconscious to the ground with blood trickling out of all of these orifices.

However, as soon as someone collapsed, they would immediately be replaced, so the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array remained as steady and resilient as ever, much to the relief of the four Dao Ancestors.

"If that's all they've got, then we can easily trap them in here for months!" Meng Yuan said.

"Don't get complacent. Make sure to keep a close eye on everything and immediately address any holes that appear," Zi Shan said in a cautious manner, and her three companions immediately gave a collective, affirmative response.

Inside the array, Han Li had already withdrawn his flying swords and was hovering in mid-air in a contemplative silence.

A streak of golden light flew over to his side from the distance, then faded away to reveal Jin Tong.

"I can't do anything to this array," she grumbled as she crossed her arms in a frustrated manner.

"This area has been completely sealed away, so my Almighty Sword Array is unable to connect with heaven and earth. As a result, it's nowhere near as powerful as it normally is, and it was also unable to break this array," Han Li said.

All of a sudden, an idea seemed to have occurred to Jin Tong, and he proposed, "How about instead of attacking the spatial barrier, we each unleash an attack at each other and see if the power generated by the clash can tear this space apart? If we can do that, then we'll be able to escape into the Extraheavensphere through the resulting spatial rift!"

Han Li considered the idea for a moment, then decided that it was worth a try.

Thus, the two of them quickly flew back until there was a distance of tens of thousands of kilometers between them, following which they engaged in a clash between fist and sword.

A deafening boom rang out as bursts of shockwaves swept through the surrounding space, rebounding back and forth against the spatial barrier.

Jin Tong flew back to Han Li's side, dodging the oncoming shockwaves along the way, and the two of them exchanged a disappointed glance with one another.

The clash between their attacks had caused the space to tremble violently, but not even the tiniest of spatial rifts had appeared.

Chapter 1358: Unwelcome Guest

"Perhaps there wasn't enough power because we didn't go all-out," Jin Tong suggested, unwilling to give up on her idea just yet.

"If we engage in an all-out clash, we may be able to tear open this space, but there's also a good chance that we'll sustain injuries in the process, leaving ourselves vulnerable to those four Dao Ancestors," Han Li replied with a shake of his head.

"What the hell is up with this array? It doesn't seem to have any weaknesses to exploit! It's like we've been devoured into the belly of some mighty beast!" Jin Tong exclaimed in a disgruntled manner.

Han Li's eyes abruptly lit up at the mention of the word "devoured", and seeing this change in his expression, an idea also quickly occurred to Jin Tong.

"Maybe I can use my devouring law powers to devour this entire space and suck in the array in the process!"

"That's exactly what I was thinking. This space serves as the foundation for this array, so if you devour this space, then the array will surely be affected. Once that happens, it shouldn't be difficult for us to break it," Han Li replied with a nod.

"It won't be difficult for me to devour this space, but ideally, I don't want to be interrupted in the process. Otherwise, if I have to use my law powers over and over again, that'll only accelerate my assimilation with the Heavenly Dao," Jin Tong said.

"You focus on devouring this space, I'll make sure that you're not interrupted," Han Li said in a confident manner.

With the decision made, Jin Tong immediately began flying toward a corner of the array.

Along the way, she took on her Gold Devouring Beetle form and began tearing at the space around her, while a golden vortex took shape in her gaping mouth.

A chunk of space instantly came collapsing toward her, and a pleased smile appeared on Han Li's face upon seeing this.

Outside the array, Zi Shan and the others were looking on with hesitant expressions.

"We shouldn't have trapped that Gold Devouring Immortal in there with him," Meng Yuan sighed.

"Way to state the obvious! What the hell do we do now?" Zhu Yan snapped.

"What do you say, Fellow Daoist Zi Shan?" Dong Lihu asked, and the other two Dao Ancestors also turned to Zi Shan for a verdict.

"If we let them escape, we'll have Gu Huojin to answer to, so I'm afraid that's not an acceptable outcome," Zi Shan sighed.

Dong Lihu nodded in response, then pressed a palm down onto the spatial barrier before him.

A wave of ripples surged over the spatial barrier, allowing him to step into the array.

Meanwhile, Meng Yuan lowered his gaze toward the space down below, seemingly not intending to enter the array right away.

"Even the four of us combined aren't guaranteed to be able to defeat those two, so if any of you try to hang back or refuse to put in your full effort, then even if you manage to survive, you won't be getting away free of consequences, do I make myself clear?" Zi Shan warned in a cold voice.

Zhu Yan took a disdainful glance at Meng Yuan, then entered the array after Dong Lihu, while Zi Shan and Meng Yuan brought up the rear.

Han Li was immediately able to detect the arrival of the four Dao Ancestors, and he directed his gaze toward them as he sneered, "You've finally decided to show up!"

......

Heavenly Palace Continent.

More and more prestigious immortals continued to enter the Bodhi Banquet venue in the Jade Pond Paradise before being guided to their seats by the celestial maidens of the Heavenly Court.

Even with the beautiful music and dance performances put on by the celestial maidens, the atmosphere in the venue was rather solemn.

Aside from a very small number of acquaintances who were gathered in small groups, quietly chatting among themselves, the majority of the banquet's attendees were seated on their cushions, either meditating with their eyes closed or silently watching the dancing celestial maidens, waiting for the arrival of their host.

Most of the seats near the center of the venue had been occupied by representatives of sects that had very close ties with the Heavenly Court, and they were often on very good terms with the immortal palaces of their respective immortal regions.

The two Great Encompassment Stage patriarchs of the Dharma Union Sect and Molten Chamber Mountain weren't sitting together, but they were communicating with one another through voice transmission.

One of them, an azure-robed, middle-aged man asked, "Did you enjoy a smooth journey on your way here, Fellow Daoist Sui Gu?"

Sui Gu was a brocade-robed elderly man, and he replied, "I did, but I heard that many of our fellow daoists were attacked and perished on the way here, including Fellow Daoist Hu Liang, who you and I are both familiar with."

"Have you seen the armies assembled outside the eastern, southern, and western heavenly gates? It looks like the Reincarnation Palace is out in full force this time," the azure-robed man continued.

"It's very impressive that the Reincarnation Palace Master has been able to oppose the Heavenly Court all this time, but it's far too reckless of him to be attacking at a time like this. In fact..."

Sui Gu's voice abruptly trailed off into an awkward smile as he realized that he was speaking on matters that he had no right to comment on.

"I'm sure the Heavenly Court also wants to take advantage of this opportunity to eradicate the Reincarnation Palace once and for all. Given that we are guests of the Heavenly Court, perhaps we're obligated to help out," the azure-robed man said.

"I think self-preservation should be our top priority at all times," Sui Gu objected.

"A clash between Supreme Lord Gu Huojin and the Reincarnation Palace Master will truly be a battle for the ages. I must admit that I'm rather looking forward to seeing it happen," the azure-robed man said with a smile.

As soon as his voice trailed off, a small commotion suddenly rang out from behind them, and they turned to discover a thin figure in a black and white daoist robe leading a black-robed man into the venue, the latter of whom had his face completely concealed behind a veiled hat.

"Who is that? He must be someone very important to have been personally escorted here by Daoist Master Qing Qiu..."

"Could it be..."

"Could it be him?"

"No way! Even if he dares to come here, surely he wouldn't do it alone! Does he have a death wish?"

"Why wouldn't he dare to come alone? I heard that Supreme Lord Xuanyuan Jie has recently met his demise, and it was most likely at his hands."

"Well, well, well, things are certainly going to get interesting now!"

......

As the two figures made their way down the white jade path, the nearby banquet attendees erupted into chatter, and many of them had risen to their feet with stunned and apprehensive expressions.

"It's the Reincarnation Palace Master!" Sui Gu exclaimed in a quiet voice, while the azure-robed man was looking on in a speechless manner.

The Reincarnation Palace Master had never revealed his true appearance to anyone, and his location had always been one of the biggest mysteries of the True Immortal Realm, but all of the banquet attendees present were some of the most powerful figures in existence, and they were able to identify him based on his attire and his aura.

Under everyone's intense scrutiny, even Daoist Master Qing Qiu was beginning to feel the pressure, and a few beads of cold sweat had appeared on his forehead.

In contrast, the Reincarnation Palace Master seemed completely unflustered, not even bothering to spare a glance at the stunned bystanders as he followed along behind Daoist Master Qing Qiu.

Right at this moment, a thunderous roar suddenly rang out from near the front of the venue.

"There is no place here for you, Reincarnation Palace Master!"

Yu Menghan was rather startled by this outburst from True Lord Cang Wu. He had appeared so mild and amicable just a moment ago, yet he was suddenly livid with rage.

This was exactly what Daoist Master Qing Qiu feared would happen, and he was left at a loss for what to do.

True Lord Cang Wu had no descendants, only a prized disciple that he regarded as his own son.

Back when he had been serving in the Blazing Heavens Immortal Palace, he had been sent out to capture Gan Jiuzhen, and he very nearly succeeded, but she was ultimately able to slip away from what had seemed like a dire situation.

In the wake of her near-capture, the Reincarnation Palace Master sent out Tan Lang of the eight reincarnation envoys to attack the Blazing Heavens Immortal Palace, slaughtering all of the Heavenly Court cultivators inside, including True Lord Cang Wu's prized disciple.

To this day, it remained unclear to everyone except for the Reincarnation Palace Master why the Reincarnation Palace had retaliated against the Blazing Heavens Immortal Palace in such brutal fashion.

From that day forth, Tan Lang and the Reincarnation Palace Master had been regarded as sworn enemies of True Lord Cang Wu, and the scar on Tan Lang's face had been left behind by none other than True Lord Cang Wu.

The Reincarnation Palace Master took a calm glance at True Lord Cang Wu, then asked, "Who're you?"

True Lord Cang Wu was even more infuriated to hear this, and his aura instantly swelled to a peak, putting his almighty power as a Dao Ancestor on full display as he prepared to throw himself at the Reincarnation Palace Master.

"Don't be reckless, Fellow Daoist Cang Wu!" Meng Po warned while shielding Yu Menghan behind her.

However, True Lord Cang Wu's fury had driven him far beyond the point of rationality, and he ignored her warnings as he took a step forward, causing the entire Jade Pond Paradise to shudder violently.

"Please stand down, Fellow Daoist Cang Wu. The Reincarnation Palace Master is an esteemed guest that was invited here by Supreme Lord Gu Huojin himself," Daoist Master Qing Qiu declared as he reluctantly stepped forward to mediate.

"Get out of my way!" True Lord Cang Wu spat through gritted teeth as veins began bulging on his forehead.

Daoist Master Qing Qiu's expression darkened slightly as he prepared to pacify True Lord Cang Wu by force.

Before the situation could escalate any further, an authoritative voice suddenly rang out across the entire Jade Pond Paradise.

"This is a day for celebration and peace, Fellow Daoist Cang Wu..."

Everyone immediately looked up into the heavens upon hearing this, while True Lord Cang Wu stopped cold in his tracks, then slowly turned back as he forcibly stifled his own fury.

Immediately thereafter, several figures suddenly appeared behind the seven jade tables situated right next to Pure Clear Lake, bringing with them a pleasant aroma.

At the very center of the group was none other than Gu Huojin, seated on his white jade wheelchair, and to his left was Chi Rong, the Essential Fire Dao Ancestor.

Chapter 1359: Commencement of the Banquet

Seated on Gu Huojin's right was a beautiful young woman in a short, blue dress, presenting a stark contrast with Chi Rong on Gu Huojin's left. There was a sweet smile on her face, and her long, black hair had been arranged into countless little braids around the pair of delicate dragon horns on her head.

Her appearance and attire both struck the beholder with the impression that she was just a harmless young woman, but in reality, she was the Essential Water Dao Ancestor, Chen Ruyan.

Her aura was the polar opposite to Chi Rong's, and it felt as if their Great Daos were conflicting with one another. As a result, both of them held an innate distaste for each other, and they were stoically looking away from one another, clearly not on very good terms.

Seated to the other side of Chi Rong was Patriarch Li Yuanjiu of the Nine Origins Temple. For this occasion, he had put on a striking, purple and golden daoist robe as opposed to his usual coarse linen robe, and it was very apparent that the robe was a powerful immortal treasure.

On the other side, seated next to Chen Ruyan, was a tall figure dressed in a long, black robe. The figure's entire body was covered from head to toe, leaving only a pair of purple eyes exposed, and there seemed to have been countless stars flashing within their pupils.

Their name was Yin Ming, and they were the most mysterious and enigmatic of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords.

Over the countless years that Chen Tuan had spent in seclusion, he had been gradually forgotten, but there were still legends of his feats being told. However, there weren't even any legends surrounding Dao Ancestor Yin Ming, and even the high-ranking cultivators of the Heavenly Court knew next to nothing about them.

At this point, Chen Tuan had already been assimilated by the Heavenly Dao to such a degree that he was almost no different from a mortal, while Xuanyuan Jie had been recently slain, so all that remained of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords were these five.

Gu Huojin would always make an appearance during the past editions of the Bodhi Banquet, but that was not the case for the other Seven Heavenly Dao Lords, particularly Yin Ming, so it was already quite a rare sight to see five of them at once.

All of the banquet attendees immediately rose to their feet to extend a welcome toward the five supreme lords, while Gu Huojin smiled as he said, "The Reincarnation Palace Master is a guest today, so please observe the proper etiquette, Fellow Daoist Cang Wu."

It sounded more like he was serving as a friendly mediator rather than issuing a warning, but True Lord Cang Wu knew better than to challenge Gu Huojin's authority, and he returned to his seat with a defeated and weary look on his face.

The Reincarnation Palace Master turned his gaze to the five supreme lords with a calm expression, while Daoist Master Qing Qiu heaved an internal sigh of relief before leading him to the front row of the venue, where all of the Dao Ancestors were seated.

"Please take a seat, Palace Master," Daoist Master Qing Qiu said.

The Reincarnation Palace Master took a glance at the seat that he had been led to, then stepped over the table to arrive before the tables designated for the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords.

He then made a beckoning motion to one of the seven tables, and the table was instantly drawn to him along with the cushion behind it.

"He's already dead, so what's the point in leaving a table out for him?" the Reincarnation Palace Master chuckled as he sat down onto the cushion, then poured himself a cup of wine from the flagon on the table.

The entire venue erupted into a frenzy upon seeing this, and Daoist Master Qing Qiu began sweating profusely once again.

At the same time, he couldn't help but feel a hint of admiration toward the Reincarnation Palace Master. He couldn't think of anyone else that would be able to put on such a bold display in a setting like this.

However, he still had a job to do, so he had no choice but to muster up his courage and approach the Reincarnation Palace Master as he said, "Please return to your assigned seat, Palace Master."

The Reincarnation Palace Master completely ignored him as he downed the wine in his cup in one go.

"It's fine, he can sit where he likes," Gu Huojin said with a smile.

Daoist Master Qing Qiu was very relieved to hear this, and he quickly bade farewell to the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords before setting off on a return journey to the Eastern Victory Continent.

As the head of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords, Gu Huojin was naturally seated in the center, and his table was slightly taller than the others.

There was one vacant table reserved for Chen Tuan, while the deceased Xuanyuan Jie's table had been claimed by the Reincarnation Palace Master.

With the Reincarnation Palace Master's new seating arrangement approved by Gu Huojin, the tense atmosphere gradually subsided, and the heavenly music played by the celestial maidens resumed.

Right at this moment, a figure enshrouded in a dense layer of cloud and mist appeared before everyone.

After the mist faded away, a tall figure dressed in an azure robe with clouds embroidered upon it was revealed, and it was another one of the Heavenly Court's Dao Ancestors, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun extended a salute toward Gu Huojin and the others, then turned to the other banquet attendees with a wide smile as he greeted, "Welcome one and all to the Bodhi Banquet!"

As soon as his voice trailed off, a blanket of rainbow clouds appeared above everyone, within which dozens of stunning celestial maidens broke into an elegant dance with flower petals raining down from their gorgeous dresses, presenting a marvelous spectacle to behold.

Everyone was finally able to relax a little upon seeing this, and they began sampling the wine and spirit fruits on their tables.

......

Deep within a boundless expanse of space was a gargantuan, silver mountain that was hovering in mid-air, with a summit so tall that it was completely out of sight.

The silver mountain was entirely crafted from a type of translucent, silver ore, and it was giving off formidable spatial law power fluctuations. This type of silver ore was a type of powerful spatial material known as Void Crystals, and the collective spatial law powers emanating from this vast mountain of Void Crystals was enough to cause the entire surrounding space to tremble incessantly.

As soon as the nearby bursts of chaotic spatial turbulence drew close to the silver mountain, they immediately turned submissive and docile before flowing past it.

Beneath the mountain was an unfathomably enormous black turtle that resembled a vast continent, carrying the silver mountain on its back as it slowly swam through the spatial turbulence.

The silver mountain was riddled with countless small holes that ran all the way from the foot of the mountain to the summit, giving it the appearance of a beehive.

Upon closer inspection, one would discover that these holes were all entrances to caves that formed a complex system of tunnels, and it seemed that the entire silver mountain had been hollowed out.

The tunnels were lined with stone chambers that were separated by rather short intervals, and each tunnel contained countless chambers, amounting to an astronomical number when the entire mountain was taken into consideration.

The stone chambers were connected by thick, silver lines, forming a dense and complex silver net that connected all of the stone chambers in the mountain together, and there were also many silver lines that vanished into the space, making it unclear where they ultimately extended to.

These silver lines were all flashing incessantly, as if they were transmitting something, and within each stone chamber were several arrays.

In contrast with normal teleportation arrays, these only facilitated the teleportation of objects, and occasionally, items of all descriptions would appear in the arrays.

There were Reincarnation Palace cultivators stationed beside each array, putting those items into other teleportation arrays or handing them off to the puppets off to the side.

After receiving said items, the puppets would immediately exit the chamber before delivering them to other parts of the silver mountain.

The interior of the silver mountain was like a gargantuan nation that was extremely busy, but also functioning in a very orderly manner.

On the summit of the silver mountain sat a palace with an internal space that was tens of thousands of feet in size.

The palace was completely empty with the exception of four massive tool refinement cauldrons situated at the very center.

These cauldrons were hundreds of feet tall, reaching almost all the way up to the ceiling of the palace, and they were identical in style, but were blue, azure, crimson, and black in color.

The undersides of the four cauldrons were enveloped by silver flames, and seated around them were dozens of cultivators, most of whom were wearing Reincarnation Palace mask, while the rest were dressed in the purple robes of the Devil Realm's Night Sun Empire.

All of these cultivators were making strings of hand seals, casting precious materials into the four cauldrons.

Bursts of dull, thunderous rumbling could be heard ringing out from within the cauldrons, and all of a sudden, the lid of the blue cauldron flew up on its own, following which a ball of blue light shot out from within.

A tall man from the Reincarnation Palace near the cauldron raised his hand, and the ball of blue light was drawn into his grasp, revealing a blue rabbit Reincarnation Palace mask.

The man examined the mask momentarily, then made his way into a side hall at the back of the palace.

There were three stone platforms in the side hall, with one cultivator seated atop each of them. The three of them were each holding a white jade slab, upon which lines of text were flashing incessantly.

The three of them were constantly keeping an eye on the text flashing over the jade slabs while making strings of hand seals, looking very busy.

The one on the left was a gray-robed, middle-aged man with a gaunt face and a pair of sunken eyes.

The one in the center was a purple-robed elderly man who seemed to have come from the Night Sun Empire. He was slightly hunch-backed, and his skin was heavily wrinkled, but his eyes were very bright and energetic.

To his right was a white-robed woman with fair and delicate skin, but her beautiful features were marred by her cold expression.

All three of them were at the Great Encompassment Stage, with the purple-robed elderly man possessing the loftiest cultivation base of the three, having already reached the pinnacle of the mid-Great Encompassment Stage.

Chapter 1360: Infinite Generosity

The man from the Reincarnation Palace set the blue mask down before the three cultivators on the stone platforms with a respectful bow, and the three of them immediately turned their attention to the mask before each casting an incantation seal onto it in unison.

Three beams of light, one gray, one silver, and one white, shot out of their fingertips before surging into the blue mask.

There were countless silver runes dancing within the beam of silver light, warping the space around them.

The beam of gray light wasn't giving off any aura fluctuations, and it was as if it were nothing more than an illusion.

As for the beam of white light, it was rippling incessantly as it took on all types of peculiar shapes and forms, presenting an intriguing sight to behold.

All the while, the man from the Reincarnation Palace had his head lowered as a gesture of respect, not daring to look at the three Great Encompassment cultivators at work.

These three cultivators were very important figures in the Reincarnation Palace. All of the Reincarnation Palace masks were refined by them, and it was thanks to them that the masks possessed their item teleportation, concealment, and shapeshifting abilities.

The blue mask rose up into the air, and silver, gray, and white spirit patterns began to slowly spread over their surface.

Within mere moments, the spirit patterns had spread over the entire mask, following which it sprang up into the air and began racing through the hall like a joyous blue bird.

The man from the Reincarnation Palace swept a sleeve through the air to release a streak of white light, which caught the mask before drawing it into his grasp.

The spirit patterns on the blue mask quickly faded away, but it continued to radiate layers of vibrant light.

"Thank you, seniors!" the man from the Reincarnation Palace said as he extended a respectful salute, then departed with the mask, while the three Great Encompassment cultivators immediately turned their attention back to their jade slabs.

Shortly thereafter, another cultivator of the Reincarnation Palace entered the side hall, this time with an azure mask, and the three Great Encompassment cultivators sprang into action again.

It took a little longer to engrave the spirit patterns onto the azure mask than it had for the blue one, and not long after that, a crimson mask was brought to them.

The masks were brought in one after another almost without pause, and only after working on over a hundred masks in succession were they afforded a short break.

There were no more lines of text appearing on the jade slab, and at this point, both the gray-robed man and the white-robed woman were looking a little weary, while the purple-robed elderly man wasn't showing any signs of strain.

"Your powers are growing by leaps and bounds, Fellow Daoist Shi. It looks like it won't be long before you reach the late-Great Encompassment Stage," the gray-robed man said as he turned to the purple-robed elderly man.

"Your concealment law powers are also becoming more and more profound, Fellow Daoist Lu. The concealment abilities of the recent batches of masks have become more and more potent. As for reaching the late-Great Encompassment Stage, that's not something that I dare to hope for," the purple-robed elderly man replied with a faint smile.

"My concealment law powers cannot even begin to compare with your spatial law powers, Fellow Daoist Shi. In fact, I'd say they're even inferior to Fellow Daoist Bai's shapeshifting law powers," the gray-robed man said with a modest shake of his head.

"Right now, the palace master is facing very powerful foes in the Heavenly Court, yet here you two are, chatting about irrelevant nonsense! If you truly wish to do your part and help the palace master, then focus your attention on the task at hand!" the white-robed woman interjected in a scathing manner.

The gray-robed man gave an awkward smile in response, while the purple-robed elderly man's brows furrowed slightly in displeasure.

Right at this moment, an azure-robed figure emerged from deep within the side hall and reprimanded, "Don't be so rude, Bai Yu. Fellow Daoist Shi is currently serving our Reincarnation Palace, but he's a member of our own force, so we must treat him with respect."

"Palace Master Huangfu!" the gray-robed man exclaimed as he hurriedly rose to his feet before extending a respectful bow toward the azure-robed young man.

"My apologies, Palace Master Huangfu," the white-robed woman said as she also hurriedly rose to her feet.

She then turned to the purple-robed elderly man as she apologized once more, "Please forgive me for my rude outburst just now, Fellow Daoist Shi."

The purple-robed elderly man had also stood up from his stone platform, and he waved a hand in the white-robed woman's direction before turning to the azure-robed young man to extend a slight bow.

The azure-robed young man was none other than Dao Ancestor Huangfu Yu of the Reincarnation Palace, who had previously made an appearance in the Gray Realm.

"No need for formalities. Thank you for your hard work over the years," Huangfu Yu said with a pleasant smile.

"There's no need to thank us, we've only been performing the duties that are expected of us. How are things going in the Heavenly Court?" the gray-robed man asked.

"The situation is still rather unclear at the moment, but as long as our hearts are one and we have the palace master to lead us, defeating the Heavenly Court is very much possible," Huangfu Yu replied, and the three Great Encompassment cultivators gave a collective, affirmative response.

Huangfu Yu turned his gaze to the purple-robed elderly man, then said, "Fellow Daoist Shi, I'll have to trouble you to oversee the deal between our Reincarnation Palace and the Vast Origin House. As for the costs incurred, you'll be compensated once this battle is over."

"I'll be sure to keep a close eye on things," the purple-robed elderly man replied with a nod.

"I knew I could count on you, Fellow Daoist Shi," Huangfu Yu said with a pleased nod, and after issuing a few more instructions, he departed from the side hall.

Shortly thereafter, he appeared on the summit of the giant mountain, then cast his gaze toward a certain direction in an absentminded manner.

......

At the Bodhi Banquet.

Following the conclusion of the customary song and dance performance, everyone was beginning to grow rather excited as their main objective for this trip was about to be fulfilled.

"I'm sure everyone is already tired of waiting. As usual, all banquet attendees will receive Bodhi Dao Fruits, but this time, things will be a little different..."

Everyone was immediately feeling a little apprehensive in the wake of this announcement from Dao Ancestor Bai Yun. Could it be that something had to be done in exchange for the Bodhi Dao Fruits for this edition of the Bodhi Banquet?

With that in mind, the entire venue erupted into concerned chatter.

"Rest assured, everyone, this will only come as good news for all of you. Out of the infinite kindness of our supreme lord, he has decided to distribute Bodhi Dao Fruits to all banquet attendees, regardless of whether they're invited guests or merely part of the entourages!" Dao Ancestor Bai Yun declared.

Everyone was quite relieved to hear this, following which they chanted in unison, "Thank you, Supreme Lord!"

Gu Huojin gave a slight nod at everyone's gratitude, while the Reincarnation Palace Master looked on in a calm and composed silence.

Moments later, eight giant immortal birds appeared in the sky, with each fo them holding an ornate crate in their beaks. The eight birds set off in different directions like speeding arrows, and the crates contained the Bodhi Dao Fruits designated for the other sub-venues.

Following their departure, groups of celestial maidens began to file into the main venue, carrying Bodhi Dao Fruits atop jade platters, and sure enough, each of the banquet attendees received a dao fruit, including even the Reincarnation Palace Master.

He picked up the Bodhi Dao Fruit that had been placed before him to discover that it was a bright red fruit that resembled a plum in shape, and it was far from what he had expected.

Furthermore, the fruit seemed to have been glowing from the inside, giving it the appearance fo a miniature, red lantern, and it was also giving off an alluring aroma.

The Reincarnation Palace Master took a glance at the Bodhi Dao Fruits in front of Gu Huojin and the others to discover that they were identical to his own, so these were most likely all Bodhi Dao Fruits of the highest caliber.

All of the Dao Ancestors and Great Encompassment cultivators present were able to maintain their composure, while the members of their entourages were unable to suppress their excitement at this unexpected blessing.

All of them were holding onto their dao fruits as if they were the most precious treasures under the heavens, and they were virtually salivating in excitement, but no one dared to consume their dao fruit without permission from Gu Huojin.

"There's no need to restrain yourselves, everyone. The Bodhi Dao Fruits have already been distributed, so they are free to be devoured as you please," Gu Huojin declared with a warm smile, then took a bite out of his own dao fruit, and only then did everyone else dare to take their first bites.

In the blink of an eye, the entire venue was filled with radiant light and an intoxicating aroma.

In the first row, Meng Po brought her Bodhi Dao Fruit to her lips, and the same light that emanated from everyone else's dao fruits began radiating from her own, but as opposed to actually consuming the dao fruit, she secretly tucked it away.

Yu Menghan did the exact same thing, stowing her own dao fruit away as well.

At the same time, she was thinking to herself that if they could meet again someday, then she would give him this Bodhi Dao Fruit as a reunion gift.

The Reincarnation Palace Master examined his Bodhi Dao Fruit for a moment longer, then casually crushed it in his grasp, and it disintegrated into streaks of light that escaped in all directions.

Gu Huojin raised an eyebrow ever so slightly upon seeing this, but he didn't express any displeasure.

Once everyone had consumed their Bodhi Dao Fruits, the sound of a gong strike rang out across the entire venue, accompanied by delightful music.

The surface of Pure Clear Lake began to ripple, while the giant locust tree behind it gently swayed from side to side. A flurry of locust leaves came drifting down onto the venue, gradually taking on a translucent appearance as they descended.

In that instant, many of the cultivators in the venue instinctively closed their eyes and began to meditate.

Chapter 1361: Grievances

Before the light from the Bodhi Dao Fruits had completely faded away, layers of spiritual light appeared over the bodies of many of the cultivators present, and a strange atmosphere descended upon the entire venue.

Oh? There really are people making breakthroughs here...

The Reincarnation Palace Master cast his gaze toward a table in the distance to discover that a young man who had accompanied a senior of his clan to the banquet had just broken through a bottleneck to reach the late-Golden Immortal Stage.

Immediately thereafter, seven or eight more cultivators made breakthroughs in rapid succession.

The Reincarnation Palace Master noticed that almost all of them were below the High Zenith Stage, which made sense, considering the loftier one's cultivation base, the more difficult it was for one to make breakthroughs.

However, judging from the excited looks on the faces of the High Zenith cultivators present, it was clear that they had also benefited immensely from this experience.

Even though the Great Encompassment cultivators present had predominantly received dao fruits of a higher caliber, their cultivation bases were already too lofty for the consumption of their dao fruits to make an immediate difference.

However, that was certainly not to say that they weren't also benefiting from their dao fruits.

Only after a long while did all of the banquet attendees awaken from their meditative state, and Gu Huojin swept his gaze over the entire venue with a wide smile as he said, "I'm glad to see all of you taking full advantage of this opportunity."

A white-robed young man who had just made a breakthrough rose to his feet in excitement, then knelt down and kowtowed to Gu Huojin as he said, "It's all thanks to your infinite generosity, Supreme Lord. We are forever grateful to you!"

Many of the other banquet attendees also followed suit, expressing their gratitude to Gu Huojin and the Heavenly Court.

A faint smile appeared on the Reincarnation Palace Master's face upon seeing this, and he mused, "As expected of the Heavenly Court to be able to win over so many hearts with just these Bodhi Dao Fruits..."

He wasn't speaking particularly loudly, nor had he done anything to amplify his own voice, but given the cultivation bases of everyone present, his words were still loud enough to attract everyone's attention, and most of the banquet attendees were not very pleased to hear this flippant remark.

An elderly man sprang to his feet as he yelled, "The Reincarnation Palace has always been going against the Heavenly Court and the natural order, wreaking havoc throughout the entire True Immortal Region. In his infinite generosity, the supreme lord has allowed you a seat at this Bodhi Banquet, the least you can do in return is keep your mouth shut!"

That seemed to have opened the floodgates, and a flurry of complaints and accusations were levied against the Reincarnation Palace Master.

Gu Huojin continued to maintain an amicable, smiling facade as he made a quieting gesture, and the commotion quickly died down.

"Do not be so hostile, everyone. Our Heavenly Court and the Reincarnation Palace have been at odds with each other for countless years, and it's already impossible to recall what initially sparked the conflict and which side is in the wrong. I have invited the Reincarnation Palace Master to the Bodhi Banquet to propose a peaceful resolution, not for a public lynching," Gu Huojin said.

Everyone nodded in praise of Gu Huojin's foresight and eye for the bigger picture upon hearing this.

"As expected of the ruler of the Heavenly Court! I don't think there's anyone else under the heavens that can tell such atrocious lies with the same degree of composure as you!" the Reincarnation Palace Master chuckled.

"Are you doubting my sincerity? Is it not already enough of a show of sincerity that you were able to arrive here safely, while the armies that you've assembled outside my heavenly gates have not been forcibly quashed? If you're willing to set aside our past differences and strive for peace, then I would be eager to do the same," Gu Huojin said.

Many of the banquet attendees were clearly not very happy to hear this.

"You're going to become allies with a scoundrel like him? You're going to simply let bygones be bygones? Then what about my personal differences with the Heavenly Court? What about the lives of all of the loyal subordinates of the Heavenly Court that were taken by the Reincarnation Palace?" True Lord Cang Wu yelled.

"We can't just hold onto past grudges forever, Fellow Daoist Cang Wu. While it's true that many Heavenly Court cultivators have perished at the hands of the Reincarnation Palace over the years, the reverse is also true. If we do not move on, then there will only be more bloodshed, and when will the cycle ever end?" Gu Huojin said in a sincere and heartfelt manner.

"You make it sound so easy! If the Heavenly Court isn't going to stand against the Reincarnation Palace, then I'll do so on my own!" True Lord Cang Wu declared in a defiant manner.

"Looks like the Heavenly Court isn't filled entirely with spineless yes men after all," the Reincarnation Palace Master remarked with a hint of praise in his voice.

"I've shown you my sincerity, Palace Master. Are you really not willing to accept a peaceful resolution?" Gu Huojin asked.

"A peaceful resolution? Why don't you take a look at my face first before you decide whether your offer still stands," the Reincarnation Palace Master harrumphed coldly as he finally removed the veiled hat that was perpetually on his head.

A hint of incredulity flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes upon seeing the Reincarnation Palace Master's true appearance, and the other Dao Ancestors beside him were also displaying similar emotions of astonishment, particularly Li Yuanjiu.

"Han Li?!" Li Yuanjiu involuntarily exclaimed.

This was a name that most of the banquet attendees were familiar with.

Initially, it was a name that was only occasionally brought up in passing, but as his powers and feats continued to grow, his name was heard more and more frequently, with his most recent and most astonishing confirmed feat being his defeat of Dao Ancestor Feng Qingshui.

After that, it was rumored that he had brought about Xuanyuan Jie's demise, but there was no substantial evidence to back up these claims, so barely anyone had taken the rumors seriously.

Regardless of how powerful the three paramount laws were, surely it was too far-fetched for a Great Encompassment cultivator to have slain one of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords.

"The Reincarnation Palace Master is Han Li?"

"But that doesn't make sense on the timeline..." a Great Encompassment cultivator that had been battling against the Reincarnation Palace for many years murmured to himself.

"Isn't Han Li a cultivator of the laws of time? What's going on here?"

"Could it be that Supreme Lord Xuanyuan Jie really has fallen, and his demise was brought about by the Reincarnation Palace?"

......

The entire venue had erupted into a frenzy, and there were all types of wild theories and conjecture being thrown around with regard to Han Li and the Reincarnation Palace Master.

Yu Menghan was also astonished beyond belief, and she was almost unable to suppress the urge to rise to her feet upon catching a clear glimpse of the Reincarnation Palace Master, but thankfully, Meng Po was able to react in time and hold her down by the shoulder.

"Don't be reckless!" she scolded through voice transmission.

She didn't know why Yu Menghan had suddenly lost her composure, but she had a feeling that it had something to do with that Five Lightning True Mantra.

However, Yu Menghan calmed down on her own, and she carefully examined the Reincarnation Palace Master for a moment before murmuring to herself, "It's not him..."

"No wonder Chen Tuan's past divinations yielded such confounding and ambiguous outcomes, it's because the cycle of karma has already been thrown into disarray," Gu Huojin murmured to himself with an enlightened expression, as if a question that had been weighing on him for many years had finally been answered.

"It sounds like you've figured it out already, Fellow Daoist Gu," the Reincarnation Palace Master remarked.

"I feel like I have a good grasp on what's happened. You are Han Li, and Han Li is also you, is that correct?" Gu Huojin asked, and his question only served to further confuse everyone.

"All those years ago, you hunted me down and killed my dao partner just because you couldn't tolerate someone else standing at the pinnacle of the laws of time with you. In what I had thought were going to be my final moments, I was able to go back in time, and I reinvented myself into the Reincarnation Palace Master. Do you still think our past differences can simply be set aside now?" the Reincarnation Palace Master asked.

Everyone was becoming more and more perplexed by the second, while Li Yuanjiu raised an eyebrow, seemingly having just pieced together part of the puzzle.

He was naturally aware that it was impossible for one person to simultaneously cultivate two of the three paramount laws at once. The Reincarnation Palace Master and Han Li were the same person, but also not the same person.

In that case, which one of them was the one that had bestowed those cultivation arts upon him in the past?

Chapter 1362: Dramatic Turn

"Ultimately, it still comes down to a battle of Great Daos. I suppose it can also be regarded as a conflict from a previous lifetime. Now that you've mastered the laws of reincarnation, I'm sure you understand that such conflicts are unavoidable. Right now, there is no longer any direct conflict of interest between us, so why not let bygones be bygones?

“You can replace Xuanyuan Jie as one of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords, and I can help you reach the pinnacle of the laws of reincarnation. What do you say?" Gu Huojin proposed.

"To you, these are nothing more than trivial matters of the distant past, but to me, these are excruciating experiences that are ingrained into the very fibers of my being. Besides, the conflict between the Heavenly Court and the Reincarnation Palace no longer concerns only the two of us. Countless more people have been swept up in this conflict, so no peaceful resolution is possible," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied with a shake of his head.

Gu Huojin didn't appear surprised by this response, and he asked, "In that case, what do you plan to do, Palace Master?"

"This conflict will only truly subside once one of us ceases to exist," the Reincarnation Palace Master declared.

"Despite our past differences, I had always thought of you as someone who would be able to understand me and see things from the same vantage point as I do, but it seems that I was wrong. You are still too short of sight and too narrow of mind," Gu Huojin remarked in a disappointed manner.

The Reincarnation Palace Master remained silent, seemingly waiting for Gu Huojin to continue.

"The death of your dao partner, the battle of the Great Dao between you and me, and even the deaths of the countless cultivators of the Reincarnation Palace and the Heavenly Court mean nothing in the grand scheme of things. Have you not thought about what lies above and beyond the Heavenly Dao?" Gu Huojin asked, and his amicable facade faded to reveal the ambition and ruthlessness underneath.

"You want to rise beyond the Heavenly Dao? You are already the Time Dao Ancestor and stand at the pinnacle of all cultivators, are you still not satisfied?" the Reincarnation Palace Master asked.

"I suppose it's no surprise that you don't understand me. After all, you're not a true Dao Ancestor, so you don't know how suffocating it feels to constantly have the Heavenly Dao hanging over your head. It's... an indescribable feeling that makes me want to punch a hole through the heavens!" Gu Huojin said as he clenched his fists tightly.

Everyone was rather taken aback to see this. They had never seen Gu Huojin speak like this, and they felt like this Gu Huojin was very different from his usual self.

"Are you finally displaying your ambition? It's a pity that your grand plan won't come into fruition," the Reincarnation Palace Master chuckled, and as soon as his voice trailed off, the space on either side of the Jade Pond Paradise suddenly began to tremble violently as countless chaotic silver ripples appeared without any warning.

The entire Jade Pond Paradise was enshrouded within powerful restrictions set up by the Heavenly Court's Dao Ancestors, and they were immediately activated on their own to clash against the silver ripples.

Bursts of tremendous power were sent sweeping through the banquet venue, sending some of the guests at the edge of the venue flying through the air, and some of the cultivators with the lowliest cultivation bases present sustained severe injuries as the entire situation descended into complete pandemonium.

Right at this moment, a vast blanket of white clouds appeared on either side of the Jade Pond Paradise to oppose the silver ripples, and their power was instantly nullified.

At the same time, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun rose up into the sky above the Jade Pond Paradise, while the cultivators that had been severely wounded were frantically flying toward the center of the venue.

Beside Pure Clear Lake, Li Yuanjiu and the other Dao Ancestors all turned to Gu Huojin and the Reincarnation Palace Master with uncertain expressions, but Gu Huojin wasn't displaying even the slightest bit of emotion, seemingly completely disinterested in what was taking place before him, and the Reincarnation Palace Master was reacting in much the same way.

Contemplative looks appeared on the faces of Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong upon seeing this, while a faint smile had appeared on Chen Ruyan's face.

As for Yin Ming, he had closed his eyes like an old monk going into a stint of meditation.

The other Dao Ancestors were all quite puzzled to see this, and they were at a loss for what to do.

Meanwhile, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun continued to conjure up more clouds to oppose the silver ripples that were sweeping through the surrounding space, aided by all of the restrictions around the Jade Pond Paradise.

However, right at this moment, the silver ripples suddenly began to glow radiantly as two bursts of tremendous and peerlessly sharp power erupted out of them.

A loud tearing sound rang out as the white clouds on either side of the Jade Pond Paradise were torn apart, and the restrictions around the venue weren't able to fare much better.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun shuddered violently, and only after stumbling back close to twenty steps was he able to steady himself.

Clearly chagrined at being embarrassed in front of all of these banquet attendees, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun immediately prepared to spring into action again, but right at this moment, the space on either side of the Jade Pond Paradise was torn apart by the silver ripples to create a pair of bottomless spatial passageways.

Countless figures came flying in through the spatial passageways, and those arriving from the left were all purple-robed cultivators of the Devil Realm, led by none other than the Devilish Monarch, Shi Kongyu.

At the moment, Shi Kongyu was clad in a suit of purple armor that was riddled with black patterns, and a crimson cape was flapping audibly behind him.

There were four figures standing on either side of him.

To his left were a man and a woman, the former of which had a head of limp, straw-like long hair and an alarmingly emaciated body, while the latter was stunningly voluptuous and beautiful, like an evil flower that inspired both fear and entrancement.

Of the two people standing on Shi Kongyu's right, one of them was a woman in a white dress who was remarkably tall, towering over even the Devilish Monarch. She was also extremely rotund, resembling a mountain of meat that was not dissimilar in build to Patriarch Miro.

Standing beside her was a yellow-robed man who appeared to have only been in his twenties. There was an ordinary-looking black longsword strapped to his waist, and his appearance was also quite unremarkable, but his eyes were extremely hollow and lifeless, looking as if they belonged to a dead man.

Their auras indicated that all of them were Dao Ancestors, and there was a collection of around forty to fifty Great Encompassment cultivators gathered behind them.

Among them were Shi Pokong and Shi Jingyan, both of whom had reached the early-Great Encompassment Stage.

Standing beside the two of them was a handsome young man dressed in imperial attire, and the auras of Shi Pokong and Shi Jingyan were completely dwarfed by his late-Great Encompassment Stage aura.

Assembled behind them was a mighty devilish army, all of whom were at or above the Golden Immortal Stage, and it was clear that all of the elite forces of the entire Devil Realm were out in full force.

Meanwhile, true spirit beings of the primordial land were pouring out of the other spatial passageway, and they were led by none other than Bai Zi, Yue Mian, and a bald, middle-aged man with a nonchalant smile on his face.

The bald man was clad in a suit of ancient copper armor that was devoid of all patterns, making it appear no different from a suit of armor one would find in the mortal world, but it was made to appear extraordinary by its wearer.

Standing behind the trio were around thirty to forty Great Encompassment Stage beings, including some tribal chiefs, as well as Lekima, Xiaobai, Liu Le'er, and Fox 3.

They were also joined by an army of the primordial land's most elite forces, and the two mighty armies had the entire Jade Pond Paradise surrounded in an instant.

......

Meanwhile, in the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array.

With a sweep of his sleeve, Han Li released his seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, all of which were sent hurtling directly toward the four Dao Ancestors that had just stepped into the array.

Dong Lihu sprang forward to position himself at the forefront of the group, shielding his three companions behind him as he joined his palms before thrusting his hands forward.

His hands resembled a pair of sharp swords that parted the space up ahead, and bursts of golden light surged out from within to form a huge mountain. Even though the mountain had no substantial form, it was just as mighty as any mountain.

The flurry of Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords crashed into the mountain, but were unable to penetrate through it. Instead, they blasted a series of holes into the mountain before sliding away to the side, diverted off their original paths.

The seventy-two flying swords flew away into the distance before dispersing and transforming into seventy-two sword spirit children, all of which crossed their arms as they observed the four Dao Ancestors with furrowed brows, seemingly in no hurry to attack or arrange themselves into any arrays.

"What an honor it is to be visited by four Dao Ancestors at once," Han Li said as he approached the four Dao Ancestors with his hands clasped behind his back.

Chapter 1363: Mounting Tension

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun's complexion instantly paled at the sight of the two almighty armies, and he hurriedly stopped cold in his tracks.

Right at this moment, two figures suddenly appeared by his side, one of whom was a white-robed, middle-aged man who appeared to have been around forty years of age.

His hair and short beard were all white, and his entire body was giving off a frosty aura.

The other new arrival was an elderly man who was less than five feet tall. He had a bright, red complexion and a fiery, red nose, which gave him a very warm and approachable appearance when coupled with his benevolent smile.

Both of them were also Dao Ancestors, and they positioned themselves in front of Gu Huojin and the others along with Dao Ancestor Bai Yun.

"What are these devilish cultivators and primordial true spirits doing here?!"

All of the banquet attendees had risen to their feet in an alarmed panic to gather around Gu Huojin and the others.

True Lord Cang Wu swept a sleeve through the air to release a burst of crimson light that enveloped Meng Po and Yu Menghan, following which he also flew over to all of the Heavenly Court's Dao Ancestors.

All of a sudden, another group of people appeared beside True Lord Cang Wu's group, and they were led by a physically imposing man with a head of azure hair and the aura of a Dao Ancestor.

"Fellow Daoist Feng," True Lord Cang Wu greeted as he cupped his fist in a salute toward the man, who returned the salute with a smile.

Even though the two of them weren't particularly close, they had reflexively banded together in the wake of this sudden turn of events.

Right at this moment, a red-robed elderly man flew onto the scene, then descended beside True Lord Cang Wu and the azure-haired man.

The elderly man was completely bald, and his face was thin and withered, but his eyes were exceptionally sharp and bright, and he was also a Dao Ancestor.

"Greetings, Fellow Daoist Feng, Fellow Daoist Cang Wu. You wouldn't mind if I joined you for a bit, would you?" the red-robed elderly man asked with a smile.

True Lord Cang Wu and the azure-haired man exchanged a glance with one another, then welcomed, "Of course, Fellow Daoist Zhen. We are more than happy to have you join us."

The red-robed elderly man's name was Zhen Shiyin, and he was a vagrant Dao Ancestor who resided in a small immortal region. He had a rather enigmatic personality, and he hadn't founded any sects, nor taken any disciples, but his power was not to be understated, and he had left behind many legendary tales in quite a few immortal regions.

With the three of them joining forces, their chances of safely weathering the storm would be significantly increased.

As was usually the case, most of the Dao Ancestors across the True Immortal Realm actually hadn't come to personally attend the Bodhi Banquet, instead choosing to send their juniors to attend on their behalf, so True Lord Cang Wu's trio were the only true Dao Ancestors present.

Hence, with the three of them forging an alliance, many of the other banquet attendees hurriedly gathered around them for protection.

......

Inside the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array, Han Li was looking as calm and composed as ever, and a sense of apprehension welled up in the hearts of Zi Shan and the others upon seeing this.

They were an almighty collection of four Dao Ancestors, yet for some reason, they were feeling fear in the presence of a single man who wasn't even a Dao Ancestor.

Regardless of whether they normally got along, now that they had entered the array, they had to set aside all of their differences and focus on eradicating this common enemy.

Zi Shan took a glance at Dong Lihu and Zhu Yan, both of whom nodded in response before positioning themselves to the right and the left of Han Li, forming a triangular encirclement with Zi Shan, while Meng Yuan remained standing behind her.

In light of this, Han Li began to assess the situation.

Judging from how Dong Lihu had just warded off his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, it appeared that he was a cultivator of mountain law powers, a subsidiary of the laws of earth, so his fortes were most likely going to be his strength and his defenses, making it difficult to strike him down in a short time.

As for Zi Shan and Zhu Yan, the fact that they were directly confronting him indicated that they had to have been cultivators of certain offensive law powers. That left Meng Yuan, who was clearly not adept in direct combat, which meant that he had to have had some other tricks up his sleeve.

With that in mind, it was clear that Meng Yuan was the one that he had to kill first.

Right as Han Li made up his mind, the space up ahead rippled violently, and a sea of scorching, purple flames erupted toward him without any warning.

Purple flames... She's a cultivator of fire law powers!

Han Li sprang back in retreat as his Mantra Treasured Axis appeared behind him, and it began revolving rapidly while giving off countless rays of golden light that enshrouded the entire surrounding space.

As soon as the purple fire came into contact with the rays of golden light, it was instantly slowed down significantly, allowing Han Li to get away.

However, at the point where the flames met the rays of golden light, bursts of loud crackling began ringing out incessantly as the rays of golden light were rapidly burned away.

Right at this moment, a figure that was entirely enshrouded in flames emerged from the purple fire, wielding a fiery, purple longsword that they thrust directly toward Han Li's heart.

Han Li was already prepared for this, and he threw a punch at the tip of the sword in retaliation.

A burst of explosive power swept through the air in all directions as countless balls of purple flames erupted everywhere, and before Han Li had a chance to withdraw his fist, a gargantuan, golden mountain suddenly came crashing down upon him from above.

Swirling around the golden mountain was a layer of dense, yellow clouds that was giving off incredibly formidable earth law power fluctuations, and the entire space beneath the mountain was forced downward by its tremendous weight.

Han Li looked up at the underside of the mountain, then thrust the palm of his other hand toward it, releasing a giant palm projection to strike the mountain from below, bringing it to a juddering halt.

However, the mountain was only stopped for a split second in its descent before continuing to crash down from above.

Han Li's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this, and he kept his palm raised to the heavens, catching the mountain from below.

He shuddered slightly under its immense weight, but was quickly able to steady himself.

Right at this moment, a thunderous roar rang out from above, and a streak of golden light descended outside the golden mountain.

Within the golden light was Dong Lihu, and there was a layer of blinding, golden radiance around his entire body, giving him the appearance of an almighty deity clad in a suit of golden armor.

He laid one hand out before him, then joined the middle and index fingers of his other hand, using them as a brush to inscribe something onto the palm of his spread hand.

Before long, the words "Capital Sun Mountain" had taken shape on the palm of his hand in large, flowing characters.

The style with which these characters had been inscribed onto his hand was very similar to that of the inscription of runes in that all of the strokes were connected to one another in an unbroken sequence, giving the characters the appearance of an undulating mountain range.

A miniature mountain appeared over the palm of his hand, joining another even smaller mountain that was already hovering above his hand, a golden mountain that was twice the size of the one that Han Li was supporting appeared in the heavens before crashing down onto the original mountain.

Waves of golden ripples spread through the air in all directions, and Han Li shuddered beneath the combined weight of the two mountains as his arm was forcibly bent at the elbow, to the extent that the back of his hand had almost come into contact with the top of his head.

He wanted to retract his other arm, only for the fiery, purple longsword to hurtle toward him once again, forcing him to extend his fist in retaliation.

At the same time, an earthquake of unprecedented magnitude took place on the tallest Five Mountain Peak on the Yellow Mountain Continent in the Mountain Moving Immortal Region, causing the entire summit to crumble.

As the Mountain Dao Ancestor, Dong Lihu was capable of moving any mountain from any of the immortal regions.

However, his powers were also hampered by the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array, albeit to a lesser extent than Han Li. As a result, he was unable to directly draw upon the true form of the mountains, but he was still able to draw upon their aura to unleash tremendous power.

Seeing as Han Li was still able to support the two mountains with one arm, Dong Lihu drew upon his law powers once again and inscribed the words "Divine Origin Peak" onto the palm of his hand, which manifested a third miniature mountain.

Immediately thereafter, yet another enormous mountain came crashing down from the heavens to land atop Capital Sun Mountain, and this time, Han Li's arm completely folded, forcing him to carry the three mountains on his shoulder.

Beneath the three mountains, Han Li was made to appear as tiny as a speck of dust, but the smile on his face had never faded.

His head was slightly cocked to the side as he cast his gaze toward Zhu Yan, who was hovering in mid-air with her hands clasped together in a strange seal, while the light emanating from her body was constantly fluctuating in brightness.

For some reason, Han Li's intuition was telling him that outside of Meng Yuan, she was the one that he had to be most wary of.

Chapter 1364: On the Cusp of Battle

All of a sudden, Zhu Yan vanished from the spot as a streak of light, hurtling directly toward Jin Tong.

It seemed that their objective from the very beginning had always been to stop Jin Tong from devouring this space.

She abruptly appeared behind Jin Tong in a wraith-like manner, yet before she had a chance to do anything, a cold look suddenly appeared on Han Li's face as a golden mountain range abruptly tok shape up above before crashing down from the heavens.

It descended with such incredible speed that Zhu Yan had no time to take evasive measures before she was crushed under it.

As soon as she was crushed under the mountain range, particles of sand that were imbued with tremendous time law powers converged toward her from all directions to envelop her entire body.

The layer of light emanating from her body was flashing urgently as she attempted to struggle free from the constraints of Han Li's Illusory Dawn Sand, but to no avail, and she was quickly inundated as if she had fallen into a sea of quicksand.

Furthermore, there were also thin roots extending toward her from all directions before wrapping themselves around her body in layers.

A sense of foreboding welled up in Zi Shan's heart upon seeing this, and she immediately sprang back in retreat, right as a fiery storm of shooting stars came raining down from the heavens.

At the same time, an animalistic roar rang out as Han Li abruptly swelled to over a hundred times his original size, transforming into a devilish deity with three heads and six arms that easily shrugged off the three mountains weighing down upon him.

An indescribably fearsome aura erupted out of his body, forcing Dong Lihu into retreat.

Freed from the burden of the three mountains, Han Li was finally able to direct his gaze toward Meng Yuan, who was currently seated in mid-air with a ring of white light beneath him.

The ring of white light was riddled with all types of runes and countless star patterns, and it was giving off an extremely peculiar law aura that Han Li had never felt before, one that didn't seem to belong to any of the five elements, nor was it related to souls.

"I thought facing four Dao Ancestors at once would be quite a challenge, but it seems like I was wrong," Han Li remarked as he looked down upon the trio.

Zi Shan's expression remained unchanged as she turned to Meng Yuan and asked, "Are you still not ready?"

Meng Yuan slowly opened his eyes, and his pupils were glowing with the radiance of countless stars as he smiled and said, "I'm ready..."

......

Li Yuanjiu and the other members of the Seven Heavenly Dao Ancestors were finally beginning to display some concern at the scene that was unfolding before them, but Gu Huojin remained as relaxed and composed as ever.

"Shi Kongyu, our Heavenly Court and your Devil Realm have already signed a peace treaty! Are you trying to instigate a new war?" Dao Ancestor Bai Yun accused.

"Your Heavenly Court sent your forces into our Devil Realm and plundered countless resources while slaughtering our brethren in droves! This is the day that we exact our revenge!" the Devilish Monarch declared, and the devilish army behind him let loose a collective roar of fury.

As for the bad blood between the primordial land and the Heavenly Court, that required no further elaboration, and all of the primordial tribes were glowering at the cultivators in the Jade Lake Paradise with intense hatred in their eyes. If it weren't for the fact that Bai Ze and the others had instructed them to stay put, they would've already pounced on these detestable human cultivators.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun surveyed the surrounding hostile forces with a hint of alarm in his eyes.

At the moment, he was the one running the Heavenly Court, and he had arranged everything related to this Bodhi Banquet.

The Jade Pond Paradise was situated deep within the Heavenly Court with countless layers of restrictions around it, transforming it into an impregnable fortress. On top of that, there were also many Dao Ancestors and Great Encompassment cultivators stationed here, so he had thought it to be an absolute safe haven.

It was for this reason that he had sent out the majority of the Heavenly Court's forces to deal with all of the attacks that the Reincarnation Palace was staging on the Middle Earth Immortal Region.

At the moment, there were many guards in the Heavenly Court, making it just about the worst possible time for a devilish and primordial infiltration.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun swept his gaze over the banquet attendees as a contemplative look flashed through his eyes.

Even though the banquet attendees were far outnumbered by the forces of the Devil Realm and the primordial land, all of them were top-tier cultivators who stood at the pinnacle of their respective immortal regions.

Among them were over a hundred Great Encompassment cultivators, as well as the three Dao Ancestors in the form of True Lord Cang Wu's trio, so when it came to top-end power, the Heavenly Court still held the advantage.

With that in mind, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun was put slightly at ease as he turned to Gu Huojin to await further instructions.

Gu Huojin paid no heed to the Devilish Monarch or the primordial Dao Ancestors. Instead, he turned his gaze to the Reincarnation Palace Master, but right as he was about to say something, he suddenly reached out to make a grabbing motion with his right hand.

A giant, golden palm projection appeared several thousand feet to his right, then swooped down from above.

The space before it was instantly torn apart, and the Reincarnation Palace Master stumbled out from within, while the Reincarnation Palace Master that was still seated at his table slowly dissipated into nothingness.

The golden palm projection continued to swoop down upon the Reincarnation Palace Master, who threw a punch in retaliation after steadying himself.

A dark red, hexagonal plate appeared above his head, revolving rapidly while releasing a burst of tremendous suction force, and everyone in the Jade Pond Paradise felt as if their souls were about to be sucked out of their bodies.

The hexagonal plate appeared just in the nick of time to oppose the golden palm projection, and the two clashed with an earth-shattering boom, while dazzling golden and red light swept through the air in all directions.

Right at this moment, four figures appeared around the Reincarnation Palace Master without any warning, and they were none other than Li Yuanjiu, Chi Rong, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun, and the short elderly man with the red complexion.

Golden, crimson, white, and black light surged out of their bodies to form an incredibly dense four-colored light barrier, containing the Reincarnation Palace Master and the explosion of red and golden light.

The light barrier appeared nigh indestructible, and there were countless runes of four different colors swirling around inside.

In the face of the collective power of four Dao Ancestors, the Reincarnation Palace Master was struggling to even lift a finger, and it was as if there were a gargantuan mountain weighing down upon him.

Meanwhile, the golden and red light around him quickly dissipated before fusing into the runes swirling around within the light barrier.

All of this had taken place in the blink of an eye, and only now did everyone fully comprehend what had just happened.

The Devilish Monarch and the three primordial Dao Ancestors immediately prepared to enter the fray, while Gu Huojin took a glance at Chen Ruyan and Yin Ming.

Chen Ruyan's brows furrowed slightly as she vanished from the spot, only to reappear before Bai Ze's trio an instant later, joined by that white-robed, middle-aged man with the frosty aura.

"I do not wish to fight you, so please don't force my hand," Chen Ruyan said as a layer of blue light surfaced over her body.

Deep within the blue light was an antiquated, blue stone gate that was giving off a primal aura, as if it had been in existence even before the creation of heaven and earth.

Within the gate were countless churning waves, and it didn't appear all that remarkable at first glance, but upon closer inspection, one would be struck by the illusion that the stone gate had suddenly become infinitely massive, encompassing the entirety of heaven and earth, while the waves within threatened to inundate and crush anyone that dared to stand in their path.

"This is the Myriad Water Gate!"

Bai Ze, Yue Mian, and the bald man all stopped in their tracks as wary looks appeared on their faces.

Meanwhile, Yin Ming appeared before the devilish army without any warning, and the Devilish Monarch also drew to a halt.

However, the rotund woman beside him continued onward without pause, and a massive, black mace that was even taller than herself appeared in her grasp before being swung through the air.

The black mace swelled drastically in size to form an enormous, black shadow that came crashing down upon Yin Ming with unmatched power, and the Devilish Monarch's expression changed slightly upon seeing this, but he made no effort to stop her.

Meanwhile, Yin Ming remained completely still on the spot, allowing the black mace to strike him head-on.

His body instantly exploded upon contact, only to disintegrate into a vast cloud of black smoke.

The rotund woman faltered slightly upon seeing this, then gave a cold harrumph as she swept her mace through the air, conjuring up a gust of fierce wind to scatter the black smoke.

However, right at this moment, a dazed look suddenly appeared in her eyes, following which a horrified look surfaced on her face, and she let loose a blood-curdling scream, as if she had fallen into some type of illusion.

At the same time, she swung her mace wildly through the air, unleashing countless mace projections that swept through the air in all directions.

The three devilish Dao Ancestors that were about to enter the fray all stopped in their tracks upon seeing this, while the Devilish Monarch's expression darkened slightly as he swept a sleeve through the air.

Countless ripples instantly appeared in the space around the rotund woman, and all of the mace projections, as well as the mace itself, were sucked into the spatial ripples.

Despite the rotund woman's best efforts, she was unable to free her mace from the spatial ripples, and before long, half of her body had also been inundated.

Immediately thereafter, the Devilish Monarch appeared before her, then pressed a finger against her glabella, and a hint of lucidity quickly returned to her eyes, while the irrational horror faded away.

"Thank you, Devilish Monarch," she said in a grateful manner while panting heavily.

The Devilish Monarch swept a sleeve through the air, and all of the surrounding spatial ripples faded away, while the rotund woman turned to discover that Yin Ming was still standing in his original position, seemingly having not even moved a single step.

Chapter 1365: Curse

"You've mastered the laws of heavenly devils, which transcends beyond the laws of inner demons! You must be the Heavenly Devil Dao Ancestor!" the Devilish Monarch deduced.

Yin Ming offered no response, continuing to stand in the devilish army's path in silence.

The rotund woman's expression changed slightly upon hearing this, as did the expressions of the other three devilish Dao Ancestors, while the rest of the devilish army looked on befuddlement.

Most of the banquet attendees also had no idea what the Devilish Monarch was talking about, with only the True Lord Cang Wu's trio and several exceptionally old Great Encompassment cultivators, one of whom was Meng Po, turning to stare at Yin Ming with stunned expressions.

"Who is this Heavenly Devil Dao Ancestor, Mistress? Everyone seems to be very afraid of him," Yu Menghan asked through voice transmission.

"The Heavenly Devil Dao Ancestor is a Dao Ancestor from ancient times, said to have lived for even longer than Supreme Lord Gu Huojin. It's said that whenever he goes into seclusion, his spiritual sense would split up into countless avatars that infiltrated all of the realms, searching for suitable cultivators to contaminate their mental state in order to further his heavenly devil law powers. Those spiritual sense avatars of his are what's commonly referred to as Extrarealm Heaveny Devils," Meng Po replied.

"So all of the Extrarealm Heavenly Devils were created by him!" Yu Menghan exclaimed in a stunned manner.

Extrarealm Heavenly Devils had always been a major cause for concern for all cultivators beyond the Grand Ascension Stage as there was a chance that one would arise with each breakthrough that they made, and countless cultivators throughout history had perished to these feared entities.

"Of course, that's just a rumor, so it may not be true, but the heavenly devil law powers are extremely fearsome, able to easily infiltrate a cultivator's mind and drive them mad, following which the Heavenly Devil Dao Ancestor would feast on the power of his victims' emotions to enhance his own powers. In his quest for power, he destroyed no fewer than a thousand lower realms and even several immortal regions.

“The ruler of the Heavenly Court at the time had sent out over ten Dao Ancestors to hunt him down, and he completely faded into obscurity after that. I didn't think that he was still alive," Meng Po said as a hint of fear flashed through her eyes.

"That's not necessarily the case. Perhaps the Heavenly Devil Dao Ancestor from back then is already dead, and this is someone else who's managed to cultivate the laws of heavenly devils to the top," Yu Menghan speculated.

"That's definitely a possibility, but in any case, this is an extremely dangerous individual that we must stay far away from," Meng Po said.

......

Inside the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array, Han Li was observing Meng Yuan with slightly furrowed brows.

White light was currently rippling over Meng Yuan's body, which was rapidly withering away as a series of wood-like patterns appeared over his skin.

At the same time, his robes had turned into a spruce of withered grass, and in the blink of an eye, it was as if he had transformed into a living scarecrow.

A peculiar feeling welled up in Han Li's heart upon seeing this, and he had no idea what type of law powers he was dealing with.

"It's said that the words of the gods of ancient times were like heavenly decrees, allowing them to speak anything into existence. I wonder how their powers would've compared with my laws of curses," Meng Yuan said as a ball of crimson light suddenly appeared in his left hand.

At the same time, Han Li was struck by a burst of sharp pain in the palms of the three hands on his left side.

He looked down to discover that the palms of his three hands had been pierced through, and the resulting holes were bleeding profusely.

He hurriedly channeled his immortal spiritual power to try and heal the wounds, but not only did that not work, his blood was only flowing faster.

"The show's only just getting started. Enjoy!" Meng Yuan cackled, and as soon as his voice trailed off, three huge holes suddenly appeared in Han Li's three left arms, and these wounds were also bleeding profusely.

Han Li was meticulously scouring his surroundings with his spiritual sense to see if he were being targeted by certain obscure attacks, but that did not appear to have been the case.

Could it be that he really is able to inflict injuries upon others just with curses alone?

"Where should I target next? Let's go for the shoulder..."

Han Li immediately reacted upon hearing this as a burst of radiant, white starlight erupted out of the profound acupoints on his shoulders to form a protective barrier.

However, his efforts proved to be completely futile as a hole was blown into his left shoulder.

Han Li's expression darkened slightly as he reverted back to his human form.

"I must admit that your law powers are very unique. Given my physical constitution, I shouldn't be this inept at dealing with your attacks. Would you be able to enlighten me on the nature of your powers?" Han Li asked.

"Sure, I'll tell you everything once you're dead. I'm going to target the lower abdomen next. It's going to hurt a bit more this time, so get ready!" Meng Yuan cackled, and sure enough, a hole around the same thickness as an infant's arm appeared in Han Li's lower abdomen without any warning, instantly soaking his robes with blood.

Han Li's complexion paled slightly as he stumbled back a couple of steps, and he attempted to raise his mangled left arm, only to discover that it had become as heavy as lead.

"There's no need to put on an act, Fellow Daoist Han. I can tell that these injuries are not enough to make you stumble. Not to worry, there's a lot more left to come," Meng Yuan sneered.

"I wasn't putting on an act, I was just employing a minor distraction," Han Li said with a smile as he made a hand seal with his right hand, which was concealed up his sleeve, and two streaks of golden swordlight suddenly appeared behind Meng Yuan without any warning before racing toward the back of his head and chest at an incredible speed.

However, they were stopped in their tracks by Zi Shan and Dong Lihu, who had swooped in to protect Meng Yuan.

"So my assessment was correct. Even though I've sustained such severe injuries, those who have chosen to protect you rather than continue to attack me, so it must be the case that you cannot move while using your law powers. In that case, why didn't you use your law powers outside the array? Wouldn't that have all but guaranteed your victory?" Han Li asked.

This time, Meng Yuan was happy to give an answer.

"The Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array isolates the space encompassed within it, so I'm unable to use my law powers on you from the outside. Otherwise, how do you think this array was able to trap you?"

"I see," Han Li mused with a nod as a hint of killing intent surfaced in his eyes.

All of a sudden, all of his seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords began hurtling toward Meng Yuan's trio at once.

Zi Shan and Dong Lihu positioned themselves in front of and behind Meng Yuan as the former conjured up a fiery, purple barrier, while the latter produced a golden light barrier, and the two combined to form a huge, spherical light barrier that encompassed the three of them within.

The seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords rained down upon the spherical light barrier, unleashing a torrential barrage of attacks upon it, but were unable to pierce their way through.

"Meng Yuan, cut the chit-chat and kill him already!" Dong Lihu snapped.

"You do it if it's so easy!" Meng Yuan countered as he continued to channel his law powers, and in the next instant, Han Li felt a burst of searing pain in his chest, and another hole was torn in his body right beside his heart.

Cold sweat began to bead up on Han Li's forehead as he discovered that the entire left half of his body was beginning to go numb, and it wasn't the type of numbness that would result from excessive blood loss. Instead, his muscles, sinews, and bones had been sealed away, leaving him unable to even channel his immortal spiritual power and starpower.

It was as if... he were slowly transforming into a scarecrow.

This is not good...

All of a sudden, the seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords reverted back into their childlike form at Han Li's behest, then adopted a certain formation, and an almighty heavenly gate took shape high up in the sky.

"Hurry up, Meng Yuan! He must already be catching on to the fact that something's not right!" Zi Shan urged.

"All I need to do is drive one more needle into his dantian and he'll be completely powerless to resist," Meng Yuan assured, and at the same time, he was proceeding with the utmost caution.

His curse law powers was one of the laws that went most against the Heavenly Dao, and not only was it exceedingly difficult to use, it made him much more susceptible to assimilation from the Heavenly Dao than other Dao Ancestors.

As he was speaking, a transparent needle that was invisible to the naked eye was slowly being driven into his body slightly below his lower abdomen, and it was inching its way toward his dantian.

At the same time, Han Li also began to feel a hint of barely detectable pain in his dantian.

Right at this moment, the heavenly gate up above sprang open, and a massive lightning sword projection formed by hundreds of golden lightning dragons came crashing down upon Meng Yuan.

Dong Lihu looked up to discover that the sword projection was aimed precisely at the seam between the light barriers that he and Zi Shan had conjured up.

That was the most vulnerable part of the spherical light barrier, and it was clearly not going to be able to withstand the falling sword projection.

With that in mind, he withdrew his half of the spherical light barrier and sprang up into the air as several mountain projections appeared in his hand as he threw an almighty punch.

His fist was imbued with the power of several vastly renowned mountains, and as soon it crashed into the sword projection, the latter instantly exploded without being able to pose any resistance.

A hint of triumph flashed through Dong Lihu's eyes upon seeing this, but his expression then instantly swiveled as he hurriedly swung around in alarm.

That sword projection had been nothing more than a distraction, and it had actually disintegrated on its own, so Dong Lihu's punch had only struck empty air.

At this point, Zi Shan had also realized that something was amiss, but it was already too late.

There was an Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Sword concealed within the scattered sword projection, and it had already reached Meng Yuan.

At this point, the transparent needle was only an inch away from piercing into Meng Yuan's dantian...

Chapter 1366: Reversal

A flurry of radiant lightning flashed over the Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Sword, and Han Li abruptly appeared beside it, even though he had been hundreds of thousands of kilometers away just an instant ago, and he grabbed onto the hilt of the sword before slashing it through the air without any hesitation.

Meng Yuan's head flew up into the air, decapitated from his body, while dark golden blood spurted out of his body.

Han Li caught the head, and a flurry of golden lightning erupted out his hand, forming a golden lightning cage around the decapitated head, while Dong Lihu and Zi Shan could only look on helplessly from afar.

Upon being decapitated, Meng Yuan's head had reverted back to its original appearance, as had his headless body, and it was revealed that there were four holes on his left arm and abdomen, corresponding with the locations of the injuries on Han Li's body.

"So your curse law powers allow you to wound your target by harming yourself. No wonder you hadn't dealt any fatal blows upon me up to this point," Han Li mused, and his injuries were already healing as he spoke.

"I only needed a bit more time to leave you completely helpless, but seeing as I've already lost, I have nothing to say," Meng Yuan said, and on the surface, he was looking quite calm and collected, but internally, he was very frustrated.

He had been so close, only for Dong Lihu to ruin everything at the last moment.

"Under normal circumstances, I would've spared you so that I could examine your unique law powers, but given that I have to deal with three other Dao Ancestors, I'll have to send you on your way," Han Li sneered.

He really was very curious about Meng Yuan's curse law powers, but leaving him alive was too much of a risk, one that he wasn't willing to take.

"Han Li, I curse you!" Meng Yuan roared as a furious look appeared on his face.

"Do whatever you please," Han Li replied in an indifferent manner.

......

While all of the devilish and primordial Dao Ancestors were confronting Chen Ruyan and Yin Ming, the Reincarnation Palace Master was still working to free himself.

Dark red light flashed urgently around his body as waves of fearsome reincarnation law powers crashed against the surrounding light barrier.

The four-colored light barrier shuddered violently, while Li Yuanjiu and the other Dao Ancestors were also beginning to display signs of strain.

Gu Huojin made a hand seal in an expressionless manner upon seeing this, and the golden palm projection swooped down once again before fusing into the four-colored light barrier.

A palm print rune appeared over the top of the light barrier in a flash, and an additional color was given to the four-colored light barrier, while its power and thickness both increased significantly.

The Reincarnation Palace Master had been trapped in what was known as a Thirty-Three Heavens Space Locking Array, an ability that had been passed down in the Heavenly Court since ancient times. In order to conjure up the array, multiple Dao Ancestors had to combine their law powers to form a restrictive space.

Furthermore, the more types of law powers that were incorporated, the more powerful the Thirty-Three Heavens Space Locking Array became. It was said that if thirty-three types of law powers could be assembled, then the resulting array would be capable of sealing the entire True Immortal Realm.

However, the more types of law powers that were incorporated, the more difficult the array became to set up. Gu Huojin had only passed down this array to some of the Dao Ancestors serving the Heavenly Court, and most of them were only able to conjure up a four-man Thirty-Three Heavens Space Locking Array.

The palm print rune on the light barrier was flashing incessantly while releasing waves of golden ripples that swept through the interior of the light barrier, and this time, the Reincarnation Palace Master was completely immobilized.

Despite this, Li Yuanjiu and the other Dao Ancestors were still frantically making hand seals to keep the array intact.

A Thirty-Three Heavens Space Locking Array that incorporated five types of law powers was already far beyond what they were capable of controlling.

Gu Huojin made a grabbing motion with his right hand once again, releasing a streak of golden light that vanished into the Reincarnation Palace Master's body before quickly reemerging with a silver talisman, which was delivered into his hand.

The talisman was riddled with complex silver patterns and was giving off extremely subtle spatial power fluctuations.

The Devilish Monarch's expression darkened slightly upon seeing this.

"A spatial location talisman. No wonder Shi Kongyu was able to bypass all of the restrictions of my Heavenly Court to open up spatial passageways here. This is why you came to attend the Bodhi Banquet, right? Unfortunately, you overestimated your own abilities. You should've never come to my Heavenly Court on your own," Gu Huojin said in an indifferent manner.

Subjugated within the five-colored light barrier, the Reincarnation Palace Master was unable to respond.

"Take him away and seal him," Gu Huojin instructed as he crushed the silver talisman in his hand, and Li Yuanjiu and the others gave a collective, affirmative response before flying away with the five-colored light barrier.

The banquet attendees erupted into excited cheers upon seeing this. It was no exaggeration to say that the Reincarnation Palace Master was the Heavenly Court's nemesis, and he had finally been captured.

With his capture, the Reincarnation Palace was no longer a cause for concern, and it also served as a massive hit in morale for the devilish and primordial armies.

Indeed, he should've never come here on his own, even if his purpose was to carry that spatial location talismans into the Jade Pond Paradise. Looks like the legends of his unmatched power and wisdom were severely exaggerated, True Lord Cang Wu thought to himself.

Now that the Reincarnation Palace Master had been captured, the Heavenly Court had clearly gained the upper hand, so perhaps it was time to pick a side.

With that in mind, many of the banquet attendees were beginning to turn their eyes toward the Heavenly Court's Dao Ancestors, including True Lord Cang Wu's trio.

This shift in attitude naturally didn't escape Gu Huojin's attention, and a faint smile appeared on his face, yet right as he was about to say something, two resounding thumps rang out, immediately followed by two agonized cries as a burst of tremendous power swept through the air.

Gu Huojin immediately swung around to discover that a massive, black claw the size of a house was grabbing down upon him, and its five scythe-like tips seemed to be capable of tearing through anything that came into its path.

The giant claw was giving off an incredibly evil aura, as if it had been stewing in resentment for countless years in the depths of hell, and behind the massive claw was the Reincarnation Palace Master, who had somehow managed to free himself.

Behind him, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and the red-faced elderly man had both had their bodies split into two and were laying in puddles of their own blood. They weren't dead, but they weren't going to be able to move anytime soon.

As for Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong, those two were nowhere to be seen.

Gu Huojin's brows furrowed slightly as he swept a sleeve through the air.

His robe was clearly also an immortal treasure, and its sleeve swelled drastically in size before forming a golden light barrier.

The golden light barrier shuddered violently, and the black claw was able to pierce almost halfway through it, but was ultimately stopped in its tracks.

Right at this moment, a blazing fireball shot out of the space behind Gu Huojin before crashing into his back.

Within the fireball was an array that was formed by countless crimson lines, an it was giving off incredibly fearsome heat, melting through the nearby space with ease.

The entire surrounding area was illuminated a crimson color, and the Jade Pond Paradise was instantly transformed into a sea of fire.

Chi Rong emerged from behind the crimson fireball, and at the same time, countless strands of golden light appeared around Gu Huojin, all of which were imbued with astonishing metal law powers.

The nearby flames were sliced to shreds, as was the unbearable heat in the air, providing everyone present with some temporary relief.

All of the strands of golden light were piercing toward Gu Huojin, and they had been released by none other than Li Yuanjiu.

Gu Huojin's expression darkened slightly upon seeing this, he was inundated by the crimson flames and strands of golden light before he had a chance to react.

"Supreme Lord!" the debilitated Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and red-faced elderly man exclaimed in unison.

The Dao Ancestors confronting the devilish and primordial armies were also stunned by this abrupt turn of events, but everything had unfolded too quickly for them to be able to do anything.

What's going on? Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong have defected to the Reincarnation Palace?!

All of the banquet attendees were struggling to believe their own eyes.

Right at this moment, all of the crimson flames and strands of golden light around Gu Huojin suddenly fell completely still, presenting a bizarre sight to behold.

The Reincarnation Palace Master's expression changed slightly upon seeing this, and he hurriedly drifted back in retreat, while Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong also did the same, and it seemed that the three of them were trying to avoid something.

In the next instant, a layer of blue light suddenly appeared in the sky, following which a burst of vast glacial law powers descended from the heavens, instantly transforming the scorching hot environment into one that was teeth-chattering cold.

The Reincarnation Palace Master, Li Yuanjiu, and Chi Rong were momentarily stopped in their tracks as this blanket of glacial law powers descended upon them.

Meanwhile, the white-robed man that had been opposing the primordial Dao Ancestors with Chen Ruyan suddenly appeared in the sky, and with a sweep of his sleeve, countless blue ice spikes took shape before raining down upon the trio below.

Every single ice spike was imbued with immense glacial law powers, and they were freezing the very space around them.

At the same time, hundreds of streaks of light of different colors were sent hurtling toward the trio alongside the barrage of ice spikes. As it turned out, the near one hundred Great Encompassment cultivators serving the Heavenly Court had finally seized an opportunity to attack.

The collective might of close to one hundred Great Encompassment cultivators was nothing to be scoffed at, and the Reincarnation Palace Master chose not to fight fire with fire as he vanished from the spot before reappearing in the air above the devilish army.

At the same time, Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong also flew over to join him.

Chapter 1367: Astonishing Plot

"Get back here, you traitors!" the white-robed man yelled as he prepared to set off in pursuit, and the Heavenly Court's Great Encompassment cultivators were quick to follow his lead.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and the red-faced elderly man were also doing everything in their power to recover from their injuries as they prepared to retaliate, but right at this moment, Gu Huojin's voice suddenly rang out from deep within the crimson flames and strands of golden light.

"Stop!"

All of the Heavenly Court cultivators instantly stopped in their tracks.

A cloud of golden mist began to spread from deep within the crimson flames, and there were countless golden runes dancing within it.

The ghostly, black claw, the crimson flames, and the strands of golden light instantly began to rapidly decay upon contact with the golden mist, and it wasn't long before there was nothing left.

Everyone in the nearby vicinity hurriedly fled from the golden mist like the plague, but right at this moment, the cloud of golden mist faded away to reveal Gu Huojin.

Not only was he completely unharmed, even his robes were immaculately unscathed.

"Are you alright, Supreme Lord?" Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and the red-faced elderly man asked in a concerned manner as they flew over to Gu Huojin's side after reassembling their bodies.

"I'm fine. Such petty tricks would never harm me," Gu Huojin replied.

A hint of excitement flashed through Dao Ancestor Bai Yun's eyes upon hearing this.

The Reincarnation Palace Master, Li Yuanjiu, and Chi Rong were all among the top ten most powerful cultivators in the True Immortal Realm, yet their combined powers hadn't even been enough to leave the slightest scratch on his robes.

Gu Huojin cast an incantation seal into the bodies of Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and the red-faced elderly man, and they instantly reverted back to their original condition.

This wasn't any type of healing ability. Instead, it was as if they had never sustained any injuries in the first place, as if they had gone back in time to before those injuries were sustained.

The Reincarnation Palace Master's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this, while Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and the red-faced elderly man gleefully expressed their gratitude to Gu Huojin.

Gu Huojin waved off their gratitude as he turned his gaze to Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong, and Dao Ancestor Bai Yun did the same as he interrogated in a cold voice, "Li Yuanjiu, Chi Rong, the Heavenly Court has always treated you well, and you've even been granted two seats among the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords and promised the opportunity to transcend beyond the restrictions of the Heavenly Dao in the future, so why have you betrayed the Supreme Lord for the Reincarnation Palace?"

Everyone else in the Jade Pond Paradise also turned to Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong with perplexed expressions, while True Lord Cang Wu's trio was astonished by what they had just heard.

During the earlier conversation between the Reincarnation Palace Master and Gu Huojin, the notion of transcending beyond the Heavenly Dao had been mentioned, but they had only thought that that had been a figure of speech.

However, it seemed that this was a far more tangible thing than they had first imagined.

As Dao Ancestors, the assimilation of the Heavenly Dao was their foremost concern, so if there really was a way to transcend beyond the Heavenly Dao, then they were desperate to find out how.

"Looks like you haven't detected anything at all, Fellow Daoist Bai Yun. You better be careful that you don't get sold by Gu Huojin like a fool," Li Yuanjiu said with a faint smile.

"How dare you slander the Supreme Lord like this!" Dao Ancestor Bai Yun yelled in a furious manner.

"You'll know if it's slander very soon," Li Yuanjiu said with a faint smile, then retreated to behind the Reincarnation Palace Master, while Chi Rong also did the same, positioning the Reincarnation Palace Master at the forefront.

"Fellow daoists of the True Immortal Realm, I have not come to this Bodhi Banquet to cause trouble. Instead, I have come to tell all of you something," the Reincarnation Palace Master declared.

Gu Huojin's brows furrowed slightly upon hearing this, but his composed facade quickly returned.

"What I'm about to tell you concerns a plot that Gu Huojin has been hatching for a very long time, so long that some of you hadn't even begun cultivation at the time of its inception. I am not exaggerating when I say that this is the most heinous plot in all of history, and for his role as the mastermind, he deserves to die countless times over!" the Reincarnation Palace Master declared as he stabbed a finger in Gu Huojin's direction.

"What insolence!"

"You are the one who deserves to die countless times over for your crimes, you scoundrel!"

The cultivators of the Heavenly Court were furious.

"Have you come here just to levy baseless accusations against me? What evidence do you have to back up your claims?" Gu Huojin asked with a composed smile.

"It's a very long story, the origin of which must be traced back to the distant past. As I'm sure all of you are aware, Dao Ancestors are able to draw upon the law powers of the Heavenly Dao, but also are constantly under threat of being devoured by the Heavenly Dao. This is the biggest concern for all Dao Ancestors, and it's a problem that all of the Dao Ancestors throughout history have been trying to resolve.

“Some people have attempted to cultivate secret techniques that bolster their mental fortitude to resist the Heavenly Court, some have refined special immortal treasures for the purpose of warding off the Heavenly Court's assimilation, and some have even tried emulating Earthly Immortals by taking in the power of faith.

“Unfortunately, none of these attempted solutions have proven effective, but things began to change when the Heavenly Court welcomed its previous ruler before Gu Huojin." the Reincarnation Palace Master said.

Gu Huojin's expression changed ever so slightly upon hearing this.

"The previous supreme lord of the Heavenly Court was a peerless prodigy who was able to reach the pinnacle of the laws of time, and he also invented a way to combine law powers of different attributes into one through the use of arrays," the Reincarnation Palace Master continued as a hint of admiration appeared in his eyes.

Everyone in the Jade Pond Paradise was astonished to hear this.

It was extremely difficult to fuse together law powers of different attributes, and it was only achievable through an extensive process of mutual acclimation.

Hence, it was incredible to think that this could be achieved through the use of an array.

Such an extraordinary figure should've been vastly renowned across the entire True Immortal Realm, so why had they never heard of him?

"That supreme lord's name is Gu Daoshen. With the passing of time, many have forgotten him, but I'm sure this is a name that Gu Huojin and the other fellow daoists of the Heavenly Court will be very familiar with," the Reincarnation Palace Master said with a faint smile.

Contemplative looks appeared on everyone's faces upon hearing this.

Gu Huojin and Gu Daoshen both shared the same surname, so was there a connection between the two?

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun took a glance at Gu Huojin, then suddenly interjected, "What's the point in telling these stories? You brought the cultivators of the Devil Realm and the primordial land to this place and also turned Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong against our Heavenly Court all so that you could start a war. In that case, why waste all this time with words?"

"What's the hurry? Could it be that you have something to hide?" the Reincarnation Palace Master asked with a cold sneer.

All of the banquet attendees had begun chattering among themselves through voice transmission upon hearing this. Could it be that the Reincarnation Palace Master was telling the truth, and Gu Huojin and the Heavenly Court really were plotting something in secret?

With these questions hanging in the air, the cultivators who were planning to side with the Heavenly Court were beginning to have second thoughts.

In reality, even the likes of Dao Ancestor Bai Yun didn't know much about Gu Daoshen. All they knew was that he had been the previous supreme lord, and that something had happened between him and Gu Huojin when the position of supreme lord was passed down from one to the other.

They didn't know exactly what had happened at the time, but it clearly wasn't going to be something beneficial to them, given that the Reincarnation Palace Master was choosing to bring it up now.

Gu Huojin remained calm and collected, making no effort to cut off the Reincarnation Palace Master.

"Supreme Lord, I don't know what he's about to say, but we can't allow him to keep swaying hearts like this! Even though we're outnumbered, I'm sure we'll be able to overcome them with your powers. As for all of the banquet attendees, even if they don't help us, I'm sure they wouldn't dare to turn to the Reincarnation Palace," the red-faced elderly man urged through voice transmission.

"It's fine, let him speak. Go ahead, we'll listen," Gu Huojin said as he turned to the Reincarnation Palace Master, not bothering to hide what he was saying behind the veil of voice transmission.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and the red-faced elderly man were clearly still of the opinion that this was not a good idea, but there was nothing that they could do, given that Gu Huojin had already give the Reincarnation Palace Master permission to continue speaking.

"As expected of the ruler of the Heavenly Court. You may be a deplorable man, but you're certainly not lacking in poise," the Reincarnation Palace Master chuckled.

"Gu Daoshen discovered that the combination of multiple law powers could ward off the assimilation of the Heavenly Dao, so he combined nine types of law powers to create the Divine Dao Seal.

“The reason why consuming Bodhi Dao Fruits can delay the assimilation of the Heavenly Dao is precisely because they contain the power of the Divine Dao Seal," the Reincarnation Palace Master revealed, and only then was everyone present made aware of why the Bodhi Dao Fruits had the effect that they did.

Meanwhile, True Lord Cang Wu was looking at the Reincarnation Palace Master with a complex mixture of emotions in his eyes.

He had just been denouncing the Reincarnation Palace Master for his recklessness, but not only was he actually extremely well-prepared, he was also privy to information that was beyond the knowledge of almost everyone present.

In comparison, he felt like a frog sitting at the bottom of a well, and with that in mind, even his desire for vengeance had abated significantly.

"So you're even aware of the Divine Dao Seal. Looks like you really do know quite a lot," Gu Huojin remarked in a calm manner.

"The Divine Dao Seal is far from Gu Daoshen's greatest creation. Instead, that would be the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array, something that he dedicated his entire life to. Then again, there's no need for me to tell you that, considering you, his self corpse soul, were the one who helped him complete the array," the Reincarnation Palace Master scoffed.

"What!"

Everyone turned to Gu Huojin with incredulous expressions upon hearing this, including even the likes of Dao Ancestor Bai Yun.

Chapter 1368: Suspicions

A hint of surprise flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes upon hearing this, but he quickly settled back into his composed facade and remained silent.

The fact that he wasn't denying any of this created another stir among everyone present.

All of a sudden, Zhen Shiyin, the red-robed elderly man standing with True Lord Cang Wu, suddenly interjected, "What is this Three Thousand Daos Divine Array that you speak of, Palace Master?"

Everyone's attention was immediately drawn to him.

There were many people who were internally displeased with the Heavenly Court, but given Gu Huojin's unmatched power and authority, no one dared to openly oppose the Heavenly Court, so it came as a shock to everyone that Zhen Shiyin dared to directly interact with the Reincarnation Palace Master at a time like this.

"It's an array capable of both destroying worlds and creating worlds," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied.

"What's that supposed to mean? Can you elaborate?" Zhen Shiyin asked as he raised an eyebrow.

"If I'm not mistaken, the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array is an array capable of incorporating all of the laws of the world. Once the array is activated, the entire world will be destroyed, returning everything to chaos. The wielder of the array will be able to draw upon its power to overcome the restrictions of the Heavenly Dao, mastering the laws of chaos, said to be the origin of all laws, to become an entity that transcends beyond the Heavenly Dao.

“From there, they'll be able to create a new world that they will be the absolute ruler of," the Reincarnation Palace Master explained.

The entire Jade Pond Paradise had fallen into a stunned silence, and this was no surprise, considering the astonishing revelation that everyone had just been met with.

All of the Heavenly Court Dao Ancestors were just as astonished as everyone else, while Gu Huojin remained as calm and unflustered as ever.

Zhen Shiyin turned to Gu Huojin with a horrified expression as he asked, "Is the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array how you plan to overcome the Heavenly Dao?"

Everyone instantly turned to Gu Huojin upon hearing this.

"That is the only way to transcend beyond the Heavenly Dao, isn't that right, Fellow Daoist Gu?" the Reincarnation Palace Master answered before Gu Huojin had a chance to speak.

"Are you telling the truth?" Zhen Shiyin asked as he turned to stare intently at the Reincarnation Palace Master.

"In order to activate the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array, two prerequisites must be fulfilled, the first of which is that there must be an extremely vast energy supply, and that's why the Heavenly Court has been plundering spirit materials from all of the immortal regions over the years," the Reincarnation Palace Master said.

"And what's the second prerequisite?" Zhen Shiyin asked.

"That would be to gather as many types of law powers as possible, and that's something that the Heavenly Court has also been secretly working on. I'm sure all of you are aware of what happens to the fugitives captured by the Immortal prison. On top of that, the Heavenly Court has also been constantly collecting treasures that contain special law powers for the same purpose," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied.

All of the banquet attendees seemed to have been convinced by the Reincarnation Palace Master's story, and they collectively turned to Gu Huojin with mixed emotions in their eyes.l

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun could see that the tide of public opinion was quickly turning against their favor, and he hurriedly yelled, "That's pure nonsense! How could there possibly exist an array that's capable of destroying an entire world? As for the law powers extracted from the fugitives in the Immortal Prison, that's done as a punishment, and their law powers are used to refine immortal treasures.

“The materials with special law powers that are collected by the Heavenly Court are also used to refine certain special treasures to be used to oppose the Reincarnation Palace. Do not be fooled, everyone!"

"That's right! The Reincarnation Palace is constantly seeking to wreak havoc and dissension everywhere, and it's now attempting to do so in the very heart of the Heavenly Court!" the red-faced elderly man yelled.

"Fellow Daoist Bai Yun, I've also always been curious about why your Heavenly Court has been extracting the law powers of its fugitives, and my investigation tells me that those extract law powers have not been sent to the Hundred Refinement Peak, where the Heavenly Court refines immortal treasures. Instead, they've been sent elsewhere," Zhen Shiyin said.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun turned to him with a cold look in his eyes upon hearing this.

"At this point, I am unable to continue placing my trust in the Heavenly Court. I have no intention of taking any part in this conflict, so please excuse me now," Zhen Shiyin said as he cupped his fist in a parting salute, then turned to fly out of the Jade Pond Paradise.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch exchanged a glance with one another, and the latter raised a hand, upon which the devilish army parted to allow Zhen Shiyin safe passage.

As opposed to actually departing, Zhen Shiyin chose a safe place to stop nearby, and many of the banquet attendees quickly began to follow his lead, flying their way to safety.

True Lord Cang Wu and the azure-haired Dao Ancestor exchanged a glance with one another, then also followed suit, and in the blink of an eye, most of the cultivators in the Jade Pond Paradise had departed, leaving only less than a third left.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun was both alarmed and infuriated to see this, but with no instructions issued by Gu Huojin, he didn't dare to try and keep anyone from leaving by force.

Meanwhile, Chen Ruyan and Yin Ming remained firm in their positions, standing in the paths of the devilish and primordial armies.

With most of the banquet attendees gone, the Heavenly Court's forces were placed at even more of a disadvantage.

"How impressive that you were able to weaken the Heavenly Court's forces by so much just through a few words," the Devilish Monarch remarked through voice transmission.

"You're far too kind, Devilish Monarch. I was only revealing the truth. If it weren't for Gu Huojin's heinous ways, there's no way I would've been able to convince anyone," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied.

"You've done well, Palace Master. Leave the rest to us," the Devilish Monarch said, then swept a sleeve through the air, and the devilish army immediately began to march forward, with their collective footsteps producing a thunderous rumble.

The primordial army also began to advance, and the encirclement was shrinking by the second.

......

A burst of lightning erupted out of the palm of Han Li's hand, and plumes of smoke began billowing out of the orifices of Meng Yuan's head.

Regardless of whether this final curse of Meng Yuan's was nothing more than a furious diatribe or an actual curse, Han Li had no interest in hearing it to its conclusion.

Moments later, Meng Yuan's aura completely faded away, and Zi Shan and Dong Lihu exchanged a grim glance with one another.

As a safety precaution, Han Li sent the Essence Fire Raven into Meng Yuan's already charred black head, then tossed the head back onto his headless body, which instantly erupted into silver flames.

"You two are next," Han Li said as he turned his gaze to Zi Shan and Dong Lihu.

"Looks like we have no choice but to engage him in a direct battle. If we prove to be no match, then just incinerate everything in this Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array. There's no need to worry about me," Dong Lihu sighed.

Zi Shan was silent for a moment before nodding in response.

Dong Lihu swept both hands through the air, and bursts of formidable law power fluctuations instantly surged out of his body as a series of massive mountain projections appeared behind him.

"Han Li, do you dare to oppose my fist head-on?" Dong Lihu roared.

"Sure, show me what you've got," Han Li said with a faint smile as he released his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Sword, and it transformed into a sword spirit child before flying away to the side.

In the next instant, he launched himself at the oncoming Dong Lihu while releasing a golden spirit domain that encompassed both of them.

Countless golden ripples were sweeping through the entire spirit domain, and Dong Lihu instantly felt as if he were advancing through treacle, with his progress slowed down significantly.

However, he refused to back down as he clenched his fist tightly and threw a punch at Han Li.

The mountain projections behind him began to dissipate, transforming into bursts of golden light that surged into his arm, then flowed into his fist, and it began to glow with blinding, golden radiance.

At the same time, numerous vast mountains in several immortal regions were suddenly completely depleted of their spiritual qi before exploding without any warning.

This punch of Dong Lihu's was imbued with the power of over a hundred mountains.

A hint of excitement and battle intent surfaced in Han Li's eyes upon seeing this, and his five time law treasure manifestations behind him flew into his body, while a burst of destructive, five-elemental power took shape in his fist.

He threw an almighty punch forward, releasing a gargantuan, golden fist projection that struck Dong Lihu's mountainous fist, and both instantly exploded violently upon impact.

A burst of incredibly violent power swept through the surrounding area, creating countless spatial rifts, but unfortunately, all of them were extremely small and only lingered for a moment before fading away.

The resulting shockwaves sent both Han Li and Dong Lihu flying back tens of thousands of kilometers, following Han Li launched himself at the latter once again.

Meanwhile, Dong Lihu was looking on with an astonished expression and a trembling arm.

He had lost to Han Li in a pure clash of strength.

Right at this moment, a sharp, whistling sound rang out.

A bow had appeared in Zi Shan's grasp, and she had just fired an arrow of purple flames in Han Li's direction.

The arrow was racing through the air at an astonishing speed, and in response, Han Li swept a sleeve through the air, sending countless ripples surging out of his Mantra Treasured Axis to oppose the arrow.

However, the arrow was somehow able to remain completely unaffected by his time law powers, and it passed through the golden ripples en route to Han Li's heart without even the slightest bit of deceleration!

Chapter 1369: Making a Move

Han Li injected his starpower into his arms before crossing them in front of himself to form a protective barrier, but the arrow passed through his arms as if they didn't exist before nailing itself into his chest.

In the instant that the arrow flew into his chest, it immediately reverted back into a substantial form, and Han Li was involuntarily sent flying back through the air as a burst of indescribable scorching pain speared through his chest.

Not only was the arrow capable of phasing between a substantial and insubstantial form, it had ignited in his body, and he felt as if his immortal spiritual power had been sealed away, leaving him unable to get up.

"Kill him while his body is sealed by my purple flames!" Zi Shan yelled, and even without her instruction, Dong Lihu had already sprung up into the air before swooping down upon Han Li.

A projection of a mountain-moving giant appeared behind him, and the mountain that the giant was carrying above its head was said to have been Mount Tai, the ancestral mountain of all mountains.

If this projection of Mount Tai were to fall upon Han Li, then he would undoubtedly be crushed under it, even with his tremendous physical constitution.

However, right at this moment, the Essence Fire Raven suddenly appeared over his chest as a burst of silver flames.

As it turned out, the Essence Fire Raven had blocked the arrow for him, and he had only been putting on an act this entire time. However, the Essence Fire Raven was no match for the power of a Dao Ancestor, and it had sustained very severe injuries from the arrow.

As it returned to his body to rest and recuperate, Han Li sprang up into the ground while delivering it an apology.

Immediately thereafter, he channeled all of his true spirit bloodlines and his Heavenly Baleful Purgatory Arts at once, instantly transforming into a giant devilish deity with twenty-four arms and twelve heads, all of which were displaying different emotions.

A burst of dark purple light erupted out of the devilish deity's body, causing Dong Lihu to involuntarily slow down in his descent.

What the hell is he?!

Zi Shan was very alarmed to see this, and she hurriedly set off after Dong Lihu.

As for Dong Lihu himself, it was already too late for him to turn back, so he could only accelerate in his descent toward Han Li, who let loose a thunderous roar as he began swinging his twenty-four fists upward in a ferocious barrage of attacks.

The entire surrounding space trembled violently as bursts of formidable power swept through the air in all directions, forcing back the approaching Zi Shan.

The barrage of punches from Han Li was so fierce that it was keeping Dong Lihu aloft high up in the sky, unable to descend any further.

Moments later, a loud crack rang out, and countless cracks appeared over the surface of the mountain-moving giant projection behind him, following which it exploded violently.

However, Han Li wasn't done with him just yet, and he sprang up into the air before continuing to rain punches down upon Dong Lihu.

In the blink of an eye, Dong Lihu had already been struck by a million punches, at which point he had already fallen unconscious. After ten million punches, his entire body had been reduced to a pile of mincemeat, and only then did Han Li cease his merciless barrage.

At this moment, all twenty-four of his eyes were brimming with triumph and fierce battle intent, even though his twelve faces were still wearing different expressions.

He turned his gaze to Zi Shan, who shuddered slightly as she took an involuntary backward step.

She took a glance at Dong Lihu, who was completely out of commision, and the thought of retreat began to take root in her mind.

However, right at this moment, a peculiar look suddenly appeared in her eyes as she cast her gaze toward the mountain range formed by Illusory Dawn Sand behind Han Li.

Almost in the exact same instant, Han Li's expression changed slightly as he also turned to the same direction.

A large section of the lush Eastern Vicissitudes Divine Tree forest on the mountain range had completely withered away, as if all of its energy had been leached away.

Han Li swept his spiritual sense over the area, but didn't notice anything amiss.

However, he suddenly realized that he was no longer able to detect the aura of Zhu Yan, who had been crushed under the mountain range earlier.

......

Inside the Jade Pond Paradise, the tension in the air was becoming more and more palpable by the second, and all of the Heavenly Court cultivators were watching the approaching devilish and primordial forces with fearful expressions.

With the departure of True Lord Cang Wu's trio and the betrayal of Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong, the Heavenly Court was at a severe disadvantage when it came to top-end power.

As for the few banquet attendees that remained, it was clear from their expressions that they had no intention of helping the Heavenly Court.

"The situation has become very unfavorable for us, Supreme Lord," Dao Ancestor Bai Yun said through voice transmission.

"It's fine," Gu Huojin replied in a calm manner, and his composure was very reassuring to the Heavenly Court's forces.

Gu Huojin had ruled over the entire True Immortal Realm for countless years, so he was sure to have some tricks up his sleeve.

"Very impressive, Palace Master. You've managed to significantly weaken our Heavenly Court's forces without having to incur even a single casualty," Gu Huojin praised.

"I didn't have to do anything. You brought all of this upon yourself," the Reincarnation Palace Master harrumphed coldly as he swept a sleeve through the air, and a streak of light dark red light that was over a hundred thousand feet in length and several hundred feet thick swept toward the Heavenly Court cultivators like an almighty wave.

In response, Gu Huojin made a hand seal to conjure up a thin streak of golden light in retaliation, and as soon as the two streaks of light clashed, the dark red wave instantly melted away like snow tossed onto fire.

However, the thin streak of golden light had also become extremely dim, and it faded away shortly thereafter.

With the Reincarnation Palace Master making a move, the Devilish Monarch and Bai Ze also issued the order to attack, and their armies pounced onto the Heavenly Court's forces.

Even though they were clearly at a severe disadvantage, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun and the Heavenly Court cultivators had no choice but to engage the enemy.

A chaotic commotion instantly shattered the peace and quiet of the Jade Pond Paradise as the two sides clashed, and countless immortal treasures and streaks of light of different colors flashed through the air, while spirit domains clashed and overlapped with one another.

Everything in the Jade Pond Paradise was instantly pulverized into nothingness, while the space also shattered like a mirror, releasing bursts of violent spatial turbulence, which were then also quickly eradicated.

The entire area had transformed into a vast expanse of dark, shattered space, and the entire Heavenly Palace Continent was trembling incessantly.

Thankfully, the continent was enormous, and it had become extremely resilient thanks to the efforts that the Heavenly Court had made in bolstering it over the course of countless years, so it was able to remain intact.

The cultivators that had already evacuated the Jade Pond Paradies hurriedly evacuated even further to ensure their own safety, and in the meantime, the Dao Ancestors from both sides had also begun making their moves.

The four devilish Dao Ancestors outside of the Devilish Monarch launched themselves through the air as four streaks of light, while Bai Ze's trio also did the same.

In contrast, Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong remained by the Reincarnation Palace Master's side as both of them stared intently at Gu Huojin.

Gu Huojin turned his gaze to Yin Ming, who was already opposing the devilish army, then asked, "Can I leave the devilish army to you and Fellow Daoist Ruyan?"

Even though it was a question, it was clear that he would only accept one answer.

"As one of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords, it's only right that I fight for the Heavenly Court, but we are outnumbered, and the Devilish Monarch hasn't even made a move yet, so the two of us may not be able to keep them at bay for long. Hence, I implore you to make a decision soon, Supreme Lord," Chen Ruyan said.

"Sure," Gu Huojin replied with a faint smile, and with that, Chen Ruyan flew toward the four devilish Dao Ancestors as a streak of blue light.

With a sweep of her sleeve, a dazzling, blue wheel of light shot forth, then split up into eighty-one radiant, blue dragons.

These eighty-one dragons were all formed by blue light, but they appeared no different from true dragons, and all of them were giving off astonishing water law power fluctuations.

In the blink of an eye, all of the blue dragons intertwined with one another to form a blue array that descended upon the four devilish Dao Ancestors.

Meanwhile, Yin Ming raised his hands, and countless black shadows appeared around him.

These shadows weren't physical entities, but they weren't completely insubstantial, either, and they were able to take on all types of different forms in accordance with the thoughts of the beholder.

Chapter 1370: Bribery

Among the four devilish Dao Ancestors, the withered corpse-like man said to the seductive woman and the rotund woman, "His heavenly devil law powers are extremely proficient in manipulating the minds of others, so leave him to me and Brother Jin. He Lan, you and Fellow Daoist Gui Ling can take on Chen Ruyan."

"Chen Ruyan is said to be the most beautiful and most powerful woman in the Heavenly Court. Let's see if she's worthy of those titles," the seductive woman said as she turned to Chen Ruyan with a competitive gleam in her eyes.

She then swept a sleeve through the air to release hundreds of streaks of dark purple light, all of which transformed into giant tree-like purple vines, at the ends of which bloomed stunningly beautiful flowers the size of houses.

However, the petals of these flowers were riddled with sharp thorns, and they were constantly moving like living beings, presenting a harrowing sight to behold.

The seductive woman pointed a finger forward, and the hundreds of devilish flowers immediately sped toward Chen Ruyan's array of blue dragons.

The two sides clashed with an earth-shattering boom, and blue and purple light erupted in all directions, causing the surrounding gray space to tremble violently.

The rotund woman took a resentful glance at Yin Ming, but she also knew that she was no match for his heavenly devil law powers.

With a cold harrumph, she dropped to the ground, and her body transformed into a black storm that was several dozen kilometers in size, with countless pillars of black wind surging out of it.

A low roar rang out as a bloated, black beast emerged within the black storm.

The beast had the head of a lion and nine crimson eyes, but a lizard-like body with a pair of giant, fleshy wings on its back that were far longer than its body. The wings were lined with sharp claws, and with a flap of those wings, the black storm instantly swelled drastically in size before sweeping toward Chen Ruyan, crashing against the blue dragon array with another resounding boom.

The four of them had risen to extremely high altitudes, almost to the Extraheavensphere, so the armies down below weren't affected by their battle.

The corpse-like man and the yellow-robed man with the deathly aura pounced at Yin Ming, and as he did so, the corpse-like man began chanting an incantation, upon which his body rapidly swelled to over a hundred thousand times its original size, transforming him into a gruesome-looking yellow zombie.

Countless streams of yellow pus were squirting out of his body, producing an indescribably nauseating odor.

The giant zombie swept its hands through the air, releasing ten streaks of yellow light that raced toward the vast expanse of black devilish shadows.

In contrast with the rotund woman, the corpse-like man was somehow able to remain unaffected by Yin Ming's heavenly devil law powers.

Meanwhile, the yellow-robed man drew his longsword, which was gray in color, then thrust it forward, and an enormous, gray sword projection appeared in front of Yin Ming without any warning before hurtling toward him.

Incredibly fearsome sword qi converged from all directions, giving off a deathly aura that reduced the entire surrounding area into lifeless, gray dust.

Yin Ming's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this, seemingly rather apprehensive of the oncoming sword projection, and a hexagram array appeared beneath his feet.

In the next instant, he vanished from the spot, while six identical Yin Mings appeared at the tips of the hexagram array.

These six figures were completely identical in aura and appearance, making it impossible to tell which one was the real Yin Ming.

The yellow-robed man provided a direct and simple solution to the problem, splitting his gray sword projection into six to attack the six Yin Mings at once.

The six Yin Mings each made a hand seal in unison, and the sound of countless ghosts wailing at once instantly rang out across the entire space as one dark passageway appeared after another, with countless Extrarealm Heavenly Devils surging out of each one to inundate the pair of opposing devilish Dao Ancestors.

All of the Extrealm Heavenly Devils possessed extremely formidable auras, with no lack of Great Encompassment Stage ones among them, and a fierce battle ensued.

Meanwhile, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun, the red-faced elderly man, and the white-robed man were also clashing against the three primordial Dao Ancestors.

The six of them were inundated by lights of different colors, making it impossible to tell exactly what was happening, but it was clear that an intense battle was taking place inside.

The Heavenly Court Dao Ancestors were able to withstand the collective assault from the Devil Realm and the primordial land, but the rest of them were struggling immensely, having already been forced to gather together to form a defensive array.

The Heavenly Court cultivators were able to hold their own for now, but they were extremely passive and incapable of retaliation, and if nothing changed, then they would suffer a slow and painful demise.

Countless attacks were raining down from the heavens, and the protective barrier formed by the Heavenly Court cultivators was becoming thinner and thinner, while their hopes diminished more and more by the second.

"Looks like the Reincarnation Palace has seized the firm upper hand. Now, it's just a case of whether the Reincarnation Palace Master can defeat Gu Huojin," True Lord Cang Wu said as he observed the battle from afar.

"If Gu Huojin is allowed to get away, then the True Immortal Realm is most likely going to enter a period of great turmoil," the azure-haired Dao Ancestor remarked.

Zhen Shiyin conjured up a soundproofing restriction, then said, "In that case, why don't we help the Reincarnation Palace Master capture Gu Huojin to ensure the safety of the True Immortal Realm? In doing so, we'll also ensure that we're on the winning side. From what I've heard, the Reincarnation Palace Master seems to be a decent person. Otherwise, he wouldn't have been able to bring together both the devil race and the demon race."

The azure-haired man turned to True Lord Cang Wu upon hearing this, and the latter was silent for a moment, then chuckled, "I see that you've come here to lobby for the Reincarnation Palace, Fellow Daoist Zhen."

Zhen Shiyin faltered slightly upon hearing this, then asked, "Why do you say that, Fellow Daoist Cang Wu?"

"Back in the Jade Pond Paradise, you were clearly assisting the Reincarnation Palace Master in convincing everyone to leave. Also, I heard that you recently received a large sum of Immortal Origin Stones, with which you bought a huge spirit vine in the Yin Heavens Immortal Region, and that you're planning to establish a sect there.

“If I'm not mistaken, those Immortal Origin Stones were given to you by the Reincarnation Palace, right?" True Lord Cang Wu asked.

Zhen Shiyin's brows furrowed slightly upon hearing this, while the azure-haired Dao Ancestor turned to him with a surprised expression.

"Not only you, Fellow Daoist Zhen, but most of the sects that have chosen to leave the Jade Pond Paradise were bribed by the Reincarnation Palace at some point," True Lord Cang Wu continued.

"Is that true?" the azure-haired Dao Ancestor exclaimed.

"If not for that, do you really think so many people would be willing to leave just from hearing what the Reincarnation Palace Master had to say?" True Lord Cang Wu harrumphed.

"Buying out so many people must've required an incalculable amount of wealth. The Reincarnation Palace must've spent close to its entire wealth on that alone. What an impressive show of determination from the Reincarnation Palace Master," the azure-haired man praised.

"Now that I've been exposed, I suppose there's no need for me to hide it any longer. Fellow Daoist Cang Wu is correct in that the Reincarnation Palace Master has indeed approached me in the past. He also asked me to try and win over the two of you, and he has promised the two of you the same compensation that he gave me in exchange for your help," Zhen Shiyin admitted with a smile.

"I'm flattered that the Reincarnation Palace Master thinks so highly of me. Given what Gu Huojin is plotting, it's only right that I side with the Reincarnation Palace for the sake of the countless living beings of this world!" the azure-haired man decided.

"I assure you that's a wise decision, Fellow Daoist Feng. Right now, the Heavenly Court is already on the verge of collapse, and all that's required is another little push!" Zhen Shiyin said in an ecstatic manner, while True Lord Cang Wu remained silent, refusing to take a stance.

"Fellow Daoist Cang Wu, I know that you have a vendetta against the Reincarnation Palace Master, but now's not the time to be getting caught up in personal vendettas. If we allow Gu Huojin to get away today, the entire world will be in great peril.

“Also, the Reincarnation Palace Master possesses a Six Paths Reincarnation Plate that grants him control over the cycle of reincarnation. He has promised to use the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate to resurrect your fallen disciple if you're willing to lend him your assistance here," Zhen Shiyin said.

"Is that true?" True Lord Cang Wu asked in an excited manner.

"Someone of the Reincarnation Palace Master's status wouldn't lie about something like this. However, he has told us that your resurrected disciple won't have his memories from his past life, but he'll still have his cultivation aptitude," Zhen Shiyin said with a smile.

"That's fine, I can nurture him again given enough time. In that case, I am also willing to lend the Reincarnation Palace Master my assistance," True Lord Cang Wu said.

Zhen Shiyin was ecstatic to hear this, and the three of them began devising a plan together.

......

Right as Han Li was searching for Zhu Yan's aura, a speck of azure light suddenly appeared amid the withered section of the Eastern Vicissitudes Divine Tree, following which a small tree quickly emerged.

The tree grew rapidly before sprouting four limbs and transforming into a petite figure with incredibly potent wood law power fluctuations emanating from its body.

It was a gorgeous young woman who sprang up into the air, and Han Li noticed that her aura was identical to that of the elderly Zhu Yan.

Chapter 1371: Mounting Pressure

"Let me introduce you to my laws of vicissitudes, Han Li! The last time I fought a battle of life and death was several million years ago, and during that time, my fortunes have transitioned from priority to decay, but on this day, your Twin Births Tree has helped me return to prosperity. You were fated to die by my hands!" Zhu Yan yelled in a gleeful manner.

She swept a hand through the air as she spoke, and her long, black hair instantly swelled to form an all-encompassing wave of black vines that inundated her entire body.

All of the space within a radius of close to a hundred thousand kilometers was quickly taken over by the black wave, and in response, Han Li summoned all seventy-two of his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords back to his side, upon which they formed a giant, circular sword array around him.

Immediately thereafter, they began to circle around rapidly in the air while releasing long tendrils of lightning and streaks of peerlessly sharp sword qi to eradicate the oncoming wave of black hair.

As opposed to lending Zhu Yan her assistance, Zi Shan picked up Dong Lihu's pulverized body and sent him out of the array.

Han Li flew directly toward Zhu Yan in an unstoppable fashion, completely untouchable within his sword array.

However, after flying for several thousand kilometers, he suddenly noticed that all of the hair that had been severed behind him was hovering in mid-air to surround him from all directions.

All of a sudden, the scattered lengths of hair suddenly fused back together on their own to form a massive, black vortex.

The sword array around him was instantly vanquished, and all of the flying swords were caught within clumps of black hair, unable to escape.

Countless strands of hair had wound themselves around Han Li's waist and limbs, and more hair was converging toward him from all directions, crushing him from all sides.

At the same time, bursts of indescribable law power fluctuations were constantly surging into his body through the masses of moving hair, making him feel as if there were waves constantly brushing against his body.

It wasn't an uncomfortable sensation, but he could sense that with each passing wave, something in his body was gradually seeping away.

He looked down at his own arm to discover that his skin had become withered and wrinkled, as if he were being reduced to an old man.

It's not an illusion! How could this be?

Han Li was also capable of drastically accelerating the flow of time to significantly age someone in an instant, but how was Zhu Yan capable of doing this?

On top of that, he was only one step away from becoming a Dao Ancestor, making him as close to a true immortal as conceivably possible, so how had he aged so much in the short span of fewer than twenty seconds?

After a brief moment of contemplation, Han Li quickly composed himself and channeled his own immortal spiritual power, and the withered skin on his skin instantly returned to normal amid a flash of azure light.

However, mere moments later, the skin there quickly turned aged and withered once again, only recovering with another injection of immortal spiritual power.

With that, a tug of war ensued between Zhu Yan's law powers and his immortal spiritual power, and his skin was constantly going through the repetitive cycle of rejuvenation and decay.

Furthermore, he could sense that as the cycle continued to repeat itself, Zhu Yan's law powers were gradually infiltrating into his bones through his skin. If things were to continue like this, then even his Great Encompassment Stage body would eventually be broken down.

Despite this, he remained calm and collected as he sneered, "Let me show you what true acceleration of the flow of time looks like!"

His spirit domain rapidly shrank as he spoke until it was only encompassing the surrounding area within a radius of several thousand kilometers, and his five time law treasures also returned to the spirit domain before manifesting the Five Elemental Illusory World.

Inside the Five Elemental Illusory World, the flow of time was accelerated by a thousandfold. As a result, the rate at which Zhu Yan was expending her law powers had increased by a thousandfold, while the cycle of rejuvenation and decay that Han Li was experiencing was also sped up by the same degree.

However, Han Li had already devised a countermeasure to this, and he channeled his Heavenly Baleful Purgatory Arts, upon which all of his profound acupoints lit up, while his True Extreme Film surfaced over his body.

As a result, the effects that Zhu Yan's vicissitudes law powers had on him were significantly diminished.

He took advantage of this opportunity to cast his gaze in Jin Tong's direction to discover that most of the space around her had already collapsed and was in a very unstable state.

This was naturally quite an encouraging sight, and he turned his gaze back to Zhu Yan to discover that she was looking far less triumphant than before.

After around fifteen minutes, Han Li was still trapped within the vortex of hair, but the hair around him had noticeably receded significantly, and there were many sections that had turned a lifeless shade of gray.

A faint smile appeared on Han Li's face upon seeing this.

The rate at which Zhu Yan was being assimilated by the Heavenly Dao far exceeded the rate at which her law powers were infiltrating his body, so it was only a matter of time before she would be forced to give up.

At the moment, Zhu Yan was understandably feeling very frustrated. She had thought that she would be able to break down Han Li's body with her law powers, but her plans had been completely thwarted.

As Han Li accelerated the flow of time further and further, the majority of her hair had turned white, and she didn't dare to hesitate any longer as her hair released Han Li at her behest before retreating like a receding tide.

However, Han Li wasn't about to let her off the hook, and he grabbed onto her hair with a cold sneer, following which a burst of silver flames erupted out of the palm of his hand, instantly incinerating tens of thousands of kilometers of hair as it spread rapidly toward Zhu Yan.

However, right at this moment, Zi Shan suddenly descended upon Zhu Yan's hair before releasing a burst of purple flames out of her hand, which instantly overwhelmed the silver flames before sweeping toward Han Li.

After forcing back Han Li, Zi Shan turned to Zhu Yan and said in an urgent manner, "I'll hold him off while you go and stop the Gold Devouring Immortal! It'll be too late otherwise!"

"It's already too late!" Han Li chuckled as he made a hand seal, and the seventy-two sword spirit children instantly flew toward Jin Tong in unison.

"Stop them!" Zi Shan yelled, and Zhu Yan's hair immediately set off in pursuit of the Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords.

Han Li swept a sleeve to the heavens upon seeing this, and all of the stars in the sky formed by his Time Severing Torch came crashing down like a meteor shower while releasing waves of immense time law powers.

Zi Shan and Zhu Yan were both inundated by the waves of time law powers, and the flow of time around them instantly ceased, as if they had fallen into a stagnant river of time.

Immediately thereafter, a true river of time descended upon them like a jade belt, then enveloped them to fortify the surrounding time restrictions.

The full moon in the sky also descended from the heavens to hover above the two of them at Han Li's behest, and this time, he learned not to use the mountain range and the Eastern Vicissitudes Divine Tree forest growing upon it.

Han Li had only just trapped the two Dao Ancestors when a resounding boom rang out in the distance.

He hurriedly tuned to discover that his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords were flying back to him in their sword spirit children form, having just sliced an enormous gash into the space where Jin Tong was situated.

An opening had finally been torn into the Ubiquitous Myriad Immortal Array.

An elated look appeared on Han Li's face as he withdrew his Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, but all of a sudden, he suddenly detected an immense aura behind him, one that was rapidly elevating.

He turned around to find that a burst of radiant, purple light had appeared amid his time law treasure manifestations, and it was quickly becoming brighter and brighter.

Han Li's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this, and he hurriedly withdrew his time law treasures for fear that they would be damaged, following which he immediately began flying toward Jin Tong.

......

In the sky above the Jade Pond Paradise, Gu Huojin was surrounded by the Reincarnation Palace Master, the Devilish Monarch, Li Yuanjiu, and Chi Rong.

"Gu Huojin, I've been waiting for this moment for countless years!" the Reincarnation Palace Master declared as a hint of fierce killing intent flashed through his eyes.

Even with four top-tier Dao Ancestors around him, Gu Huojin remained completely unflustered as he asked, "Do you think you've won?"

"What could you possibly do to turn the tables? I've already sealed all of the Heavenly Court teleportation arrays littered throughout the Middle Earth Immortal Region, so if you're waiting for reinforcements, then I suggest you perish the thought," the Devilish Monarch sneered.

Chapter 1372: Escape

Gu Huojin was completely unbothered by this revelation, and a faint smile appeared on his face as he quickly made a string of hand seals, upon which what appeared to have been a complex array appeared over his glabella.

The array was formed by runes of nine different colors, each of which was giving off a different type of law powers.

However, not only were these nine types of law powers not in conflict with one another, they were fused together in a harmonious state to produce a peculiar aura that was somewhat similar to the power of the Heavenly Dao.

Radiant, nine-colored light erupted out of Gu Huojin's body in all directions, and his four assailants hurriedly adopted protective measures, but the nine-colored light merely swept over them in an innocuous fashion.

"What did you just do?" the Devilish Monarch asked as a dark look appeared on his face, while the Reincarnation Palace Master was also on high alert.

Right at this moment, Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong cried out in pain and alarm in unison, and a nine-colored diagram appeared over each of their glabellas before releasing lines of nine-colored light that spread rapidly over their bodies.

In the blink of an eye, both of them were completely covered in these nine-colored lines, and it seemed that this nine-colored light was attempting to control their bodies, but given that both of them were Essential Dao Ancestors that commanded tremendous power, they were able to stave off its controlling effects.

However, the two of them were temporarily robbed of their ability to use their law powers, and right at this moment, a pair of giant, golden palm projections appeared above them before crashing down upon their heads.

Gu Huojin had made his first move, and Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong were powerless to defend themselves.

All off a sudden, two streaks of dark red light raced through the air to oppose the pair of palm projections, and it was the Reincarnation Palace Master who had intervened in a timely fashion.

The two streaks of dark red light were instantly eradicated upon contact, but the pair of palm projections were also slowed down for an instant.

At the same time, a burst of spatial fluctuations erupted forth as the two of them vanished into thin air, causing the pair of palm projections to completely miss their targets.

Several hundred kilometers away, Li Yuanjiu and Chi Rong reemerged along with the Devilish Monarch and the Reincarnation Palace Master.

"Are you two alright?" the Devilish Monarch asked while keeping a wary eye on Gu Huojin.

"The marks on our foreheads attempted to control our law powers. I don't know what they are and when they entered our bodies," Li Yuanjiu explained while resisting the nine-colored array on his glabella with all his might, and Chi Rong was doing the same.

"Those are Divine Dao Seals," the Reincarnation Palace Master declared with a grim expression.

"What? Aren't Divine Dao Seals meant to ward off the assimilation of the Heavenly Dao?" Chi Rong exclaimed.

"That's right, but I tampered with the Divine Dao Seal a little on this occasion," Gu Huojin explained as he flew over from afar, and right at this moment, all of the cultivators that had just evacuated from the Jade Pond Paradise came flying back from afar.

The Divine Dao Seal had appeared over their glabellas as well, and judging from the panicked looks on their faces, it was clear that they were not in control of their own bodies.

Furthermore, blinding light was radiating from their bodies, as if they were burning through their own life force, and they crashed into the defenseless rear of the devilish army.

These cultivators were overexerting themselves to the extreme with no regard for their own health, and they were unleashing ferocious barrages of attacks like madmen, displaying superior combat prowess than under normal circumstances.

Countless immortal treasures were sent hurtling into the devilish army's ranks, and in the blink of an eye, a large number of casualties had already been incurred.

The banquet attendees were far more powerful than the devilish army's forces to begin with, and the latter had also been caught completely off guard.

As a result, large holes were quickly torn into the encirclement, and the Heavenly Court cultivators were ecstatic to see this as they withdrew their defensive array and also went on the attack.

The cultivators that were being involuntarily controlled stormed through the devilish army before crashing into the primordial army, where they continued their deranged spree of slaughter.

......

Han Li had only just withdrawn all of his time law treasures when a vast sea of purple flames came sweeping toward him from all directions.

With no available path for retreat or evasion, Han Li harrumphed coldly, "You've already wasted more than enough of my time!"

Immediately thereafter, he channeled his Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra before thrusting a palm forward, and the space within the array, which had only just regained some connection with the outside world, was instantly turned upside-down by some type of strange force, causing the sea of purple flames to rise upward.

Immediately thereafter, a gargantuan, golden hand appeared up above before sweeping toward Zhu Yan and Zi Shan like the palm of an almighty deity.

At the same time, tremendous power came flooding in from the outside world before surging into the golden hand, and the entire space within the array finally completely collapsed.

Jin Tong reverted back to her human form before flying back to Han Li's side, following which she quickly inspected the surrounding area before remarking, "So we're still in the Extraheavensphere."

Han Li peered into the surrounding spatial rifts as he mused, "No wonder that array was so difficult to break, it combined the power of ten immortal regions!"

He then turned his gaze to Zi Shan's duo in the distance, and Zhu Yan asked in a grim manner, "What do we do now?"

"With the array broken, we're no longer able to stop them," Zi Shan sighed.

"But how do we answer to the supreme lord?" Zhu Yan asked.

"Meng Yuan has already fallen, while Dong Lihu has been severely injured. As for you and I..."

Zi Shan's voice trailed off here.

"What about us?" Zhu Yan hurriedly asked.

"You and I have also suffered severe injuries," Zi Shan replied with a look of resolve in her eyes.

Zhu Yan immediately understood Zi Shan's intentions upon hearing this, and they took a glance in Han Li's direction before flying toward the nearest spatial rift, while Han Li made no effort to stop them.

"What should we do? These spatial rifts won't be around for much longer," Jin Tong asked.

Sure enough, the ten spatial rifts were gradually closing, and several of them had already disappeared.

"Let's get out of here as well."

......

The primordial army had been thrown into a state of disarray by the ferocious assault from the Heavenly Court cultivators, and out of all of the cultivators that had evacuated the Jade Pond Paradise, only several were able to resist the control of the Divine Dao Seal.

True Lord Cang Wu's trio was rooted to the spot as they did everything in their power to resist the effects of the Divine Dao Seal, and at the same time, they couldn't help but be stunned at the scene that was unfolding before them.

With this trick up Gu Huojin's sleeve, the situation had become very murky.

The Heavenly Court Dao Ancestors were ecstatic to see this, while the devilish and primordial Dao Ancestors were naturally far from pleased.

"I didn't know that the Divine Dao Seal could be used in this way, but just this alone is not going to be enough for you to turn the tables," the Reincarnation Palace Master said in a calm manner, then made a hand seal as his glabella began to glow with translucent light.

A translucent chain shot forth before vanishing into the murky, gray space above, while the Devilish Monarch also made a hand seal before releasing a thick beam of silver light into the same expanse of space.

A bolt of gray lightning suddenly flashed through the space there, and that was immediately followed by more flashes of lightning.

In the blink of an eye, several hundred bolts of gray lightning had emerged to form a huge gate.

A hint of alarm flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes upon seeing this, and he immediately threw a punch, sending a mountainous, golden fist projection hurtling toward the gate of gray lightning.

The golden fist projection was giving off an unmatched aura, and even before it had fully descended, its tremendous power was already weighing down upon the Reincarnation Palace Master and the others through the gray lightning gate.

It was as if all of the air in the nearby area had been sucked away, striking the four of them with a sense of asphyxiation.

"You focus on the gate, I'll hold him off for now!" the Devilish Monarch said as he sprang forward while raising a hand, and countless rays of silver light emerged from the space within a radius of several hundred kilometers around him.

The fractured space was instantly mended, and it had become countless times more stable than before.

Furthermore, a burst of profound and potent spatial power was emanating from the silver light, causing everything within a radius of tens of thousands of kilometers to fall completely still, including the golden fist projection.

However, the Reincarnation Palace Master's trio and the space around the gray lightning gate remained completely unaffected.

Chapter 1373: Reinforcements

A hint of relief flashed through the Reincarnation Palace Master's eyes upon seeing this, and he continued to make a rapid string of hand seals.

As more and more gray lightning surged into the gate, it began to glow more and more radiantly, completely outshining everything around it.

At the center of the gate were countless arcs of lightning, which were being manipulated by some type of force to form a swirling vortex, within which a black spatial passageway was quickly taking shape.

Gu Huojin's expression remained unchanged as he casually swept a sleeve through the air, and his eyes suddenly began to glow with golden radiance.

At the same time, a series of strange patterns appeared over the exposed parts of his skin, including his hands, his neck, and his head, and they connected with the patterns on his robes like a system of blood vessels, all of which were also a bright golden color.

What was most peculiar of all was that the same strange patterns had appeared on his wheelchair as well, and waves of golden light were emanating from his body, proliferating outward in all directions before slowly fading away.

In the blink of an eye, countless waves of golden light had spread through the air, all of which were imbued with tremendous time law powers, but in contrast with the time law powers that Gu Huojin had displayed thus far, these time law powers were extremely violent and untamed.

These rays of golden light intertwined with the surrounding silver light, presenting a dazzling sight to behold.

The space that had been frozen by the silver light began to tremble violently in the face of the endless waves of golden light, and finally, it collapsed violently into an almighty spatial storm.

The shattered space was reduced to countless translucent, silver scraps, which were scattered in all directions by the ensuing spatial storms.

The Devilish Monarch wasn't surprised that his spatial seal had been broken, and he thrust a palm forward to release a burst of spatial power, enhancing the power of the raging spatial storms by tenfold.

Countless spatial shards were swept up by the ferocious spatial storm before racing toward the golden fist projection and Gu Huojin, and the fist projection was instantly inundated before exploding violently.

Gu Huojin was caught off guard and sent flying back some distance, but he was able to quickly steady himself, and he remained completely unscathed.

At this point, the Reincarnation Palace Master was already finished with what he was doing, and at this point, the vortex within the gray lightning gate had already swelled to fill up the entirety of the gate.

All of a sudden, all of the gray light faded away at his behest, revealing everything within the gate.

It was a murky, gray world with a white sky that was enshrouded in a vast blanket of gray clouds, beneath which was a black landscape. Everything was black and white, giving the entire world a drab and desolate appearance.

The black landscape was riddled with gray figures stretching as far as the eyes could see, all of whom were Gray Realm cultivators, and their numbers were comparable with those of the devilish and primordial armies.

Judging from their cultivation bases, it was clear that all of the elite cultivators of the Gray Realm had been assembled, and there were even some severed corpse souls among them.

Many of the Heavenly Court's cultivators had turned to these severed corpse souls with alarmed looks on their faces.

The gray clouds were filled with the origin qi of the Gray Realm, which clashed with the world's origin qi to produce a thunderous commotion.

The two types of energy were complete counterparts to one another, and the world's origin qi near the Jade Pond Paradise was rapidly being whittled away.

Right at this moment, three figures emerged from the spatial doorway, the first of which was none other than Yin Chengquan.

As for his two companions, one of them was extremely tall and imposing with pitch-black skin, and he seemed to have come from the Black Rope Region, while the other one's face was completely concealed under the hood of their gray cloak, but a pair of long arms were extending out of the hood.

The arms were covered in brown, wrinkled skin, resembling a dead body that had been submerged in water for many years, presenting a harrowing sight to behold.

Judging from their auras, those two were clearly also Dao Ancestors.

As soon as the three of them appeared, one of them pointed a finger at the Heavenly Court cultivators, and countless Gray Realm cultivators came flooding out of the spatial doorway in a formidable, gray wave to intercept the Heavenly Court's forces.

The origin qi of the Gray Realm naturally suppressed the world's origin qi, so even though the Heavenly Court cultivators possessed a superior cultivation base overall, they were still immediately stopped cold in their tracks.

At the forefront of the Gray Realm amy were dozens of severed corpse souls, who had engaged themselves in battle against several dozen Heavenly Court cultivators.

Many of them had gone after the hosts that had severed them in the first place, and due to how familiar all of them were with one another, they were quite evenly matched, even though the Heavenly Court cultivators had their powers enhanced by the Divine Dao Seal.

As a result, the Heavenly Court army that had appeared unstoppable just a moment ago had been brought to a juddering halt, allowing the devilish and primordial armies to regroup before surrounding the Heavenly Court's forces once again.

With the situation stabilized again, the Devilish Monarch and the others heaved a collective sigh of relief.

As for the Reincarnation Palace Master, he remained completely unmoved by the unfolding situation as he continued to stare intently at Gu Huojin.

All of a sudden, Li Yuanjiu's eyes sprang open, and a burst of golden light surged out of his body to suppress the nine-colored light around him.

Taking advantage of this opportunity, he opened his mouth to release a ball of five-colored light, which contained a small vial that was radiating golden, red, blue, green, and yellow light, identical to the vial that Wyrm 3 and the others had stolen from the Nine Origins Temple.

As soon as the five-colored vial flew out of Li Yuanjiu's mouth, it immediately released a burst of five-colored light that enshrouded his entire body.

The five-colored light contained metal, wood, water, fire, and earth-attribute law powers, but not only were they not clashing against one another, they were fused together in a harmonious fashion, much like the law powers of the Divine Dao Seal.

A burst of tremendous suction force surged out of the vial, and all of the nine-colored light around Li Yuanjiu was sucked into the vial in a flash.

The golden light emanating from his body glowed even brighter, forcing out even more nine-colored light, all of which continued to be sucked into the vial, and after no more than a few seconds, the nine-colored symbol on his glabella had faded away.

Gu Huojin's expression changed slightly upon seeing this, but before he had a chance to contemplate what he had just seen, the three Gray Realm Dao Ancestors appeared near the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch in a flash, and the five of them formed an encirclement around him.

Meanwhile, Li Yuanjiu pointed a finger at Chi Rong, and the five-colored vial above his head immediately flew through the air to settle above her.

With his powers fully restored, Li Yuanjiu was able to make much better use of the vial, and the suction force that it released became far more potent than before as it quickly devoured the Divine Dao Seal that had been placed upon Chi Rong.

With the two of them freed from the Divine Dao Seal, they also joined the encirclement around Gu Huojin.

"I'm very impressed that you were even able to convince these three Gray Realm Dao Ancestors to join you," Gu Huojin chuckled as he turned his gaze to the Reincarnation Palace Master.

"You've left everyone with no choice but to oppose you. You only have yourself to blame for your excessive greed," the Reincarnation Palace Master replied.

His voice wasn't very loud, but it traveled far and wide, and a hesitant look flashed through Chen Ruyan's eyes as she fought against the two devilish Dao Ancestors.

Ripples of blue light were surging out of her fingertips, and they rapidly swelled to form five enormous waves that inundated the entire sky before crashing toward the seductive woman and the giant beast that the rotund woman had transformed into.

The dark purple flowers around the seductive woman were filled with corrosive poison, making them very difficult to deal with, but they had to make direct contact with their target to take effect. In the face of these massive waves, they weren't able to do much aside from sway aimlessly like seaweed.

The seductive woman's expression darkened slightly upon seeing this, and she swept her right hand through the air, upon which a long, purple saber that was riddled with devilish patterns appeared in her grasp.

With a slash of the saber, an almighty saber projection was sent crashing into the fearsome waves.

At the same time, the nine eyes of the giant beast that the rotund woman had transformed into sprang open in unison to release nine pillars of black light, which came together to form a single incredibly thick pillar of black light, within which countless arcs of black lightning were intertwined, and the pillar of light also crashed into the mighty waves.

Two huge gashes were instantly torn into the waves, and the saber projection and pillar of black light were rapidly closing in on Chen Ruyan.

Chapter 1374: The Show is About to Begin

The enormous wave collapsed into a vast wall of water, only to reform a new wave that was even more massive and powerful than its predecessor.

The saber projections and pillars of black light sliced through one wave after another, but these waves were able to recover very quickly and return with even more power than before.

The two devilish Dao Ancestors were relentlessly unleashing attacks, but ultimately, they were overwhelmed by the never-ending barrage of waves, and all of their attacks were quickly inundated and overwhelmed.

After devouring their attacks, the massive waves continued onward, crashing into the two devilish Dao Ancestors to send them flying back with tremendous force.

The two devilish Dao Ancestors quickly steadied themselves, but as they were about to resume their assault, they discovered that Chen Ruyan had already retreated to a considerable distance away.

"The outcome of our battle is hardly of consequence, so why don't we save our energy and wait for the outcome of the battle that truly matters," Chen Ruyan proposed with a faint smile.

"Never!" the seductive woman yelled with intense envy in her eyes, and she raised her purple saber as she prepared to lash out once again.

"This is not an unreasonable proposition from her, Sister He Lan. I also think we should conserve our energy and wait for the outcome of the Devilish Monarch's battle," the rotund woman said as she reverted back to her human form.

He Lan's expression changed slightly upon hearing this, and she reluctantly lowered her saber, but both of them continued to keep a close eye on Chen Ruyan to prevent her from getting away.

A faint smile lingered on Chen Ruyan's face as she stood in silence and cast her gaze in Gu Huojin's direction.

Almost at the exact same moment, Dao Ancestor Yin Ming also suddenly drifted back in retreat as he said, "The show is about to begin over there, fellow daoists. This is certainly not something that happens every day, do you not want to take a look?"

The massive zombie and the yellow-robed man exchanged a glance with one another, and neither of them said anything, but they didn't unleash any further attacks, either.

In contrast, the battle that was raging between Bai Ze's trio and the three Heavenly Court Dao Ancestors was only becoming more and more fierce by the second.

Dao Ancestor Bai Yun's trio was very alarmed to see the formidable encirclement that had taken shape around Gu Huojin, and they were frantically trying to disengage themselves from their battle against Bai Ze's trio to rush to Gu Huojin's aid, but the three primordial Dao Ancestors naturally wasn't going to allow that to happen.

At this point, all three of them had already adopted their true forms.

Bai Ze had transformed into a majestic, white, horse-like beast with a pair of horns on his head and a goatee under his chin, and almighty white storms were surging out of his mouth.

Yue Mian had transformed into the Sky Roaming Kun Peng, and there were countless arcs of lightning flashing over his body.

As for the bald man, he had transformed into a mountainous, black, fish-like beast that completely dwarfed even Bai Ze and Yue Mian's true forms.

The black beast was very hideous in appearance, and its most noteworthy feature was its mouth, which was enormous and took up virtually half of its entire head.

Within the cavernous mouth was a boundless expanse of inky darkness that was giving off tremendous suction force, looking as if it were the entrance to another world.

Anything that drifted too close to the almighty beast was instantly sucked into its mouth, and even the nearby space was being devoured.

The six of them were all Dao Ancestors, and they were quite evenly matched when it came to law powers, but Bai Ze's trio were all true spirits with tremendous physical constitutions, so they were able to withstand the frantic attacks from Dao Ancestor Bai Yun's trio without backing down in the slightest.

"You wish to kill me, is that right?" Gu Huojin asked in a casual manner, seemingly completely unconcerned by the predicament that he had found himself in.

"You only have yourself to blame for your greed," the Devilish Monarch said in a cold voice.

"Greed? I only wanted to see exactly what lied at the end of this world. Have none of you ever considered pursuing the same objective?" Gu Huojin asked as he secretly crushed a ring that he was wearing on one of his fingers.

"Don't give him time to use any of his tricks!" the Reincarnation Palace Master yelled, seemingly having detected something, and he thrust a palm toward Gu Huojin.

A dark red ghostly deity that was clad in a suit of bone armor instantly appeared, and bursts of reincarnation law powers were circling around it, producing a loud rumbling sound.

The ghostly deity thrust its palm forward, and lashing out at Gu Huojin's head, and the Devilish Monarch and the others also sprang into action upon seeing this, with all of them unleashing their most powerful attacks from the get-go.

The space within a radius of thousands of kilometers was shattered violently as radiant, golden light, near-transparent flames of hell, insubstantial black shadows, and dazzling starlight filled the entire area.

Everyone in the Jade Pond Paradise, including the devilish and primordial armies, had already fled to thousands of kilometers away in a panic, but some were not able to get away in time and had been erased from existence.

After evacuating to a safe distance away, everyone turned back to stare from afar, not daring to get any closer.

The ultimate showdown had finally begun. As the Time Dao Ancestor and the leader of the Seven Heavenly Dao Lords, Gu Huojin had stood at the pinnacle of the laws of time for countless years, and his power was unmatched.

Among the seven assailants that he had been surrounded by, the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch were the foremost masters of the other two paramount laws, and they weren't as formidable as Gu Huojin, but they could compete with him in terms of their caliber of their law powers.

As for the remaining five, they were also certainly not to be scoffed at, and even though their law powers couldn't contend with Gu Huojin's time law powers, with the laws of reincarnation and space on their side, they most definitely stood a fighting chance.

Everyone was looking on with bated breath, waiting to see which side would come out on top.

All of the space around Gu Huojin instantly collapsed violently, and it was as if the entire sky were about to fall upon him.

A serious look finally appeared on his face as he made a hand seal, and the patterns all over his body and his wheelchair began to glow with golden radiance before transforming into a suit of golden armor, the breastplate of which featured a massive dragon design.

The dragon design was formed by countless scales, and plumes of golden flames were erupting out of its mouth.

The attacks from the Reincarnation Palace Master and the others descended upon him as soon as the suit of golden armor took shape, and seven bursts of indescribably formidable law powers clashed against the time law powers around him.

The seven bursts of law powers fell stagnant for just a split second upon coming into contact with Gu Huojin's law powers, but it was precisely in this split second window that Gu Huojin abruptly launched himself upward as a streak of golden light.

The streak of golden light tore through the restrictive cocoon formed by the seven bursts of law powers, but Gu Huojin's suit of golden armor was also destroyed in the process.

Hovering high up in the sky, a vast expanse of golden light began to emanate from Gu Huojin's body, and in the blink of an eye, the suit of golden armor returned, as if it had never sustained any damage in the first place.

"Gu Huojin is able to reverse time, so normal attacks won't be able to inflict lasting damage upon him," the Reincarnation Palace Master said.

"That is indeed a troublesome ability, but how many times can he unleash it in his current state?" the Devilish Monarch sneered, and as soon as his voice trailed off, the space around Gu Huojin suddenly began to glow a bright silver, and he was abruptly rooted to the spot.

"This is our chance! I've frozen the space around him!" the Devilish Monarch yelled, and his six comrades instantly sprang into action as five spirit domains appeared around Gu Huojin one on top of the other, exerting an even more potent restrictive force upon him.

However, the Reincarnation Palace Master hadn't made a move, and a perplexed look had appeared on his face.

"All of your efforts are futile," Gu Huojin said with a faint smile, and countless rays of golden light erupted out of his suit of armor, slicing into the frozen space around him.

The nearby space and the restrictive forces acting upon him from the opposing spirit domains were all eradicated, and after freeing himself, Gu Huojin swung around like lightning before making a grabbing motion toward his seven assailants.

A mountainous, golden fist projection appeared out of thin air, and this one was far more formidable than any fist projection that he had previously unleashed.

"He's using that same attack again! Gu Huojin can't be far away from being assimilated by the Heavenly Dao at this point, so all we have to do is wear him down until the Heavenly Dao claims him!" the Devilish Monarch said in a cold voice.

"This is an opportunity that won't come around again, so we have to take full advantage," Yin Chengquan urged.

Meanwhile, the Reincarnation Palace Master was only growing more perplexed.

What is he up to? It feels like he's been stalling this entire time...

Despite his reservations, the Reincarnation Palace Master still combined his powers with his six comrades to eradicate the golden fist projection, following which all seven of them rushed toward Gu Huojin in unison.

Chapter 1375: The End of the Heavenly Dao

Seven bursts of peerless law powers surged toward Gu Huojin from all directions, but he wasn’t fazed at all.

Right as the seven bursts of law powers were about to inundate him, a vast expanse of golden light erupted out of his body once again, and in the next instant, he appeared thousands of kilometers away, completely unscathed.

However, he had only just steadied himself when a gargantuan, dark red palm projection appeared up above before swooping down upon him, staining the entire space down below a dark red color.

An enormous, hexagonal plate projection appeared beneath the gargantuan hand, and it was rapidly revolving while releasing bursts of invisible power.

The space around Gu Huojin instantly became warped and twisted as countless spatial vortexes of different sizes took shape around him.

Bursts of radiant light were spilling out of all of the vortexes, with figures rapidly flashing in and out of sight, and they were all giving off indescribably vast aura.

Gu Huojin made no effort to take evasive measures as he conjured up a small area of golden light around himself to keep the vortexes at bay. However, the number of vortexes continued to increase, twisting and warping the golden space, and it soon became impossible to see what was happening inside.

The Reincarnation Palace Master appeared above the giant palm projection, and at this moment, he was looking noticeably more emaciated.

His hands and face were covered in striking, dark red patterns, and there was a grim look on his sunken face as he said, "I've trapped Gu Huojin for now, this is the time to make a final push, everyone!"

As soon as his voice trailed off, six figures sped toward Gu Huojin from different directions, bringing with them six bursts of devastating law powers.

Tens of thousands of kilometers away, all of the bystanders were spectating the battle with their spiritual sense, and they were completely astonished by what they were witnessing.

This was a battle between the most powerful cultivators under the heavens, and it was incredible to think that it was possible for one to attain such immense power.

It seemed that Gu Huojin had found himself in dire straits.

"No matter how powerful he is, he's still only just one man. The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch's law powers can stand toe to toe with his, and with the other five Dao Ancestors also thrown into the mix, this is most likely going to be the end of him..."

"Who could've imagined that the Bodhi Banquet would end up like this?"

......

Gu Huojin paid no heed to the surrounding dark red vortexes and the six figures racing toward him as he raised his head slightly and murmured to himself, "Finally..."

At the same time, the golden palace deep within the Heavenly Court where Gu Huojin had previously been cultivating in seclusion suddenly trembled violently before exploding to release countless balls of light of different colors.

All of a sudden, it was as if countless rainbows had appeared over the murky, gray sky, presenting a stunning sight to behold.

At first glance, it appeared that these lights were scattered in a completely haphazard fashion, but in reality, there was method to the madness, and they intertwined with one another to form what appeared to have been a giant go board over the Heavenly Court.

These lights extended into the distance as far as the eyes could see, and all of them were giving off different types of law powers.

All of a sudden, the three Gray Realm Dao Ancestors were brought to a juddering halt as they charged toward Gu Huojin, and three streaks of light, two black and one gray, emerged from their bodies before rising up to the heavens.

All of this had taken place in the blink of an eye, and everything was enshrouded under a burst of pressure that was loftier than the heavens and heavier than the earth.

It was as if the full might of heaven and earth had descended, and even the power of Dao Ancestors paled into insignificance in comparison.

The nearby space constricted, and everyone present was instantly immobilized.

On top of that, the law powers in their bodies had begun fluctuating in an uncontrolled fashion, as if they were resonating with the lights in the sky.

The Reincarnation Palace Master was no exception to this, and even with his unfathomable powers, he had been rendered completely immobile.

The gargantuan palm projections exploded along with the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate, and all of the countless reincarnation vortexes around Gu Huojin also faded away.

Just like the Reincarnation Palace Master, the Devilish Monarch and all of the other Dao Ancestors present had also been completely immobilized, including even the Dao Ancestors of the Heavenly Court.

Regardless of how vigorously everyone struggled against their restraints, there was simply no opposing the restrictive forces acting upon them.

"Finally... I've been waiting for this day for far too long..." Gu Huojin sighed.

"You've already collected all of the law powers required to complete the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array?" the Reincarnation Palace Master asked.

"Looks like you only have a very rudimentary understanding of the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array. In order to activate the array, I don't necessarily have to collect all of the law powers. Instead, as long as I have over half of the law powers and the thirty-six law powers that serve as the core of the array, then that is already enough," Gu Huojin explained.

"So this was your plan all along? To lure me here along with all of the cultivators of the Devil Realm and the primordial land?" the Reincarnation Palace Master asked.

"This was indeed my plan, but the main objective wasn't to lure you in. Instead, my main focus was on those three," Gu Huojin replied as he cast his gaze toward Yin Chengquan's trio.

A look of alarm and realization appeared on the Reincarnation Palace Master's face upon hearing this.

"The aforementioned thirty-six law powers are very difficult to assemble, particularly because several of them can only be found in the Gray Realm. I've been constantly sending people into the Gray Realm over the years, but I've only managed to collect two of them, while the remaining three all belonged to Dao Ancestors.

“Hence, I had no choice but to devise this plot to use your invasion of the Heavenly Court to my advantage. Without those three, I would've never been able to complete my array," Gu Huojin revealed.

"So everything that I've worked for was all to bring your plan into fruition. You truly are an impressive man, Fellow Daoist Gu," the Reincarnation Palace Master said with a defeated smile.

"You are the only one in this world worthy of hearing this explanation from me, but unfortunately, you won't get to see me create the true Heavenly Dao," Gu Huojin said with a faint smile, then thrust a palm forward, and golden arm emerged from each of the chests of the Reincarnation Palace Master, the Devilish Monarch, and the three Gray Realm Dao Ancestors, piercing through their bodies.

A plume of golden mist then rose up from the arms to envelop their bodies, and they were instantly reduced to withered corpses.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch's bodies disintegrated into dust, while the bodies of the three Gray Realm Dao Ancestors had transformed into three balls of light, one gray and two black.

"Palace Master!"

"Devilish Monarch!"

Looks of despair appeared in the eyes of all of the devilish and primordial cultivators present, while Gu Huojin made a hand seal in an expressionless manner, and the three balls of light formed by the three Gray Realm Dao Ancestors rose up into the air before fusing into the giant go board above.

Three bursts of light, two black and one gray, appeared in the heavens, and countless runes began surging out of the giant go board, encompassing the entire sky.

The pressure weighing down from above instantly increased significantly, while the unrest in the law powers in everyone's bodies was also exacerbated.

Cries of agony rang out as rays of light began flowing out of the trembling bodies of the cultivators down below and rising up into the sky.

These rays of light contained both their law powers and their immortal spiritual power, both of which were being sucked away by the array in the heavens.

On top of that, all of the cultivators of the Devil Realm, the primordial land, the Gray Realm, and the Heavenly Court were also having their powers devoured by the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array, including the likes of Dao Ancestor Bai Yun.

The only one present who remained unaffected by the array was Gu Huojin.

"What are you doing, Supreme Lord? Did you not promise to take the three of us above the Heavenly Dao with you? Why are you taking our law powers?" Dao Ancestor Bai Yun asked in a frantic voice as he turned to Gu Huojin with a panicked expression.

"The activation of the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array marks the end of this world and the beginning of a new one. Everything that belongs to this world will be erased, and I have no say in the matter. Hence, the three of you will have to sacrifice yourselves for the true Heavenly Dao," Gu Huojin said in an indifferent manner, and the complexions of the three Dao Ancestors instantly turned deathly pale upon hearing this.

Gu Huojin paid no heed to them as he rose up into the air, and a fervent look appeared in his eyes as he declared, "You are all witnessing the most monumental moment in the history of this world! All of you are too narrow of mind and too short of sight to see my vision! I am going to create a new world where the strong will no longer have to be subjected to the oppression of the Heavenly Dao!"

As soon as his voice trailed off, he rose up even higher, resembling a dazzling, golden sun that was ascending to the peak of the heavens.

From there, he pressed a finger against his own glabella, and a corkscrew-shaped rune surfaced over his skin, giving off a bright red glow like the light of a dying flame.

Chapter 1376: Final Chance

Gu Huojin began to chant a complex incantation, and layers of golden ripples surged out of his body like waves crashing against the shore.

Nothing was able to obstruct these golden ripples, whether it be space or tangible objects, and they quickly spread out of the Middle Earth Immortal Region entirely.

At this moment, the four heavenly gates of the Middle Earth Immortal Region resembled massive horns, amplifying the golden ripples before transmitting them across the entire True Immortal Realm.

All of the immortal regions under the heavens were basked in the golden ripples at once, and ordinary mortals and average cultivators were completely oblivious to this. Even True Immortals and Golden Immortals only had a vague sense of what was happening, while only those at or above the High Zenith Stage were able to detect the changes taking place in heaven and earth.

However, even if they noticed the changes, there wasn't anything that they could do.

Specks of light lit up all over the giant go-board-like array in the heavens at Gu Huojin's behest, and it was giving off indescribable law power fluctuations.

"This marks the beginning of the new world. All of you are very fortunate to be able to witness this," he said with a smile, and as soon as his voice trailed off, the entire array began to glow with blinding radiance.

Immediately thereafter, it transformed into a series of massive pillars of light that erupted into the heavens, tearing through the Astralsphere, the Ethersphere, and the Extraheavensphere to reach even further beyond.

Meanwhile, the sub-venue on the Eastern Victory Continent had descended into a state of complete chaos. Daoist Master Qing Qiu naturally had a clearer sense of the disturbance in the air than everyone else, and he turned to discover that a giant pillar of golden light had erupted into the heavens from his daoist temple, and its origin was none other than the nondescript Heaven Guard Pavilion.

At this moment, the entire pavilion was enshrouded in golden light, and its base, which was no more than two hundred feet in size, was connected to an enormous array that spanned tens of thousands of kilometers in radius, and runes of all types of different colors were rising up into the heavens from the array incessantly.

The same phenomenon was also taking place in the Heaven Guard Pavilions on the other three continents as well, and the battles taking place there instantly drew to a halt.

A sense of indescribable panic welled up in everyone's hearts as they sensed the waves of all-encompassing power sweeping over the landscape.

Daoist Master Qing Qiu had been stationed in that Heaven Guard Pavilion for no fewer than thirty million years, and even though he was rather lackadaisical and hadn't ever carefully examined the pavilion, it was still astonishing that a Dao Ancestor like him had failed to detect such a powerful array lurking beneath it this entire time.

What was even more alarming was that the law powers in his body were beginning to seep out as translucent threads before flying toward the enormous pillar of light in the distance.

He looked around in bewilderment to discover that the same thing was happening to everyone around him, and as more and more translucent law threads rose up into the sky, then began to intertwine with one another to form a huge, colorful net up above.

Someone finally realized that everyone present had been reduced to lambs for the slaughter, and he yelled, "Run!"

......

Everyone, regardless of which powers they were affiliated with, set aside their differences to flee the scene, and many of them were making a mad dash for the teleportation arrays in the eastern heavenly gate in an attempt to leave the Middle Earth Immortal Region altogether.

However, upon reaching the teleportation arrays, they discovered that the energy fluctuations released by the pillar of light had already completely disrupted all of the law powers on this continent, including the laws of space, rendering the teleportation arrays completely useless.

In light of this, everyone turned and fled toward the eastern heavenly gate, and they were desperate to escape this place as quickly as possible. Otherwise, as more and more of their law powers were leached from their bodies, it would eventually become impossible for them to get away.

"What exactly are you trying to do, Supreme Lord?" Daoist Master Qing Qiu murmured to himself as he cast his gaze toward the Heavenly Palace Immortal Region.

After a brief pause, he sighed, "Regardless of what you're plotting, I wish to play no further part in all of this..."

He then turned and flew out of the eastern heavenly gate as a streak of white light without so much as even a backward glance.

However, right at this moment, the heavenly gate suddenly shuddered violently, and the paint on its pillars and the archway at the center peeled away to reveal the engraved runes underneath.

Those runes lit up with piercing, golden radiance while giving off bursts of peculiar energy fluctuations, and the cultivators that had just rushed into the gate didn't even have a chance to register what was happening before they were devoured by a giant vortex that had abruptly appeared out of thin air, instantly reducing their bodies to dust.

Immediately thereafter, a huge pillar of golden light erupted out of the vortex, and Daoist Master Qing Qiu instantly felt a burst of tremendous suction force begin to act upon him from behind.

He frantically redoubled his efforts to get away, but the translucent law threads flowing out of his body were sucked in by the pillar of light, forcibly dragging him back into the vortex in the heavenly gate.

With even a Dao Ancestor like him unable to escape the vortex's clutches, everyone else naturally wasn't able to fare any better, and the same thing was happening in all four heavenly gates.

The entire Middle Earth Immortal Region had transformed into a slaughterhouse, and no one that possessed law powers of any attribute was able to get away.

......

Heavenly Palace Continent.

All of the clouds in the sky above the Jade Pond Paradise had evaporated as if they had been scorched away, revealing an inky black extrarealm space up above.

Within this space was a chaotic vortex that was gradually expanding, and Gu Huojin was standing beneath the vortex, observing the entire Middle Earth Immortal Region with a look of excitement in his eyes.

Compared with the sub-venues, the situation in the Jade Pond Paradise was even more horrific, with countless law threads rising up toward the vortex high up in the sky.

Over half of the cultivators present had already perished in battle, and around half of those that were left had met their demise after having the law powers sucked out of their bodies.

A pleased look finally appeared in Gu Huojin's eyes upon seeing this.

With more and more law powers flowing into the array, it would be enhanced further and further, and before long, the entire True Immortal Realm would succumb to its power.

In order to change the world, one had to possess the power and resolve to destroy it first.

Right at this moment, he suddenly raised an eyebrow as something caught his attention.

It was Li Yuanjiu with his palms raised to the heavens, and golden light was flowing incessantly out of his hands into a palm-sized vial hovering above his head.

Golden, red, blue, green, and yellow light were surging out of the mouth of the vial, forming a five-colored umbrella of light that encompassed an area with a radius of roughly a thousand feet around him.

Under the protection of the umbrella, he was able to remain completely unaffected by the array.

There were around a dozen more figures standing behind him, also taking shelter under the five-colored umbrella, two of whom were Meng Po and Yu Menghan.

The two of them had refrained from consuming their Bodhi Dao Fruits, so they didn't fall under the control of the Divine Dao Seal and were able to get far away from the battlefield. However, in the wake of the array's activation, they knew that they wouldn't be able to get away, so they could only seek out Li Yuanjiu's protection.

Li Yuanjiu initially didn't want to protect them, but with everyone else dead or on death's doorstep, he had to muster up what few allies he could to oppose Gu Huojin.

As was the case with Chi Rong, Chen Ruyan had also had the power of the Divine Dao Seal sucked out of her body by the small vial, and the three of them had temporarily forged an alliance.

"Li Yuanjiu, you were the latest addition to the Seven Heavenly Dao Ancestors, and you were the least loyal to me, but you were smarter than all of the rest. Unfortunately, your power is required to completely activate this array, so I'll have to ask you to surrender yourself over to me," Gu Huojin said.

"Gu Huojin, I knew you were plotting something insidious, but I didn't think you would go this far... If you want my power, then you'll have to come and take it yourself!" Li Yuanjiu spat through gritted teeth.

A faint smile appeared on Gu Huojin's face, and he wasted no time with words as he pointed a finger at the swirling vortex up above.

A burst of thunderous rumbling rang out within the chaotic vortex, following which a beam of gray light shot out from within to strike the five-colored umbrella above Li Yuanjiu.

The five-colored light barrier shuddered violently, then began to rapidly fade.

"If you don't want to die, then help me power this vial!" Li Yuanjiu hurriedly urged upon seeing this, and everyone under the umbrella of five-colored light immediately began injecting their power into the vial.

At the moment, the dozen or so figures under the umbrella of five-colored light included six Dao Ancestors, namely Li Yuanjiu, Chi Rong, Chen Ruyan, and True Lord Cang Wu's trio, so their collective power was certainly nothing to be scoffed at.

There were many cultivators nearby who still hadn't had all of the law powers drained from their bodies yet, and they were forced to set aside their differences as they trudged arduously toward Li Yuanjiu.

With the inclusion of more and more people, the five-colored light barrier was bolstered to the extent that it was able to temporarily ward off the beam of gray light.

Chapter 1377: The Unpredictability of the Heavenly Dao

Gu Huojin merely shook his head with a faint smile upon seeing this, then raised his hands to the heavens, and two waves of golden light surged out of the palms of his hands toward the sky.

With the injection of golden light, the beam of gray light released by the chaotic vortex became even more formidable, and the five-colored light barrier was completely overwhelmed as it began to steadily shrink.

Everyone was forced to huddle up closer and closer to one another, but that was only going to delay the inevitable.

Li Yuanjiu heaved a forlorn sigh. Ultimately, all of his efforts had proven to be for nought.

Right at this moment, the space behind Gu Huojin suddenly began to ripple, and a massive, silver rune emerged, immediately following which a gate of silver light abruptly appeared.

Gu Huojin's brows furrowed slightly upon sensing this, and he withdrew a hand before thrusting his palm behind himself, sending nine radiant, golden wyrms racing toward the silver gate.

A burst of dark red light erupted out of the silver gate to clash against the nine golden wyrms, and a resounding boom rang out as the gate exploded, leaving behind a huge black hole that lingered in the air.

At the same time, two figures abruptly emerged, one behind Gu Huojin and one in front of him, both of which lashed out at him in unison.

Unable to take evasive measures, Gu Huojin conjured up a layer of golden light over his own body to withstand the attacks, and the golden light erupted outward in all directions with tremendous power, forcing back his two assailants to hundreds of thousands of kilometers away.

As golden light faded away, it was revealed that a trail of blood had trickled down from the corner of Gu Huojin's lips, and for the first time in this entire battle, he had been injured.

He continued to power the array with one hand while wiping the blood from his lips with the other as he mused, "So the two of you were alive all along..."

The pressure on Li Yuanjiu and the others was instantly significantly lessened, and they hurriedly turned to see who it was that had entered the fray.

To their astonishment, the two new arrivals were none other than the Devilish Monarch and the Reincarnation Palace Master, who were supposed to have already perished by Gu Huojin's hands.

Each of them had a layer of light enveloping their bodies, warding off the effects of the array to prevent any loss of law powers.

"You don't seem surprised by our return," the Reincarnation Palace Master remarked as he raised an eyebrow.

"There are three paramount laws in this world. Neither of you have reached the pinnacle of your respective laws, but you are still the two closest to me in power in this world, so I would've been sorely disappointed if it had been so easy to dispose of you. However, I must say that you used some very impressive decoys to fool me," Gu Huojin said with a composed smile.

"I have a brother by the name of Shi Kongjie, and he stands at the pinnacle of the laws of puppetry. He integrated our law powers into a pair of puppets, to create the perfect decoys, so it's no surprise that you were fooled," the Devilish Monarch explained.

"I see. I had always thought that you two were at each other's throats and that you had already killed him, but it seems like I fell for nothing more than an act," Gu Huojin said with an enlightened expression.

......

In the Devil Realm, most of the once majestic Night Sun City laid in ruins.

The war between Daoist Xie and the Devilish Monarch's forces had been an extremely brutal one, and no one that had witnessed the war would've thought that it was an act.

In reality, in the beginning, it hadn't been an act. The two sides had truly been trying to eradicate one another in earnest, and it was only the arrival of one man bearing a piece of astonishing news that put an end to the war.

That man was naturally none other than the Reincarnation Palace Master, and he had informed the two brothers of Gu Huojin's secret plot.

At this moment, Daoist Xie was seated on a cushion in a secret chamber, and he was looking very much worse for wear.

What was most astonishing of all was that the left side of his body, from his shoulder to his lower abdomen, was nowhere to be seen, clearly a result of assimilation from the Heavenly Dao from excessive usage of his puppetry law powers.

Shi Chuankong was standing nearby with a concerned look on his face.

He had been present while Daoist Xie had created those two puppets using the law powers of the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch, and at the time, he had also suffered from the effects of assimilation, but to nowhere near this severe an extent.

Not long ago, Daoist Xie had been meditating when he suddenly sustained severe injuries, and as a result, the effects of assimilation had been significantly exacerbated.

A short while later, Daoist Xie exhaled as he opened his eyes, and Shi Chuankong immediately approached him with a concerned gaze.

"There's no need to worry about me, I've only suffered some backlash from the destruction of my puppets," Daoist Xie reassured.

"How are things going over there, Uncle?" Shi Chuankong asked.

"It's... difficult to say," Daoist Xie replied with a shake of his head.

Right at this moment, a burst of peculiar energy fluctuations suddenly swept through the air, and their law powers began to seep out of their bodies in the form of translucent threads.

"What's going on?" Shi Chuankong exclaimed in an alarmed manner.

"Gu Huojin has activated the array. Things must've taken a turn for the worse..." Daoist Xie replied in a grim manner.

......

In the Extraheavensphere.

Han Li and Jin Tong were racing through the boundless expanse of darkness.

They had originally planned to enter an immortal region through one of the spatial rifts before traveling to the Middle Earth Immortal Region via teleportation array, but they had discovered that all of the teleportation arrays leading to the Middle Earth Immortal Region had become dysfunctional for some reason.

Hence, they had no choice but to travel toward the Middle Earth Immortal Region through the Extraheavensphere.

Right at this moment, their law powers began to flow out of their bodies before vanishing into thin air.

"What's going on?" Jin Tong exclaimed as she hurriedly stopped cold in her tracks.

"I don't know, but something must've happened in the Heavenly Court," Han Li replied with a grim expression, then attempted to seal in his own law powers with his immortal spiritual power, but his efforts proved to be futile.

"What do we do? At this rate, we'll run out of law powers before we even get to the Heavenly Court!" Jin Tong exclaimed.

As soon as her voice trailed off, a burst of green light suddenly appeared over Han Li's chest.

The green light was emanating from none other than the Heaven Controlling Vial, and he hurriedly pulled it out from beneath his robe.

The green light emanating from the vial enveloped Han Li's entire body, and the outflow of law powers instantly ceased.

Han Li immediately extended a hand toward Jin Tong upon seeing this, releasing a burst of light in her direction to forge a connection between the two, and the law powers in her body were also sealed in again.

"Looks like the Heaven Controlling Vial can keep us safe, but I don't know if the effects are permanent, so we have to get to the Heavenly Court as soon as possible," Han Li said with a grim expression.

Jin Tong nodded in response, and the two of them continued on their way.

......

Middle Earth Immortal Region, Heavenly Prayer Continent.

The Rising Dragon Peak of the Heavenmend Sect was still as peaceful as ever, but for some reason, all of the peach trees on the mountain summit had been stripped of their flowers and leaves, as if they had been ravaged by a storm.

Without the cover provided by the canopies of the peach trees, the entire mountain summit was made to appear very bare and exposed, and the octagonal stone altar was fully revealed.

All that remained of Chen Tuan was half of his face, while the rest of his body had already been claimed by the black vortex hovering over the altar.

His lone, blind eye peered arduously into the distance before looking up at the heavens, and there was a concerned and hesitant look on his face.

"So be it. I've clung onto this pathetic existence of so many years, and now, all that's left for me is one final, half-divination. As for whether this half-divination will be able to yield an outcome, that'll be up to the heavens," he murmured to himself with a wry smile.

He didn't want to know the outcome of the Bodhi Banquet anymore. Instead, the only thing that he was curious about now was Gu Huojin's fate.

He began to chant an incantation, and a film of blood suddenly appeared over his blind eye, following which it disintegrated into a streak of translucent, crimson light that vanished into the space ahead of him.

The space there warped and collapsed to form a black vortex, which sucked in the streak of crimson light to form a crimson bridge between Chen Tuan and the vortex.

However, he was already a spent force, and the bridge was only able to remain intact for less than twenty seconds before crumbling away.

The black vortex flew toward Chen Tuan, then fused with the existing black vortex behind him to slowly devour what little remained of his body.

"How surprising..."

Those were Chen Tuan's final words.

All of a sudden, all of the peach trees on the entire Rising Dragon Peak erupted into flames, sending large columns of black smoke rising up into the sky.

Chapter 1378: Chaos

Jade Pond Paradise.

The Devilish Monarch was hovering in mid-air with his hands clasped together in a seal, and spatial law powers were surging out of his body, while eighty-one black spikes were hovering before him, giving off a faint glow.

All of a sudden, he thrust his palms forward, and the eighty-one black spikes instantly shot forward before vanishing into the space up ahead.

In the next instant, a burst of thunderous rumbling rang out, and all of the black spikes had transformed into massive pillars around the chaotic vortex, forming a spatial array that sealed the vortex at its center.

A clear layer of spatial cracks appeared around the array, as if someone had forcibly dug out that expanse of space and severed its connection with the rest of the world to form an independent space.

This was similar to how the Devil Realm had been created, but at the time, the power of the entire devil race had been called upon to achieve that monumental feat.

Even though this was an array that had been created using the Devilish Monarch's power alone, the space that was isolated was far smaller than the Devil Realm, so his individual power was sufficient.

Gu Huojin immediately realized what the Devilish Monarch's intentions were, and he sneered, "You have the right idea, trying to isolate me and the array from the rest of the world, but it's not going to work this time."

He spread a hand open as he spoke to reveal an ancient rune on the palm, following which he pointed a finger at one of the eighty-one pillars around him.

A pillar of radiant, golden light erupted out of the rune, reaching the pillar that it was aimed at in the blink of an eye.

However, before the pillar of golden light was able to strike its target, the Reincarnation Palace Master abruptly appeared in its path, then raised a hand to conjure up a ring-shaped, dark red light barrier.

There were six balls of light of different colors lodged in the light barrier, with a different rune at the center of each one.

The pillar of golden light struck the ring-shaped light barrier, causing it to tremble violently, and its power was absorbed by the ring before being converted into a burst of gentle light, which traveled through the six balls of light in succession before fading away.

The Reincarnation Palace Master pressed a hand against the circular light barrier, and wisps of law powers surged out of his body before flowing into the light barrier.

The runes within the six balls of light on the light barrier were illuminated one after another, and the entire light barrier instantly swelled to over a hundred times its original size, while a massive ball of dark red light appeared at its center before hurtling directly toward Gu Huojin.

The ball of light was enshrouded in crimson mist and contained the reincarnation karmic power that the Reincarnation Palace Master had been accumulating over the course of millions of years, and right as it was about to descend upon Gu Huojin, it abruptly exploded into a wave of crimson mist that swept toward him like an avalanche.

Gu Huojin was already prepared for this, and he conjured up a time barrier that stopped everything that came into contact with it cold in their tracks.

However, the crimson mist was able to pass straight through the golden light barrier without any impediment.

A hint of surprise flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes upon seeing this, and he hurriedly swept a sleeve through the air, sweeping up a fierce gust of wind to scatter the crimson mist, only for it to converge into a single stream that shot up his sleeve like an arrow.

In the blink of an eye, his entire body was enshrouded in crimson mist, and his entire body instantly fell stagnant, leaving him unable to even keep his arm aloft to power the array.

"What have you done?" Gu Huojin asked.

"Reincarnation and karma transcend beyond time, so your time law powers can't protect you. I've simply gathered all of the bad karma that the Heavenly Court has created under your command and returned it to you," the Reincarnation Palace Master explained with a smile.

"You think this will be enough to bring me down? Isn't that a little too naive of you?" Gu Huojin sneered.

Rays of golden light appeared over his body as he spoke, and it was as if he were bathed in the river of time, which slowly washed the karma away.

However, not only was the Reincarnation Palace Master not dismayed in the slightest to see this, a faint smile had appeared on his face instead.

At the same time, he quickly made a string of hand seals, and an array began to take shape beneath Gu Huojin.

The Devilish Monarch had also sprung into action at the same time, and eighty-one translucent chains of black light shot out of the eighty-one pillars before winding themselves tightly around Gu Huojin.

The space around Gu Huojin was instantly sealed, causing the flow of the river of time around him to cease.

"Go!" the Devilish Monarch yelled, and Yin Ming abruptly emerged out of thin air behind Gu Huojin, following which his body abruptly elongated to several hundred feet in length before coiling itself around Gu Huojin like a constricting python.

"I'll be taking your soul, Supreme Lord!" Yin Ming cackled with his shadowy face no more than three feet away from Gu Huojin's.

After Gu Huojin's plot was exposed, he had agreed to the Reincarnation Palace Master's alliance proposition without any hesitation. According to their plan, the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch would be responsible for trapping Gu Huojin, at which point he would swoop in to devour Gu Huojin's soul.

Even he couldn't imagine how powerful he would become if he could successfully devour Gu Huojin's soul. He would definitely be able to put an end to Gu Huojin's plans, and perhaps he could even eradicate the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch at once.

A hint of irrepressible excitement welled up in his heart at the thought of destroying the trio that stood at the pinnacle of the three paramount laws, and he reared up before plunging head-first toward Gu Huojin's glabella.

If he could enter Gu Huojin's consciousness, then his victory would be sealed.

Right at this moment, what sounded like a gong strike suddenly rang out from Gu Huojin's glabella, and waves of golden ripples surged out of his consciousness before sweeping over Yin Ming, whose essential energy was instantly set alight.

"No! This is impossible!" he exclaimed in a panic as he attempted to distance himself from Gu Huojin, only for a hand to close itself around his throat.

"On the path of exploring the Great Dao, I have walked further than all of you combined, so you really shouldn't be underestimating me like this," Gu Huojin said, following which a burst of completely unprecedented time law powers erupted out of his hand to erase Yin Ming from existence in the blink of an eye.

At the same time, the layer of crimson mist clinging to his body also peeled away like old paint before dissipating into nothingness.

The Reincarnation Palace Master sliced a gash into the palm of his own hand upon seeing this, releasing a drop of blood essence that flowed down onto the space before him.

The array beneath Gu Huojin instantly began to glow brightly, and what appeared to have been an entrance to the underworld had opened up, revealing a crimson space, from within which a harrowing cacophony of heart-wrenching howls could be heard.

There were also countless crimson figures crawling toward the opening in hordes, but they were unable to crawl out of the underworld even as they desperately clawed and clambered over one another.

A burst of tremendous suction force was surging out of the opening, attempting to suck Gu Huojin in.

However, he remained completely unfazed, and a corkscrew-shaped pillar of gray light descended from the chaotic vortex overhead before plunging into the opening, and the crimson space within was instantly thrown into a state of disarray.

Countless crimson figures were completely obliterated before they even had a chance to react, and the remnants of their bodies rose up with the corkscrew-shaped pillar of gray light to be sucked into the chaotic vortex, causing it to swell drastically in size once again.

The Reincarnation Palace Master's expression darkened slightly upon seeing this, and he switched to a different hand seal, upon which the array beneath Gu Huojin slowly faded away along with the crimson opening.

The Devilish Monarch and the Reincarnation Palace Master exchanged a concerned glance with one another, and a faint smile appeared on Gu Huojin's face upon seeing this as he remarked, "It seems like you're finally beginning to understand the hopeless situation that you're in."

With a casual sweep of his hand, all of the translucent chains around him dissipated into nothingness.

"The chaotic law powers within this array are what has created this world, and they're far more ancient than the three paramount laws. Even the Heavenly Dao itself was born from chaos, so what makes you think that you can contain it with your spatial law powers?" Gu Huojin scoffed, and a grim look appeared on the Devilish Monarch's face upon hearing this.

In the next instant, a rumbling thunderclap rang out from within the chaotic vortex up above, and it swelled drastically to devour the eighty-one pillars around it.

"Your time is up, but at least you get to enjoy witnessing the creation of a new world in your final moments," Gu Huojin declared.

Bursts of rumbling continued to ring out incessantly as the chaotic vortex expanded further and further.

All of the world's origin qi across the entire Heavenly Palace Continent was stirred up into a chaotic frenzy, and all of the law powers were also disrupted, shattering all of the rules that heaven and earth had operated by since the beginning of time.

The already severely ravaged Jade Pond Paradise came plummeting out of the sky, but it completely disintegrated before it even had a chance to reach the Heavenly Palace Continent down below.

Li Yuanjiu and the other survivors began to descend toward the Heavenly Palace Continent, but before they could get there, a series of chasms that stretched further than the eyes could see had appeared all over the entire continent.

At the same time, all of the volcanoes had begun erupting at once, while tsunamis were crashing over the entire coastline, presenting a doomsday-like scene to behold.

"Let's all appreciate the final moments of the old world," Gu Huojin said with a fervent look in his eyes.

The Devilish Monarch heaved an internal sigh as he turned his gaze to the Reincarnation Palace Master with tightly furrowed brows.

The latter also had a grim look on his face, but it seemed as if he wasn't ready to give up just yet.

Chapter 1379: Intervention

Extraheavensphere.

Han Li suddenly stopped in his tracks before looking down with a puzzled expression.

He was just about to examine whatever had caught his attention when his head suddenly began to throb in pain, and an image depicting the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch's battle against Gu Huojin surfaced in his mind.

At the same time, a sense of intense hatred for Gu Huojin that he had never felt before welled up in his heart, and this emotion was coming from the Reincarnation Palace Master.

Instinctively, Han Li had a feeling that his thoughts and emotions were also being transmitted to the Reincarnation Palace Master, and somehow, a spiritual connection had formed between the two.

Han Li was rather taken aback by this, and he immediately made a hand seal, upon which an arc of golden lightning shot out of his sleeve before vanishing into the space up ahead.

Immediately thereafter, he latched onto Jin Tong, and the two of them vanished from the spot.

Meanwhile, on the Heavenly Palace Continent.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch were engaged in a fierce battle against Gu Huojin.

All three of them had summoned their spirit domains, and numerous spatial, time, and reincarnation passageways had opened up, leading to countless realms and immortal regions to draw upon more power to fuel their spirit domains.

Following an almighty clash, the three combatants flew back through the air, and after steadying himself, the Devilish Monarch swiped his hands through the air in rapid succession with silver light flashing between his fingers.

Dozens of mountainous, silver giants instantly emerged within his spirit domain before pressing themselves tightly against Gu Huojin's golden spirit domain.

These giants were incredibly physically imposing, and their facial features were identical to the Devilish Monarch's. Their entire bodies were riddled with a type of translucent, silver crystals, which were formed by the power of shattered space, containing incredibly violent spatial law powers.

All of a sudden, all of the silver giants exploded in unison at the Devilish Monarch's behest, forming dozens of silver mushroom clouds that sent boundless, devastating spatial power erupting in all directions.

A huge hole was instantly torn into the golden spirit domain, and the Reincarnation Palace Master appeared before the hole in a wraith-like manner before throwing a punch, upon which a gargantuan Six Paths Reincarnation Plate appeared behind him.

The surface of the plate was riddled with countless complex patterns, and countless projections of all types of living beings were flashing over each of its six corners. There were humans, demons, ghosts, devils, Gray Realm beings... It was as if all of the living beings in this world were gathered here.

The gargantuan plate revolved rapidly as it crashed straight into Gu Huojin's spirit domain, and it was giving off an indescribably fearsome aura, far more formidable than the aura that it had displayed back when it claimed the life of Bone Emperor.

The golden spirit domain trembled violently as a series of huge cracks appeared over its surface, while the sections of the spirit domain nearest to the plate had fallen away altogether.

The Reincarnation Palace Master's entire body was riddled with dark red patterns, and his sunken cheeks became even more gaunt and emaciated, as if all of his vitality were being sucked dry, but he he paid no heed to his own condition as he made a hand seal before thrusting it forward, releasing a thick beam of dark red light into the reincarnation plate.

The Six Paths Reincarnation Plate instantly swelled drastically in size, while the light radiating from it also became far brighter, shattering even more of Gu Huojin's spirit domain.

The rate at which the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate was advancing was also sped up by tenfold, and it seemed completely unstoppable as it rumbled its way toward Gu Huojin.

A serious look appeared on Gu Huojin's face as he made a hand seal, and a thin, golden veil rose up from his body with countless specks of golden light shimmering over its surface, giving it the appearance of a golden galaxy.

Boundless time law powers were emanating from the veil, and it was clearly an extremely formidable artifact that was infinitely approaching a first tier immortal treasure.

The veil unfurled itself before transforming into nine massive, golden light barriers, which had only just taken shape when the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate crashed into them with almighty power.

A string of dull thumps rang out as one golden light barrier was shattered after another.

In the blink of an eye, all nine light barriers had been broken, and the golden veil reappeared, having already been torn into close to twenty pieces.

However, the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate was also slowed down for an instant, and Gu Huojin took advantage of this brief window of respite to make a rapid string of hand seals before pointing a finger forward.

The torn golden veil erupted into flames, and countless golden stars flew out of it before spreading throughout the surrounding spirit domain.

All of a sudden, it was as if the golden light within the spirit domain had been ignited, and a turbulent golden galaxy appeared, sweeping up the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate, the Reincarnation Palace Master, and the Devilish Monarch behind him.

Boundless time law powers were churning within the galaxy, and the Devilish Monarch was caught completely off guard, inundated before he even had a chance to react.

The Six Paths Reincarnation Plate was also swept up by the golden galaxy, and it instantly began to tremble slightly.

The Reincarnation Palace Master hurriedly made a rapid string of hand seals upon seeing this, and the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate immediately stabilized itself before crashing down upon Gu Huojin, only for his body to dissipate into disintegrate into specks of golden light upon contact.

The Reincarnation Palace Master faltered slightly upon seeing this, while the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate stopped in its tracks at his behest.

Right at this moment, the turbulent, golden galaxy suddenly began to revolve, forming a massive vortex in the blink of an eye.

The surrounding tearing forces instantly became several times more formidable, and the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate began to drift toward the vortex in an unsteady fashion.

The Reincarnation Palace Master clasped his hands together into a seal upon seeing this, and the runes on the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate instantly began to glow radiantly as it sped up drastically in its revolution.

Tremendous reincarnation law powers erupted out of it, helping it ward off the tearing forces of the golden vortex, and it was quickly able to stabilize itself again.

However, right at this moment, countless golden chains shot out of the golden vortex, then wound themselves around the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate to form a cage.

Every single chain was giving off extremely formidable, restrictive time law powers, and the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate instantly ceased in its revolution, as if it had been sealed away.

Several of the golden chains had also wound themselves around the Reincarnation Palace Master, instantly immobilizing him.

Gu Huojin appeared above the golden vortex in a flash before flicking a finger through the air to release a golden arrow projection, which was traveling at an astonishing speed, reaching the Reincarnation Palace Master in the blink of an eye.

However, not only did the Reincarnation Palace Master not display any panic at the sight of the arrow projection, a faint smile had appeared on his face instead.

Right at this moment, a golden lightning sword emerged out of thin air up above, following which Han Li appeared beneath the sword in a flash.

He was already familiar with the situation, having witnessed everything through the Reincarnation Palace Master's eyes, and he immediately lashed out upon his arrival, unleashing a Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fist.

The golden fist projection was able to intercept the arrow projection in a timely fashion before it could strike the Reincarnation Palace Master, and a resounding explosion rang out as the arrow projection imploded into countless specks of golden light.

"Oh? You're still alive? So be it, I guess I'll just have to take care of you myself!" Gu Huojin harrumphed coldly, yet right as he raised a hand in preparation to do something, a rapidly revolving golden wheel projection suddenly appeared behind Han Li, and he instantly vanished from the spot before abruptly reappearing in front of the Reincarnation Palace Master.

With a sweep of his sleeve, a burst of golden flames from his Time Severing Torch erupted forth, forming a fiery, golden sword that struck the cage of golden chains in a flash.

The golden cage was sliced into two to free the Reincarnation Palace Master, who gave Han Li a grateful nod.

A look of dismay appeared in Gu Huojin's eyes at how easily Han Li was able to traverse through his spirit domain and destroy his Heaven Locking Cage.

However, as opposed to pursuing Han Li's duo, he vanished into the surrounding spirit domain again.

The golden vortex vanished in the blink of an eye, and the section of the spirit domain that had earlier been destroyed by the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate also instantly recovered. At the same time, the spirit domain swelled to over a hundred times its original size, and it was rippling like a vast, golden sea.

Unlike Han Li's more substantial spirit domain, Gu Huojin's spirit domain seemed to have been in a liquid form, giving it a gentle and frail appearance, but in reality, it was nigh indestructible.

Tremendous pressure was converging from all directions in relentless waves, bringing it with bursts of invasive time law powers.

Han Li's brows furrowed slightly as he immediately conjured up his own time spirit domain, which was able to ward off Gu Huojin's intrusive time law powers.

Gu Huojin's time spirit domain was flashing urgently as it attempted to stop the expansion of Han Li's spirit domain, but it was powerless to do so.

However, Han Li's spirit domain had only taken up less than 1% of the total area of Gu Huojin's spirit domain, so it was far from a major concern.

"The Devilish Monarch was swept away by Gu Huojin's time law powers earlier, and I don't know where he is right now. His power will be indispensable if we want to oppose Gu Huojin, so would you be able to rescue him as well?" the Reincarnation Palace Master asked through voice transmission.

Han Li immediately began scouring his gaze over the surrounding area upon hearing this, and his gaze quickly settled on something, following which he made a grabbing motion in that direction.

A streak of golden light erupted out of his hand before vanishing into a certain section of Gu Huojin's spirit domain, following which the streak of light returned with none other than the Devilish Monarch.

Chapter 1380: Collaborative Effort

The Devilish Monarch's robes were in tatters, giving him a rather disheveled appearance, and an incredulous look appeared on his face at the sight of Han Li.

After rescuing the Devilish Monarch, Han Li continued to scour his surroundings with his Infernal Devilish Eyes in an attempt to track down Gu Huojin, but it was as if he had truly vanished, and not even the slightest hint of his aura was left behind.

"Gu Huojin's trying to stall for time," the Reincarnation Palace Master said with tightly furrowed brows as he cast his gaze toward the ever-expanding chaotic vortex.

Now that he was in such close proximity to the Reincarnation Palace Master, the spiritual connection between them seemed to have grown even stronger, and he was able to sense what the Reincarnation Palace Master was about to say even before the words had left his mouth.

With that in mind, he couldn't help but wonder if the Reincarnation Palace Master could also see his thoughts.

"What do we do? Is there a way to force him out of hiding?" the Devilish Monarch asked.

"Fellow Daoist Han has mastered Miro's Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra. If we combine our three paramount law powers, we may be able to break Gu Huojin's spirit domain," the Reincarnation Palace Master said.

"Your condition is already less than ideal. If you continue using your reincarnation law powers, even if we manage to defeat Gu Huojin, there's a good chance you'll be claimed by the Heavenly Dao," the Devilish Monarch cautioned.

"That's still a better outcome than going down with this world. At this point, we have no choice but to go all out!" the Reincarnation Palace Master replied.

As soon as his voice trailed off, he summoned his dark red spirit domain again to overlap with Han Li's spirit domain.

The two spirit domains shuddered in unison, and both of them began to glow far brighter than before.

This was not an unfamiliar sight to Han Li. The same type of spirit domain resonance had previously been observed between his and Gan Jiuzhen's spirit domains, but on this occasion, the two spirit domains were resonating with a far higher level of harmony.

As the two spirit domains completely fused as one, the mountains in Han Li's spirit domain swelled rapidly in size to form gargantuan peaks, while the river of time transformed into a raging sea.

The same thing had taken place in the Reincarnation Palace Master's spirit domain, but he didn't appear surprised at all to see this.

"How is this happening?" Han Li asked through his and the Reincarnation Palace Master's spiritual connection.

"In a sense, you and I are still the same person, so it's naturally very easy for law resonance to take place between us. On top of that, you've also fully mastered the Spirit Refinement Technique, allowing you to establish spiritual connections with others, thereby making law resonance even easier to achieve, so this is far from surprising," the Reincarnation Palace Master explained.

Han Li was enlightened upon hearing this, and he realized that this had to have been another reason why the Reincarnation Palace Master had bestowed the Spirit Refinement Technique upon him.

The Reincarnation Palace Master could sense Han Li's apprehension, and he communicated, "I bear no ill will toward you, Fellow Daoist Han. Everything I did was for the sake of bringing down Gu Huojin. If you can help me accomplish that objective, I'm willing to hand over full control of the Reincarnation Palace to you."

"I don't even know if we'll be able to survive past today, so we'll discuss that another time," Han Li replied with a shake of his head.

Through their spiritual connection, he could sense that the Reincarnation Palace Master's offer had been made in earnest, but he didn't have much interest in power.

Furthermore, even if it weren't for the Reincarnation Palace Master's sake, he still had to defeat Gu Huojin as there could only be one Time Dao Ancestor.

Furthermore, exacting vengeance for Patriarch Miro also served as an additional incentive.

With that in mind, Han Li made a hand seal, and his time spirit domain swelled even further in size as a series of swords of golden light came flying out from within, every single one of which was imbued with immense power.

The Reincarnation Palace Master could sense Han Li's resolve through their spiritual connection, and he was very glad that they were on the same page.

Bursts of dark red light shot out of his spirit domain at his behest, then intertwined with the swords of golden light flying out of Han Li's spirit domain.

Thanks to their spiritual connection, they were able to work in perfect synchronicity, and their law powers were also combining together in a seamless fashion.

All of the golden swords instantly swelled rapidly to dozens of times their original size while also becoming clearer and more substantial.

A series of dark red spirit patterns appeared over the golden swords as they became infused with reincarnation law powers, and they erupted in all directions to slice through Gu Huojin's spirit domain.

One massive gash after another was easily torn into the spirit domain, reducing it to tattered rag.

A stunned look appeared on the Devilish Monarch's face upon seeing this, and he hurriedly conjured up more of the same silver giants from earlier before detonating them to send bursts of destructive spatial powers sweeping through the surrounding, golden spirit domain.

As one of the three paramount laws, his spatial powers were also resonating with Han Li and the Reincarnation Palace Master's law powers to a certain extent, and before long, Gu Huojin's spirit domain was on the verge of collapse.

The golden light inside was frantically trying to mend the rifts that had been torn into the spirit domain, but to no avail.

Encouraged by the progress that they had made, Han Li and the Reincarnation Palace Master redoubled their efforts, and countless swords of golden light shot forth to strike at the already severely ravaged spirit domain.

Finally, the golden spirit domain completely disintegrated into a vast expanse of golden light, and Gu Huojin was revealed, but much to the surprise of Han Li's trio, the entire lower half of his body had already vanished into the chaotic vortex.

Furthermore, a series of chaotic patterns had appeared over his skin, including his face, presenting a harrowing sight to behold.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch were stunned to see this, while Han Li looked up into the sky with a thoughtful expression.

Ever since reaching the Great Encompassment Stage, he had constantly felt as if there were some type of invisible force weighing down on him from above, as if an insurmountable obstacle stood between him and further advancement in the laws of time.

The presence of Gu Huojin at the pinnacle of the laws of time had made it impossible for any other cultivator of time law powers to reach the same heights, but in this moment, Han Li felt as if this insurmountable obstacle had suddenly disappeared.

Could it be...

A hint of excitement welled up in Han Li's heart as a possibility occurred to him.

"You're too late! I've already become one with the Great Dao and attained the laws of chaos! I'm completely impervious to your law powers now!" Gu Huojin guffawed in a deranged manner as his composed facade completely slipped away.

An almighty, all-encompassing aura erupted out of his body, and there were all types of different law power fluctuations emanating from within, the most prominent of which was still his original time law powers.

"He's gone insane!" the Devilish Monarch exclaimed.

"He's most likely not in a sound state of mind as he's still yet to gain full control over the power of chaos in his body. We don't have any time to waste! If he manages to attain full mastery over the laws of chaos, then even our combined powers will be no match for him," the Reincarnation Palace Master said in an urgent manner, then immediately launched himself at Gu Huojin, followed closely by Han Li and the Devilish Monarch.

Gu Huojin turned to them with a deranged expression as he swept both sleeves through the air, and countless brown arrow projections came hurting out of the chaotic vortex, every single one of which was over a thousand feet in length and as thick as a millstone.

These arrow projections were also imbued with different law powers, but only four types, two of which were space and time, which were distinctly separate, while the other two had fused as one, making them rather difficult to distinguish, but they seemed to have been the laws of wind and lightning.

Both the laws of wind and lightning were geared toward speed, and this quality was further enhanced by the laws of space and time, granting the arrow projections incredible speed that allowed them to reach Han Li's trio in an instant.

The three of them were caught off guard by the astonishing speed of the oncoming projectiles, yet right as the arrow projections were about to strike them, the Devilish Monarch abruptly appeared before Han Li and the Reincarnation Palace Master before making a hand seal.

All of the space within a radius of tens of thousands of kilometers instantly fell completely still at his behest, and all of the arrow projections were brought to a halt.

However, in the next instant, four bursts of law powers erupted out of the arrow projections in unison to shatter the stagnant space, and they continued to race through the air.

This brief window of respite was enough for Han Li and the Reincarnation Palace Master to react to the situation, and they combined the powers of their spirit domains to send a flurry of golden sword projections flying toward the oncoming arrow projections.

Golden, dark red, and brown light erupted in all directions amid a string of deafening booms, causing the surrounding space to ripple violently, and even the chaotic vortex had begun churning incessantly.

The brown arrow projections were extremely formidable, but they were no match for the combination of Han Li and the Reincarnation Palace Master's law powers, and all of the arrow projections were quickly eradicated, but many of the golden sword projections had also been shattered in the process.

Han Li and the Reincarnation Palace Master were injecting their immortal spiritual power and law powers into their spirit domains with no reservation, and the two spirit domains expanded rapidly toward Gu Huojin while releasing countless more golden sword projections.

At the same time, the Devilish Monarch appeared out of thin air on the other side of Gu Huojin before pointing a finger at him, and a series of silver rifts appeared in the space up ahead.

These silver rifts were giving off far more fearsome spatial law powers than normal spatial rifts, and all of them converged toward Gu Huojin at the Devilish Monarch's behest.

Chapter 1381: Resurrection

The deranged look on Gu Huojin's face became even more pronounced at the sight of the oncoming attacks, and he slit his left wrist with his finger, releasing a large stream of blood essence into the chaotic vortex beneath him.

A layer of faint, crimson light instantly appeared over the chaotic vortex, and it began to expand at a far faster rate than before.

With a sweep of his sleeve, countless flaming rocks flew out of the chaotic vortex like fiery asteroids to strike the golden sword projections and silver spatial rifts.

Unlike the brown arrow projections, these flaming rocks were imbued with nine types of different law powers.

The fiery rocks instantly exploded upon making contact with the sword projections and spatial rifts, creating a scorching sea of fire.

Nine bursts of law powers were intertwining with one another in a frenzy within the sea of flames, devouring the golden sword projections and spatial rifts.

At the same time, Han Li's trio was struck by a burst of tremendous power from afar, sending them flying back through the air.

A pleased grin appeared on Gu Huojin's face as he swept both sleeves through the air once again, and the chaotic vortex shuddered violently as countless balls of lightning the size of houses came raining down upon the trio.

These balls of lightning didn't appear to have been imbued with any types of law powers. Instead, they were giving off a chaotic aura, and it looked as if each of them contained a miniature world.

"Get back! This is Chaotic Divine Lightning!" the Reincarnation Palace Master yelled in a panicked manner while making a rapid string of hand seals, and six bursts of dark red light flew out of the six holes in the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate to envelop his entire body as he shot back in retreat.

Han Li and the Devilish Monarch didn't know how much of a threat this Chaotic Divine Lightning posed, but they also hurriedly flew back in retreat upon seeing the Reincarnation Palace Master's reaction.

The Devilish Monarch swept his hands through the air, and the surrounding space instantly formed a spherical, semi-transparent cocoon around him.

Even though the cocoon was clearly visible, it also seemed extremely distant, as if it were in some type of alternate dimension.

Meanwhile, Han Li shrank down his spirit domain to only less than two hundred feet in size, making it extremely condensed and resilient.

At the same time, he conjured up an Immortal Golden Cloud around himself, and the golden cloud had only just taken shape when the Chaotic Divine Lightning crashed down upon his spirit domain.

The entirety of heaven and earth took on a chaotic coloration as everything was completely obliterated. The Chaotic Divine Lightning inundated everything, and a large section of the space that had already disintegrated into nothingness collapsed once again.

The spirit domain around Han Li wasn't even able to hold itself together for an instant before it was torn apart, following which the lightning crashed down upon the Immortal Golden Cloud, which immediately began to thin rapidly.

In the blink of an eye, most of the cloud had already been eradicated, leaving only a thin layer behind.

Han Li was astonished to see this, and he finally understood why the Reincarnation Palace Master had displayed such a panicked reaction at the sight of the Chaotic Divine Lightning.

He channeled his Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra with all his might as his time law powers gushed into the Immortal Golden Cloud in a frenzy.

Immediately thereafter, he summoned his five time law treasures, which began orbiting around him while releasing tremendous time law powers.

The nearby space instantly twisted and warped into a golden vortex that resembled a space-time passageway with incredibly formidable time law powers swirling around within, pulverizing anything that dared to enter the vortex.

At the same time, a series of black, devilish patterns and black scales appeared over his body as he transformed into a devilish deity with twelve heads and thirty-six arms.

The oncoming Chaotic Divine Lightning crashed into the golden vortex, causing it to tremble violently like a small boat in a raging storm, and despite Han Li's best efforts, the vortex was simply unable to devour the Chaotic Divine Lightning.

Balls of Chaotic Divine Lightning exploded around the vortex, causing it to shrink rapidly, and Han Li's five time law treasures were quickly revealed.

As more Chaotic Divine Lightning began to crash down from above, the five time law treasures were quickly obliterated, and Han Li's complexion turned deathly pale as he threw up a mouthful of blood with an alarmed look on his face.

His five time law treasures were the most important treasures in his possession, and they had helped him overcome countless formidable foes, yet they had just been shattered like fragile pieces of chinaware!

While it was true that he could slowly reform them over time, how was he supposed to oppose Gu Huojin in his current state?

With the golden vortex destroyed, the Immortal Golden Cloud around Han Li was also significantly weakened, and it was being rapidly whittled away by the Chaotic Divine Lightning.

Bursts of destructive power infiltrated his body from all directions, causing his meridians to tremble violently, and even in his most formidable devilish deity form, he was struggling to withstand the assault.

He hurriedly channeled his Heavenly Baleful Purgatory Arts and the remaining time law powers in his body with all his might, and bursts of tremendous power erupted out of his body to expel the infiltrating destructive power.

Right at this moment, the Immortal Golden Cloud around Han Li finally collapsed under the might of the Chaotic Divine Lightning, forcing him to lash out with his fists to defend himself.

In the blink of an eye, thirty-six golden fist projections were unleashed, every single one of which possessed the power to smash a hole in the heavens, yet they were instantly eradicated upon contact with the Chaotic Divine Lightning without so much as a whimper.

A vast expanse of chaotic lightning came cascading down upon Han Li, tearing his thirty-six arms to shreds.

At the same time, countless scales were flying off his body, following which his skin and flesh were torn away to reveal the black bones underneath.

If it weren't for the fact that he was protecting these bones with all his might by channeling both his Heavenly Baleful Purgatory Arts and his time law powers, they would've also been destroyed.

His ravaged body was sent flying like a tattered rag, and he reverted back to his human form in the process.

The Chaotic Divine Lightning in the sky dissipated shortly thereafter, and the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate had managed to weather the storm, but several cracks had appeared over its surface, and the dark red light emanating from it had also dimmed significantly.

Behind the reincarnation plate was a humanoid ball of light, from within which emerged the Reincarnation Palace Master.

His complexion was also extremely pale, clearly indicating that withstanding the storm of Chaotic Divine Lightning had taken quite a toll on him.

To his dismay, the Devilish Monarch's lifeless body was hovering nearby, having already been dismembered into several pieces.

Han Li was able to survive the ordeal, but was also only just barely clinging onto life.

"Did you enjoy the taste of my Chaotic Divine Lightning? Now that both of your little helpers are done, you're the only one left. How are you going to exact your revenge now?" Gu Huojin chortled with glee.

Bursts of chaotic light were streaming into his body from the surrounding vortex, and his aura swelled to even greater heights.

"Your Chaotic Divine Lightning is indeed formidable, but it's not over yet!" the Reincarnation Palace Master harrumphed coldly as he flew back in retreat while opening his mouth to release a ball of dark red light, within which were several dozen reincarnation law threads, all of which vanished into the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate in a flash.

The reincarnation plate immediately began to revolve rapidly while releasing a burst of tremendous suction, drawing in the bodies of Han Li and the Devilish Monarch.

One of the six holes on the reincarnation plate swelled drastically in size as it devoured the Devilish Monarch's remains, and the Reincarnation Palace Master made a rapid string of hand seals, upon which the reincarnation plate began to radiate dazzling, dark red light that seeped into the space around it.

Gu Huojin's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this.

Immediately thereafter, the Devilish Monarch flew out of another hole on the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate, and he was back to peak condition, having just been resurrected.

He looked around in a bewildered manner for a moment, but he was quickly able to make sense of what had just happened, and he extended a grateful bow toward the Reincarnation Palace Master.

"No need for formalities, Fellow Daoist Shi. I was able to resurrect you with my reincarnation law powers, but it's cost you one future lifetime, so it's not to be used repeatedly," the Reincarnation Palace Master said, then turned to Han Li to try and bring him back from the brink of death, only to suddenly stop what he was doing as a surprised look appeared on his face.

At this moment, Han Li was hovering in mid-air with only the faintest of auras emanating from his body.

The remaining time law powers in his body had been forced out and dissipated into nothingness, leaving his body completely empty.

He was no longer able to feel any pain, and his five senses were also gradually fading.

Is this it for me?

This thought didn't evoke any fear in his heart. Instead, he felt as if he had fused as one with this world.

Everything around him suddenly began to slow down and present itself to him with incredible clarity.

He was no longer able to see with his eyes, but he was sensing this world through alternative means...

Chapter 1382: Heavenly Dao Tribulation

What's going on? Am I about to meet my demise and become one with this world? I've been so careful and vigilant throughout my entire cultivation journey, yet it seems like that was all for nought... Compared with all of the countless cultivators who perished earlier in their cultivation journeys, the only difference is that I was able to live a bit longer than them. I'm sorry, Wan'er.

If we can be reunited in the next life, I would rather that we were both mortals. Immortality would be out of our reach, but at least we wouldn't have to waste the majority of our lives toiling away in cultivation.

A hint of sorrow and resignation welled up in his heart as these thoughts drifted through his mind.

Right at this moment, streaks of golden light suddenly appeared in the surrounding space. They were rapidly converging toward him, imbued with bursts of time law powers, but the world was still moving extremely slowly.

These streaks of golden light surged into his body as five torrents of golden radiance, and they were none other than the five types of time law powers that Han Li had been cultivating for so many years through his Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra.

He was rapidly regaining what he had lost, and as his body was filled with time law powers once again, his five senses also began to recover.

The five bursts of time law powers were churning through his entire body in a frenzy, while the passages of the Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra flowed through his mind, giving him an unprecedented level of understanding of the cultivation art.

All of a sudden, it was as if a door had been opened, allowing him to step into a brand new world.

More and more time law powers continued to flow into his body, quickly restoring him to his former peak, but the influx of time law powers showed no signs of stopping.

The world's origin qi was also gushing into his body alongside the time law powers, and his injuries began to rapidly heal.

A burst of blinding, golden light erupted out of his body along with aura fluctuations that were several times more formidable than before, and all of the world's origin qi in the entire Middle Earth Immortal Region had begun churning wildly.

The flow of time around Han Li abruptly returned to normal, and the Reincarnation Palace Master, the Devilish Monarch, and Gu Huojin had all turned to him with alarmed expressions.

From their perspectives, all of this had taken place in the blink of an eye, with Han Li on the brink of death one moment, then making a breakthrough the next.

Looks of excitement quickly surfaced in the eyes of the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch.

They didn't know how it had happened, but they could sense from Han Li's aura that he was making a breakthrough to become a Dao Ancestor.

If Han Li could become a Dao Ancestor at such a critical juncture, then their chances of victory would be significantly increased.

"How is this possible? Gu Huojin is still alive, how is Fellow Daoist Han able to become the Time Dao Ancestor?" the Devilish Monarch exclaimed.

"By taking in the power of chaos to try and transcend beyond the Heavenly Dao, Gu Huojin has relinquished the berth of Time Dao Ancestor. I'm assuming this is something that even Gu Huojin himself failed to anticipate," the Reincarnation Palace Master said.

A hint of killing intent flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes as he turned his gaze to Han Li, but before he had a chance to do anything, he was confronted by the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch.

Gu Huojin's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this. His powers had been significantly enhanced after he became one with the chaotic vortex, but the process had also left him unable to move.

Right at this moment, dense blankets of dark clouds began to converge from all directions, quickly filling the entire sky, and a burst of almighty pressure descended from above.

A combination of concern and elation appeared on the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch's faces upon seeing this.

They knew that this was the precursor for Han Li's Heavenly Dao Tribulation, something that he would have to overcome in order to become a Dao Ancestor, but failure to do so would spell his demise.

Once the Heavenly Dao Tribulation descended upon Han Li, anyone that tried to approach him would be struck by the power of heavenly tribulation, so even Gu Huojin wouldn't be able to get to him.

"As one of the three paramount laws, the Heavenly Dao Tribulation for the laws of time is far more fearsome than for other law powers! I had to make extensive preparations in order to transcend my tribulation, and even then, it was only through some strokes of luck that I managed to emerge unscathed, so there's no way he'll be able to transcend his tribulation completely unprepared," Gu Huojin harrumphed coldly, and it seemed that he had regained some sanity.

At this point, the entire sky had already turned as black as ink, and all of the dark clouds up above began to swirl, forming an enormous vortex directly above Han Li, who looked up into the sky with a calm expression.

Having just "died" once, he had gained some new perspective on life, leaving him in a composed and unflappable state.

Arcs of black lightning were flashing within the vortex, and at its center was a black hole that led to some unknown place.

A deafening thunderclap rang out, and the pressure emanating from the vortex instantly became countless times more fearsome than before, causing the nearby space to tremble and warp violently.

Han Li shuddered slightly under the pressure, but was able to immediately steady himself.

Countless dense, gray clouds surged out of the vortex before descending upon Han Li, and this was a familiar sight to him as he had seen the same gray clouds during Daoist Xie's Heavenly Dao Tribulation.

However, the gray clouds that had descended upon Daoist Xie at the time weren't even a tenth of what he was currently facing.

A faint smile suddenly appeared on Han Li's face.

Back when he had witnessed Daoist Xie's tribulation transcendence, he had fallen unconscious as soon as those gray clouds had appeared. Now that he was facing his own tribulation, he was able to face the same gray clouds with much more composure.

Upon closer inspection, he discovered that these gray clouds were formed by countless tiny arcs of gray lightning that were imbued with a type of peculiar power capable of bringing one's inner demons to the fore.

Han Li let loose a low roar as he threw a punch upward, and countless rays of golden light erupted out of his fist like a radiant sun.

These rays of golden light were able to tear the gray clouds apart with ease, and they quickly dissipated into nothingness.

The power of lightning posed no threat to Han Li, and as for inner demons, he had none to speak of after severing his three corpse souls.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch were both ecstatic to see this, while Gu Huojin sneered, "The first tribulation is just the appetizer, the main course is still yet to come."

As soon as his voice trailed off, the black tribulation clouds up above suddenly turned a crimson color.

Thick bolts of crimson lightning were flashing within the tribulation clouds, taking on the shape of crimson lotus flowers that were giving off a fearsome aura of annihilation.

Red Lotus Divine Lightning!

Red Lotus Divine Lightning was one of the thirty-six heavenly lightnings, one that ranked above Cardinal Heavenly Lightning, and what was most fearsome about it was its ability to target the soul, an ability that gave it its alternative name of Soul Destruction Lightning.

Furthermore, this Red Lotus Lightning was far more formidable than normal Red Lotus Lightning as it was imbued with the power of heavenly tribulation.

Before Han Li had a chance to ponder the situation any further, the bolts of Red Lotus Lightning in the tribulation clouds converged to form a mountainous, red lotus flower that came crashing down upon him.

Han Li remained completely unfazed as a ball of golden light flew out of his hand, then transformed into a huge, golden shield of light that hovered above his head.

The shield was extremely translucent, looking as if it had been crafted from some type of crystalline material, and there were countless runes dancing over its surface, giving it an indestructible appearance.

This was another one of the True Mantra Sect's defensive abilities that ranked alongside the Immortal Golden Cloud, the High Heavens Shield.

The Red Lotus Divine Lightning struck the High Heavens Shield with an earth-shattering boom, and the shield shuddered violently as the runes dancing over it began to blur.

However, it displayed no signs of breaking as it continued to hover above Han Li's head, providing him shelter from the Red Lotus Divine Lightning.

All of a sudden, a semi-transparent red lotus projection flew out of the Red Lotus Divine Lightning up above, and it passed through the High Heavens Shield as it descended rapidly upon Han Li.

Han Li wasn't surprised to see this, and he quickly made a hand seal, upon which a complex mark appeared on his glabella, releasing bursts of translucent ripples that encompassed his entire body.

The red lotus projection struck the translucent ripples, causing them to tremble incessantly, but they were able to keep the projection at bay.

After a full fifteen minutes, the red lotus projection finally faded away, while Han Li remained completely unscathed, but before he even had a chance to catch his breath, the tribulation clouds up above suddenly took on a golden color.

Countless thick bolts of golden lightning were racing through the clouds, releasing deafening thunderclaps that threatened to shatter the entire surrounding space.

These bolts of golden lightning were giving off extremely formidable and destructive time law power fluctuations, and a grim look appeared on Han Li's face as he identified it to be lightning of time.

Chapter 1383: Golden Meridians, Jade Bones

Han Li hurriedly made a rapid string of hand seals, and his five time law treasures appeared around him, and they had all undergone substantial evolutions after being reformed.

The five time law treasures were revolving incessantly while radiating incredibly pure golden light and immense time law power fluctuations.

Before Han Li had a chance to do anything else, the bolts of golden lightning came crashing down from above at an incredible speed.

Thankfully, Han Li was up to the task, and he reacted just quickly, raising his arms to the heavens.

The High Heavens Shield above him immediately began to revolve rapidly while releasing a stream of countless golden runes.

As the lightning of time crashed down onto the High Heavens Shield, countless cracks instantly appeared over its surface, and they were rapidly expanding.

Immediately thereafter, the High Heavens Shield exploded into countless golden shards that erupted in all directions, but at this point, it had already bought Han Li enough time.

As his five time law treasures orbited around him, a gargantuan, golden vortex took shape, releasing almighty devouring power that sucked in the oncoming bolts of golden lightning.

Han Li stood at the center of the vortex, swaying side to side as the vortex trembled in the face of the lightning of time, but his hands remained as steady as ever, and he was making a rapid string of hand seals.

The golden vortex stood firm against the lightning of time crashing down from above, and an impasse ensued.

Golden lightning erupted in all directions amid rumbling thunderclaps, causing the nearby space to tremble violently.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch were forced to retreat into the distance, and only after several minutes had passed did the storm of golden lightning finally recede.

The golden vortex down below also faded away, and it was revealed that Han Li's robes were in tatters, giving him a rather bedraggled appearance, but he remained largely unscathed.

Right at this moment, the golden coloration of the tribulation clouds up above quickly faded away, and it reverted back to its original, inky black color.

All of a sudden, a streak of purple light descended out of the tribulation cloud vortex, and one end of it vanished into Han Li's body in a flash.

All of his injuries were instantly fully healed in the blink of an eye, while a pillar of golden light that was filled with time law threads rose up from his body, then fused as one with the streak of purple light.

The pillar of golden light instantly began to glow brighter than before, and it circled around in the air above Han Li like a roaming dragon while giving off incredibly formidable time law power fluctuations that caused the surrounding space to tremble and warp.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch had already retreated to a safe distance away, but their footing had become rather unsteady once again, forcing them to retreat even further away.

The golden dragon only circled around Han Li for a moment before vanishing into his body, and a surprised look appeared on his face as he could sense that all of his time law threads were fusing into one with his body, which was beginning to take on a semi-transparent, golden hue.

At the same time, his nascent soul and his soul seemed to have also melted into his body like a pair of ice cubes, and the fearsome law power fluctuations surging out of his body quickly receded.

The tribulation clouds in the sky had also faded away, and everything returned to normal.

Han Li hovered in mid-air as he sensed all of the changes taking place in the world around him, and a winding, golden river appeared in his eyes. A thin branch split off from the golden river, passing through the boundless expanse of space to connect itself to him.

He raised his hands and looked down at his own arms to discover that his skin had become as thin and translucent as paper, and he was able to see all of his blood vessels and bones, the former of which had golden blood flowing inside, while the latter was as fair as jade.

"This is the legendary golden meridians and jade bones... So this is what it feels like to be a Dao Ancestor..." Han Li murmured to himself with irrepressible excitement in his eyes.

He then gently closed his eyes as his spiritual sense began to roam through the Middle Earth Immortal Region, and everything, the destroyed landmarks, the chaotic world's origin qi, and the countless lost lives, were presented to him in stunning clarity.

Before long, his spiritual sense had already drifted out of this immortal region to reach others, while the chaotic vortex continued to expand, looming over the entire Middle Earth Immortal Region like a massive lid.

Everything on the ground below was rapidly disintegrating, reverting back to their most fundamental constituent parts before being absorbed by the chaotic vortex in the sky.

All of the lifeless bodies that littered the earth were gradually melting away, while the surviving cultivators were darting around in a panicked and aimless fashion.

In this doomsday-like scenario, where could they possibly run?

At this point, Li Yuanjiu's group had already been separated, and Meng Po was doing her best to protect Yu Menghan as they frantically flew from one place to another for refuge.

She had been robbed of most of her power by the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array, leaving her significantly weakened, but even so, she still held firmly onto the hand of her prized disciple.

Yu Menghan's clothes were dirty and in tatters, but there wasn't much fear or panic on her face. Instead, she was looking at her mistress with a gentle and serene expression.

The two of them had only just barely evaded a rapidly expanding spatial rift when a spatial vortex appeared directly beneath them, sucking them downward against their will.

Meng Po turned around to give Yu Menghan a look of apology, and she regretted bringing her disciple here. She would've met her demise even if she had stayed in the sect, but at the very least, it wouldn't have been under such hellish circumstances.

Yu Menghan shook her head with a gentle smile, reassuring Meng Po that she had nothing to apologize for, then cast her gaze up toward the heavens, wishing to see Han Li one final time before she was devoured by the spatial vortex down below.

However, she had only just looked up when a streak of golden light descended upon the two of them from above, then pulled them out of the spatial vortex.

"Go inside my domain treasure for now," Han Li instructed as he flew to their side before sweeping a sleeve through the air to conjure up a door of silver light.

Yu Menghan opened her mouth to call out to Han Li, but was interrupted by a resounding boom as the sun hanging above the Middle Earth Immortal Region exploded violently, plunging the entire immortal region into eternal darkness.

"We'll have to catch up some other time, Fellow Daoist Yu," Han Li said in a grim manner, and the two women stepped through the spatial doorway.

Meng Po had been observing Han Li this entire time, and she could see the feelings that Yu Menghan harbored toward him from the look on her face.

Her intuition told her that the man standing before them was perhaps the biggest hope that all of the countless living beings of this world had for surviving this ordeal.

If it weren't for him, perhaps Gu Huojin's plan would've already fully come into fruition.

Even as a Dao Ancestor, Han Li wasn't able to glean the thoughts of Meng Po and Yu Menghan, and at this moment, he was looking up at the sky as his aura gradually stabilized.

Gu Huojin was standing high up in the heavens with his lower body submerged in the chaotic vortex, looking as if he were about to be devoured by it, but his eyes were alight with excitement, as if this were a fate that he would gladly welcome.

There was no longer any black visible in his pupils, only a pair of gray vortexes that were revolving incessantly while giving off a peculiar power.

On his left, the Devilish Monarch's hands were clasped into a seal, sending a massive, radiant, silver pagoda hurtling toward Gu Huojin, while a gargantuan pillar of light was also racing toward him from the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate at the Reincarnation Palace Master's behest.

In response, all Gu Huojin did was reach out with his hands, and a pair of huge, chaotic hands emerged from the vortex around him to keep the oncoming attacks at bay.

Han Li quickly made a hand seal as he channeled his Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra, and his five time law treasures began circling around while giving off radiant, golden light alongside immense time law power fluctuations.

He joined his palms in front of his own chest, and the winding river of time reappeared, as did that feeling of oneness with the world.

Inside the chaotic vortex, Gu Huojin suddenly turned his gaze to Han Li as if he had sensed something, and a hint of surprise flashed through his eyes as he exclaimed, "He actually managed to do it, and his affinity with the Heavenly Dao is even greater than what I was able to achieve!"

Chapter 1384: Anomaly

The outcome of the half-divination that Chen Tuan had previously conducted surfaced in Gu Huojin's mind, and a dark look appeared in his eyes.

"Chen Tuan was right, you really are the biggest anomaly standing in my way! You've been lucky to survive to this point, but that ends now!" Gu Huojin roared, and as soon as his voice trailed off, a massive ball of gray light emerged from the chaotic vortex around him before hurtling toward Han Li at an astonishing speed.

Han Li was already prepared, and he thrust both palms forward at once, sending countless specks of golden light surging toward the ball of gray light.

As the specks of golden light converged, the outlines of a river of time gradually began to take shape, and it crashed into the ball of gray light like a turbulent wave.

The ball of gray light began devouring the rays of golden light around it, expanding further and further in the process, but also becoming more slow and sluggish.

By the time it swelled to over a hundred thousand feet in size, it had virtually come to a complete halt.

Right at this moment, an explosive thunderclap rang out as a line of dazzling, golden radiance appeared down the center of the ball of gray light, and it was split into two before exploding with almighty power.

All of the space within a radius of hundreds of thousands of kilometers expanded rapidly, and light, debris, and the world's origin qi in the area were erased from existence.

Immediately thereafter, all of the shockwaves from the explosion began to rapidly contract, ultimately collapsing the space at the epicenter to form an all-devouring black hole.

Gu Huojin's brows furrowed slightly upon seeing this.

Right at this moment, a river of time abruptly appeared before him hundreds of thousands of kilometers away, and Han Li was walking over it as if he were treading a line between illusion and reality, and in the blink of an eye, he was no more than several thousand kilometers away from Gu Huojin.

Before Gu Huojin had a chance to do anything, Han Li threw a punch his way, and the five time law treasures around him instantly vanished into the river of time down beneath him.

The turbulent river of time instantly transformed into a gargantuan, golden fist projection that hurtled directly toward Gu Huojin, and it was uninhibited by the space before it, striking Gu Huojin in the same instant that it took shape.

An earth-shattering boom rang out as the golden fist projection exploded to fill the entire space with blinding, golden light, and the shockwaves from the explosion obliterated the two giant arms extending out of the chaotic vortex.

As a result, the pressure on the Devilish Monarch and the Reincarnation Palace Master was significantly lessened, and the two of them immediately retreated to close to a hundred thousand kilometers away.

"He's using his time law powers way too aggressively! Is he not afraid of being assimilated by the Heavenly Dao?" the Devilish Monarch asked through voice transmission, and the Reincarnation Palace Master merely shook his head in response.

Moments later, the golden light from the fist projection finally dissipated, and the five time law treasures flew back to Han Li before vanishing into his body.

However, much to Han Li's concern and dismay, not only was Gu Huojin completely unscathed from the attack, his aura had only become more formidable.

"The laws of chaos can devour all things, so I am already invincible. How much more time law power do you have? Send it all my way!" Gu Huojin chortled with glee.

Right at this moment, Han Li felt a burst of searing pain in front of his chest, and he looked down to discover that the Heaven Controlling Vial was glowing red, a color that it had never displayed before.

Immediately thereafter, the voice of the vial spirit rang out in his mind.

"Now that you've become a Dao Ancestor, you can attempt to refine the Heaven Controlling Vial. Hurry, there's no time to waste!"

"What do you mean, Senior Vial Spirit?" Heaven Controlling Vial asked.

"The Heaven Controlling Vial was the first-ever Profound Heavenly Item, and it was born alongside the Heavenly Dao, so it contains not just all of the laws under the heavens, but also some residual chaos law powers. In Gu Huojin's current state, you stand no chance of defeating him unless you refine this vial!" the vial spirit explained in an urgent manner.

"Why are you only telling me this now?" Han Li asked.

"There's no time for questions! I was only born when your previous incarnation, the Reincarnation Palace Master, injected all of his time law powers into the Heaven Controlling Vial, so even though I'm the vial spirit, my knowledge of the Heaven Controlling Vial's properties is far from comprehensive, and I've constantly been cultivating to try and unravel more of the vial's secrets," the vial spirit explained.

"Does that mean you were cultivating on all of those occasions that I called upon you, but received no response?" Han Li exclaimed.

"That's right. The Heaven Controlling Vial was born alongside heaven and earth, and it's only revealed all of its secrets to me after sensing Gu Huojin's plans to destroy this world in order to create a new one. Now hurry up and refine the vial! I'll lend you my assistance," the vial spirit urged.

Before Han Li had a chance to respond, a rumbling thunderclap suddenly rang out up above, and a pillar of chaotic lightning came crashing down upon him.

His seventy-two sword spirit children immediately flew out of his body on their own, then quickly arranged themselves into a massive sword array, which released countless arcs of Cardinal Heavenly Lightning to oppose the pillar of chaotic lightning.

The two types of lightning exploded in unison, sending ferocious shockwaves sweeping through the entire surrounding area in a radius of millions of kilometers. All of the surrounding space was torn to shreds, releasing all types of violent spatial storms as most of the Middle Earth Immortal Region was destroyed in mere seconds.

The sword array formed by the Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords also fell apart, and they reverted back into sword spirit children that returned to Han Li's side.

"Fellow Daoist Shi, Palace Master, I'll have to trouble the two of you to hold off Gu Huojin for a while. I may have a way to turn the tables, but it's going to require some preparation," Han Li said through voice transmission.

The Devilish Monarch was rather hesitant, while the Reincarnation Palace Master immediately agreed.

"If you don't have a way to stop Gu Huojin, then I suggest you place your trust in him," the Reincarnation Palace Master said to the Devilish Monarch, then flew over to Han Li's side.

The Devilish Monarch's brows furrowed slightly upon hearing this, but he ultimately obliged, and he and the Reincarnation Palace Master situated themselves in front of Han Li like a pair of guardians.

Meanwhile, Han Li sat down in mid-air, then removed the Heaven Controlling Vial from around his neck before cupping it in his hands.

All of a sudden, a burst of bright, crimson light suddenly began emanating from the vial, and it seemed to be able to seep into his body, illuminating his tendons, bones, and meridians the same crimson color.

Both the Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch turned back to take a surprised glance at Han Li upon sensing what was happening behind them.

The Heaven Controlling Vial had once been under the ownership of the Reincarnation Palace Master, and he had used it in countless battles, but never had he felt the vial giving off an aura like this.

Gu Huojin had also noticed that Han Li was preparing something, and he roared, "Han Li, I won't let you get in my way!"

As soon as his voice trailed off, he clasped his hands together in a seal before thrusting them toward Han Li in unison, and a pillar of blinding, white light erupted out of the center of the chaotic vortex, forming a vast sea of light that swept directly toward Han Li's trio.

All of the space in the wake of the sea of light was completely annihilated, leaving behind a widening chasm of complete nothingness.

A look of resolve appeared on the Reincarnation Palace Master's face as he stepped forward and swept a sleeve through the air, and the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate flew to around a thousand feet in front of him, following which it began to swell rapidly in size.

In the blink of an eye, it had already swelled to over a million feet in size, standing before Han Li's trio like a gargantuan wall.

At the same time, it began revolving rapidly, and the almighty sea of black light was kept at bay by the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate.

However, the sections of the sea of white light that swept past on either side of the reincarnation plate continued onward further into the distance, annihilating what little remained of the Middle Earth Immortal Region.

Han Li paid no heed to all of this as he focused the entirety of his attention on channeling his Great Five Elemental Illusion Mantra.

His time law powers had taken on the form of countless strands of light, which were connected to the Heaven Controlling Vial, and for the first time, he had truly entered the vial's internal space.

The vial seemed to have been harboring an infinitely large space, within which Han Li was smaller than even the tiniest speck of dust.

He was surrounded by a boundless expanse of darkness, within which balls of light of different colors could be seen, some of which appeared as massive as planets, while others were as small as bonfires, and all of them were giving off different law power fluctuations.

Chapter 1385: Unification of the Great Dao

All of the Great Daos under the heavens are in this vial...

Han Li began to roam through the internal world of the Heavenly Controlling Vial, and only then did he notice that the surrounding balls of light were not stationary. Instead, they were all displaying different patterns of movement.

A hint of agitation began to well up in Han Li's heart. How was he supposed to refine all of these Great Daos?

Right at this moment, he suddenly noticed that there were some balls of light that were flashing in a rhythmic fashion, as if they were calling out to him.

He flew over to them to discover that all of them contained law powers that had some affinity with his Great Dao, including lightning and the five elements.

The closer he drew to the center of the vial's internal space, the sparser the balls of light became, but the law powers that they contained also became more immense. At the very center of the internal space was a massive, chaotic cloud, floating around it were the three largest balls of light that were golden, silver, and dark red in color.

The law power fluctuations emanating from the chaotic cloud were identical to those of the chaotic vortex outside, while the three balls of light represented the three paramount laws.

Of course, Han Li had the greatest affinity with the ball of golden light, and as soon as he approached it, wisps of time law powers began to separate from it before flowing into his spiritual sense.

He instantly felt as if his body were full of power, and as he turned his gaze elsewhere, he discovered some hidden details that he hadn't been able to see before.

As it turned out, there were countless threads extending out of the chaotic cloud, connecting it to all of the balls of light in this boundless space to form an enormous net.

Thanks to his connection with the laws of time, Han Li seemed to have also become a part of this net.

Meanwhile, in the outside world, more and more white light was surging out of the chaotic vortex, forcing the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate back on a constant retreat.

As more and more of the white light infiltrated the reincarnation plate, it began to glow brighter and brighter, as if it were unable to bear the influx of chaotic power.

"Fellow Daoist Shi, I need your help," the Reincarnation Palace Master implored through gritted teeth.

The Devilish Monarch was already prepared, and he gave the Reincarnation Palace Master a firm nod.

Right at this moment, the Reincarnation Palace Master suddenly switched to a different hand seal, and a hole suddenly appeared at the center of the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate.

The chaotic pillar of light that encompassed the entire reincarnation plate instantly became shrank down and shot through the hole, emerging from the other side in a more condensed and powerful state.

The Devilish Monarch flew directly toward the pillar of light, and right as the two about to clash, he suddenly brought his hands apart, conjuring up a giant spatial gate that the chaotic pillar of light plunged directly into.

In the next instant, another spatial gate appeared beside Gu Huojin, and the pillar of white light shot out from within, having been redirected back at him.

Gu Huojin was instantly inundated by the pillar of white light, but his gleeful cackling indicated that this was playing right into his hands.

"He's using our attack to accelerate his absorption of chaotic law powers! Once the process is complete and he becomes the Chaotic Dao Ancestor, he'll have full control over that chaotic vortex, and he'll truly be invincible then!" the Reincarnation Palace Master exclaimed in a grim voice, following which the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate reverted back to its original state at his behest to continue opposing the chaotic pillar of light.

The Devilish Monarch flew back to the Reincarnation Palace Master's side, following which he turned his gaze to Han Li with an astonished look in his eyes.

Immediately thereafter, he conjured up a spatial barrier around Han Li to contain his aura so that Gu Huojin wouldn't notice that anything was amiss.

......

Meanwhile, in the Heaven Controlling Vial's internal space.

Han Li's spiritual sense had already transformed into a giant ball of white light.

The Three Thousand Great Daos never existed independently of one another. Instead, all of the laws under the heavens complement and support each other. That is the essence of the Heavenly Dao...

As soon as he arrived at this epiphany, all of the balls of light in the entire boundless space began converging toward the center.

First, all of the three thousand laws returned to the five elements that they belonged to, following which the five essential elemental laws converged toward the three paramount laws. In the end, all of the laws combined into one before fusing into the cloud of chaotic laws.

A burst of dull rumbling rang out within the Heaven Controlling Vial's internal space, and the chaotic cloud took on a dark green color as it began to revolve rapidly.

At the same time, Han Li's eyes sprang open as he sprang to his feet.

A layer of faint ripples emanated from his body, and that was enough to shatter the spatial barrier that the Devilish Monarch had conjured up around him.

His eyes were glowing with five-colored light as he raised his hands to the heavens, and the Heaven Controlling Vial rose up into the air to hover above him.

In the next instant, all of the patterns engraved onto the surface of the vial lit up in unison, while a series of dark green clouds surged out of its opening to form a swirling vortex that was hundreds of thousands of kilometers in size.

The Devilish Monarch's expression changed slightly upon seeing this, while the Reincarnation Palace Master exclaimed in an ecstatic manner, "This is it!"

All of a sudden, numerous massive bolts of lightning sprang out of the dark green vortex in all directions, shattering the surrounding space.

The chaotic vortex seemed to have been resonating with the dark green vortex from afar, and its rate of expansion was instantly sped up by tenfold.

An incredulous look flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes as his gaze fell upon the dark green vortex.

Given his connection to the vortex that was the manifestation of the laws of chaos, he was able to sense the threat that the dark green vortex posed.

Realizing that he had to strike, he joined his palms in front of himself, then thrust both hands forward, and countless pillars of chaotic light erupted out of the chaotic vortex before crashing down upon the dark green vortex as a series of gargantuan blades.

Han Li remained completely unfazed as a flurry of golden light surged out of his hands before descending upon the Heaven Controlling Vial, and the dark green vortex instantly swelled drastically in size, resembling the cavernous mouth of an all-devouring beast as it sped directly toward the oncoming blades of chaotic light.

As the two clashed, there was no resounding explosion, as one may have expected.

Instead, the blades of light sank into the dark green vortex without a sound, but as they pierced halfway into the vortex, the latter began to rapidly revolve, twisting the blades of light together like lengths of rope to form a bridge that connected the two vortexes.

As soon as the bridge was established, both of the vortexes began to rumble violently.

Chaotic clouds surged out of the chaotic vortex before flowing over the bridge, while plumes of green mist emerged from the dark green vortex, and initially, the two seemed evenly matched, with neither side able to get the better of the other.

However, a burst of deafening rumbling then suddenly began to ring out from within the chaotic vortex, and it sped up drastically in its revolution.

The dark green vortex was far smaller, and it appeared to have been significantly weaker as well. Before long, the dark green mist rising up from it was beginning to be sucked involuntarily into the chaotic vortex.

"The chaotic vortex has already devoured all of the world's origin qi in the entire Middle Earth Immortal Region, and it's continuing to devour more from other immortal regions. In comparison, the Heaven Controlling Vial is completely outmatched!" the Reincarnation Palace Master said in a concerned manner.

"Palace Master, Fellow Daoist Shi, I need your help!" Han Li yelled.

His entire body had already turned a radiant, golden color as he injected his time law powers into the Heaven Controlling Vial with no reservation.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch exchanged a glance with one another, then immediately sprang into action, injecting their law powers into the Heaven Controlling Vial as well.

Three giant pillars of light, one golden, one silver, and one red were rising up from the bodies of Han Li's trio before surging into the Heaven Controlling Vial, and with this injection of power, the vial began to rapidly expand until it had reached the size of a mighty pagoda.

Balls of light of different colors, containing all types of law powers, began flying out of the vial's opening before being guided up into the heavens by a blurry figure.

"Senior Vial Spirit!" Han Li exclaimed at the sight of the indistinct figure.

As soon as his voice trailed off, all of the balls of light began to connect with one another before fusing as one, forming a dazzling, rainbow ribbon of light.

The ribbon of light was giving off an unprecedented, yet somewhat familiar conflicting aura.

Chapter 1386: Fine Line Between Victory and Defeat

A hint of realization flashed through Han Li's eyes as he sensed this conflicting aura.

This was the aura of the Heavenly Dao. It was vast and all-encompassing, yet also cold and detached, harboring no empathy for any of the living beings of the world.

The ribbon of rainbow light was guided up into the sky by the vial spirit before plunging into the chaotic vortex, while Gu Huojin made no effort to intervene.

His action wasn't borne from conceitedness. Instead, he had to focus all of his effort and attention on the fierce clash taking place between two vortexes.

Of course, even more importantly, he had to speed up his absorption of the chaotic law powers around him. As soon as he became the Chaotic Dao Ancestor, he would become the embodiment of chaos, a truly untouchable deity.

In that state, no one would be able to defeat him, and Han Li's trio would be reduced to ants that he could crush on a whim.

"You think a mere Heaven Controlling Vial will be enough to turn the tables? What a joke!" Gu Huojin sneered as he swept both sleeves through the air, and the rate at which the plumes of dark green mist were sucked into the chaotic vortex was instantly sped up by a hundredfold.

The chaotic vortex twisted and warped momentarily before taking on the form of a massive, indistinct human face.

"Gu Huojin is undergoing the process of dao integration! As soon as that human face takes shape, it'll be too late for us to do anything!" the Reincarnation Palace Master yelled in an urgent manner.

The Devilish Monarch knew that he couldn't hold back any longer upon hearing this, and his body swelled rapidly in size, while a pair of huge, curved horns appeared on his head. His handsome facial features also morphed into something horrific and unsightly as he transformed into a devilish creature that was over a hundred thousand feet tall.

As he took a step forward, the space beneath his foot trembled violently, and a series of massive, silver ripples proliferated outward in all directions, only fading away after spreading to tens of millions of kilometers away.

At the same time, all of the space in the entire True Immortal Realm shuddered as if it were rejoicing in the birth of its Dao Ancestor.

Following in Han Li's footsteps, the Devilish Monarch had also surpassed his limits to ascend to Dao Ancestor status.

Both he and the Reincarnation Palace Master satisfied all of the prerequisites required to become Dao Ancestors, but he had never taken this step for fear of assimilation from the Heavenly Dao.

However, the situation had forced his hand, and he had to attain the power of a Dao Ancestor in order to stand any chance at turning the tables.

A fervent look appeared in his eyes as he raised his hands up high before bringing his palms together, and the space around Gu Huojin began to warp violently as a burst of immense spatial force compressed toward him from all directions, attempting to sever his connection with the chaotic vortex.

A resounding boom rang out as Gu Huojin's body exploded into a cloud of gray smoke, only to be instantly reformed amid a flash of gray light.

"The dao integration process is already mostly complete, there is nothing more that you can do to stop me!" Gu Huojin chortled.

Right at this moment, Han Li's eyes suddenly sprang open as he challenged, "Is that so?"

As soon as his voice trailed off, a burst of radiant, rainbow light appeared within the chaotic vortex, and it transformed into a rainbow dragon that was hundreds of millions of feet in length as it roamed through the gargantuan vortex.

Standing atop the dragon's head was none other than the vial spirit with a look of assured confidence on his face.

The rainbow dragon flew up into the heavens, then abruptly twisted around and flew straight through the center of the chaotic vortex en route to the dark green vortex down below.

As soon as the rainbow dragon flew into the dark green vortex, it began to shrink rapidly while racing toward the opening of the Heaven Controlling Vial.

The chaotic vortex was dragged along behind it, elongating the vortex into a gargantuan funnel, which surged into the dark green vortex before being sucked into the Heaven Controlling Vial.

"No! This is impossible!" Gu Huojin roared in incredulity.

Despite his frantic efforts, he was unable to prevent the chaotic vortex from being devoured by the Heaven Controlling Vial, and he was also being sucked toward the opening of the vial with it.

In a fit of fury, he was forced to sweep a hand through the air, unleashing a massive blade of chaotic light that severed him from the chaotic vortex, and he could only look on in seething rage as the vortex was completely devoured by the Heaven Controlling Vial.

After devouring the chaotic vortex, the entire vial began to flash with lights of different colors, illuminating it into a translucent state, and a rapidly revolving gray vortex could be seen within it.

The Heaven Controlling Vial remained in its massive, pagoda-sized form, and it was swaying side to side in an unsteady manner.

"Senior Vial Spirit, the vial..."

Han Li began in an urgent manner, only to be cut off by the vial spirit, who declared in an agitated voice, "I'll explain everything later. Right now, I have to help the Heaven Controlling Vial suppress this chaotic power."

Han Li didn't dare to ask any further questions for fear of distracting the vial spirit. Earlier, he had ultimately failed in his attempt to refine the Heaven Controlling Vial.

However, this was no surprise, given that the power in the Heaven Controlling Vial was infinitely approaching that of the Heavenly Dao, making it impossible to refine even for a Dao Ancestor of one of the three paramount laws.

"I should've listened to Chen Tuan and gotten rid of you first!" Gu Huojin spat through gritted teeth, and at this point, his facade of composure had already completely fallen away.

The killing intent emanating from his body was so fierce that even the chaotic power around him was unable to mask it, but Han Li remained unfazed as he smiled and goaded, "Come and get me!"

"Don't get careless," the Reincarnation Palace Master cautioned through voice transmission. "Right now, he's on the cusp of becoming the Chaotic Dao Ancestor, and his law powers aren't affected by the Heavenly Dao, so he can wield them to his heart's content, while the two of you have to worry about about assimilation by the Heavenly Dao."

As soon as his voice trailed off, the space up ahead abruptly collapsed.

Gu Huojin seemed to have become one with the cloud of chaotic, gray mist around him, and countless feelers were extending out of the cloud in all directions, devouring everything that they came into contact with.

"What's going on?" the Devilish Monarch exclaimed.

"Without the chaotic vortex to provide him with law powers, Gu Huojin has turned to absorbing power from the world around him. This entire space is most likely going to be devoured by him soon," the Reincarnation Palace Master explained.

"Fellow Daoist Shi, seal off this expanse of space to make it as difficult for him as possible to attain more power," Han Li yelled.

The Devilish Monarch immediately did as he was told without any hesitation, and two massive wings of silver light erupted out of his back before spreading through the space on either side of him.

Within mere moments, the pair of silver wings reconvened, and the entire surrounding space within a radius of tens of millions of kilometers had been encompassed within them.

"If I'm going to completely seal this area, then I have to focus solely on that task alone, and I won't be able to take any further part in battle," the Devilish Monarch said.

"That's fine. You focus on sealing this space, leave everything else to us," Han Li said, and the Reincarnation Palace Master also gave him a reassuring nod.

With that, the Devilish Monarch didn't hesitate any longer as his entire body began to blur.

He slowly became one with the silver light barrier that he had just conjured up, and a humanoid statue of himself appeared north, south, east, and west of the light barrier, while his body completely faded away.

At the same time, a massive, silver array appeared above and below the light barrier, while a series of feathers of silver light emerged between them.

These feathers were all imbued with the true meaning of the laws of space, and despite their feather-like appearance, they were incredibly heavy.

They descended like snowflakes upon the cloud of gray mist around Gu Huojin, and even the cloud of mist formed by chaotic law powers crumbled away under the immense weight of the silver feathers.

As a result, Gu Huojin was revealed, and he was looking much different from before. His clothes were in tatters, his hair was disheveled, and he was looking utterly deranged.

His legs, which had previously been devoured by the Heavenly Dao, had returned, and he was standing in mid-air barefoot with a pair of chaotic vortexes swirling in his eyes as he glowered at Han Li with ferocious killing intent.

Han Li summoned his seventy-two Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, which combined into one before falling into his grasp.

The Reincarnation Palace Master took a glance at him, then turned his gaze back to Gu Huojin, and a look of finality appeared in his eyes.

Regardless of the final outcome, the long-running vendetta between them was inevitably going to be settled on this day.

Six pillars of dark red light erupted out of the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate at the Reincarnation Palace Master's behest before hurtling directly toward Gu Huojin, who abruptly vanished into a cloud of chaotic mist.

In the next instant, he passed straight through the center of the six pillars of light to arrive before the Reincarnation Palace Master as if by instantaneous teleportation.

Han Li was astonished that Gu Huojin was still capable of mustering up such incredible speed while burdened by the Devilish Monarch's spatial law powers.

Gu Huojin let loose a low snarl as he reached out for the Reincarnation Palace Master's throat, and a layer of dark red light appeared over the latter's body as it began to dissipate.

However, Gu Huojin had other plans, and a burst of gray light erupted out of his body to envelop the Reincarnation Palace Master, forcing his body to revert back to a substantial form.

Han Li could only look on helplessly as the Reincarnation Palace Master's neck was brutally snapped, following which his head toppled off his body.

Before Han Li had a chance to try and save him, his head was decapitated head was completely pulverized by a kick from Gu Huojin, and with that, his aura completely faded away.

Chapter 1387: Seizing the Vial

A look of grief and fury surfaced in Han Li's eyes as he lashed out at Gu Huojin with his sword, and seventy-two arcs of purplish-golden lightning were sent hurtling toward him alongside a flurry of tremendous sword qi.

The space within a radius of tens of thousands of kilometers was torn to shreds and transformed into a golden pool of lightning that outshone everything around it like a radiant beacon.

Gu Huojin was swept up by the pool of lightning, and all of the chaotic mist around him was instantly eradicated, but even as his body was directly opposed to the arcs of purplish-golden lightning around him, he was able to remain completely unscathed as he strode directly toward Han Li.

He wasn't walking very quickly, but with each step that he took, a cloud of chaotic mist would gather around him, and by the time the chaotic mist dissipated, he would've already traveled over a distance of thousands of kilometers.

Hence, it only took him a few steps to emerge from the pool of lightning.

At this point, his calm facade had returned, and he looked just as sane and composed as he had at the beginning of the Bodhi Banquet, but Han Li could sense that his killing intent was more potent than ever.

He had truly been enraged by Han Li's meddlesome intervention, so much so that his fury had become entirely self-contained.

Han Li slashed his sword through the air repeatedly, sending almighty, purplish-golden lightning dragons hurtling toward Gu Huojin, transforming the entire space around him into a vast sea of lightning.

However, under the protection of the chaotic mist, he was able to remain completely unaffected, and he was making his way through the sea of lightning as if he were taking a stroll in the park.

In the blink of an eye, he was already no more than several hundred kilometers away from Han Li.

Right as he raised a hand with the intention of striking down Han Li once and for all, his expression suddenly changed slightly as he stopped in his tracks.

He then turned to discover that the Reincarnation Palace Master's headless body had vanished, while the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate had begun slowly revolving on its own.

Immediately thereafter, the six runes on the reincarnation plate lit up in unison, while a burst of dark red light appeared over its center, and the Reincarnation Palace Master emerged from within.

As soon as he made his return, six bursts of dark red light shot out of the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate, then intertwined with one another to form a dark red cage around Gu Huojin.

"I knew you wouldn't be that easy to kill," Gu Huojin said with a faint smile, seemingly completely unsurprised by the Reincarnation Palace Master's resurrection, and he dispelled the dark red cage with ease with just a raise of his hand.

However, as soon as the dark red cage was eradicated, Han Li abruptly appeared by his side, having taken on his devilish deity form with three heads and six arms. His five time law treasures were glowing radiantly behind him, and they suddenly flew into his body in a flash.

His six giant arms began to glow with dazzling, golden radiance, and he unleashed six Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fists at once.

A series of chaotic vortexes emerged around Gu Huojin to meet the six Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fists with unerring accuracy and devour them whole.

Han Li remained undeterred as he continued to lash out with his fists.

If six punches weren't enough, then what about six hundred? Six thousand? Six hundred thousand? Six million?

All that could be seen of Han Li's arms was a series of blurry afterimages as he unleashed a relentless barrage of punches upon Gu Huojin.

Initially, Gu Huojin was able to ward off the attacks with ease, but as Han Li's fists picked up more and more speed, it was often the case that the power of one punch hadn't even fully faded before the next hundred punches arrived, and each punch was imbued with sufficient power to shatter an entire continent or punch a hole in the sky.

As the fist projections layered on top of one another, they formed a massive cocoon of fist intent around Gu Huojin, trapping him within its confines.

After ten million punches, each successive punch that Han Li threw sent shockwaves erupting from the cocoon of fist intent that had taken shape around Gu Huojin to shatter the surrounding space.

Even the resurrected Reincarnation Palace Master was forced back into retreat, unable to offer Han Li any assistance, while the Devilish Monarch was also astonished by the tremendous power sweeping through the space within the spatial seal that he had created.

Right as Han Li's 16,720,000th punch fell, the accumulating pressure finally became too much, and it was released in the form of a devastating explosion.

A scorching, golden sun rose up from Gu Huojin's body before erupting outward in all directions, and the Reincarnation Palace Master instantly retreated to millions of kilometers away, followed closely by his Six Paths Reincarnation Plate.

The Devilish Monarch also withdrew his spatial seal without any hesitation and appeared beside the Reincarnation Palace Master.

In the next instant, the blinding radiance surging out of the golden sun swept over the two of them like an almighty wave, and the space around them was completely obliterated.

Immediately thereafter, a burst of immense suction force erupted out of the epicenter of the explosion, sucking in all of the remaining world's origin qi and the minute dust particles in the air, and only after what seemed like an eternity did the destroyed space manage to stabilize itself again.

Through his special connection with Han Li, the Reincarnation Palace Master was able to sense his location, and he cast his gaze in that direction to discover Han Li surrounded by a bunch of sword spirit children. He had no visible injuries, but he was panting heavily from exertion.

The sword spirit children were unable to speak, but they were flying around him in an attentive manner as if they were examining him for injuries.

After throwing over sixteen million punches in such rapid succession, he had been utterly exhausted, even with his newly attained power as a Dao Ancestor, and it was only thanks to these sword spirit children's lightning teleportation ability that he was able to safely escape from the epicenter of the explosion.

Han Li released his spiritual sense to search for Gu Huojin, but was unable to locate him.

Even so, he remained on high alert.

There was no way that Gu Huojin would be so easy to kill, particularly after he had taken in so much chaotic law power.

He cast his gaze toward the Heaven Controlling Vial to discover that it had reverted back to its original size and was hovering in mid-air while flashing with green light.

Much to his relief, the explosion just now hadn't damaged it in the slightest.

The Reincarnation Palace Master and the Devilish Monarch exchanged a glance with one another, then began flying toward Han Li, but right at this moment, a gray vortex suddenly took shape in the distance, and Gu Huojin stepped out from within, completely unscathed.

What was even more disheartening was that his aura had become even more powerful than before.

"You had some good surprises lined up for me, but let's see if you have any more tricks up your sleeves," Gu Huojin jeered as he reached out to make a grabbing motion, sucking the nearby Heaven Controlling Vial into his grasp.

Immediately thereafter, a burst of tremendous power erupted out of his hand as he tightened his grip around the Heaven Controlling Vial, attempting to crush it.

In response, a layer of dark green light surfaced over the vial to resist Gu Huojin's crushing grip.

A hint of surprise flashed through Gu Huojin's eyes upon seeing this, and he began exerting even more force.

An urgent look appeared on Han Li's face upon seeing this, and he instantly vanished from the spot.

In the same instant, a streak of swordlight came hurtling toward Gu Huojin from behind, aimed directly at his heart, only to be kept at bay by a burst of chaotic light that abruptly appeared behind him.

The streak of swordlight looked as if it were about to be devoured by the chaotic light, but in the next instant, it appeared beside Gu Huojin before racing toward his right hand, which was holding the Heaven Controlling Vial.

As it turned out, the Devilish Monarch had used his spatial law powers to redirect the streak of swordlight toward Gu Huojin's hand.

Gu Huojin's hand was severed at the wrist, and it tumbled down with the Heaven Controlling Vial still held within it.

Immediately thereafter, a spatial vortex appeared directly beneath the vial amid a flash of silver light.

Right as the vial was about to fall into the vortex, wisps of chaotic mist suddenly surged out of Gu Huojin's severed hand to reconnect it to his arm, and in the blink of an eye, it was reattached to his body.

Gu Huojin cast a cold gaze toward Han Li's trio with the Heaven Controlling Vial back in his grasp, and instead of attempting to crush it again, he slowly pressed it into the center of his own chest.

His skin and flesh slowly caved in, and the vial was devoured into his body bit by bit.

The Heaven Controlling Vial began to tremble slightly as if it were trying to resist, but its struggles were quickly stifled as it was suffocated by a cloud of chaotic mist.

Immediately thereafter, a burst of fiery, gray light appeared within Gu Huojin's chest to envelop the Heaven Controlling Vial.

Chapter 1388: Retribution

"He's trying to refine the Heaven Controlling Vial! We have to stop him!" Han Li yelled in an urgent manner.

"How? He's already mastered the laws of chaos and attained a near-indestructible body." the Devilish Monarch asked with tightly furrowed brows.

"I have one more trick that we can try. If it doesn't work, then I'll have nothing left," the Reincarnation Palace Master said after a brief silence, then disclosed his idea to Han Li and the Devilish Monarch through voice transmission.

"It's worth a try," the Devilish Monarch said after hearing what the Reincarnation Palace Master had to say, while Han Li was looking a little hesitant.

"You are the key to this plan, so banish your timidity. I'm sure you won't disappoint me," the Reincarnation Palace Master said with a smile.

A look of resolve appeared in Han Li's eyes upon hearing this, and he gave the Reincarnation Palace Master a firm nod.

With a consensus reached, a carefree smile appeared on the Reincarnation Palace Master's face as he began flying toward Gu Huojin.

"Gu Huojin, you were belittling me earlier for not knowing what it's like to be a Dao Ancestor. Let me see if the scenery up there really is as depressing as you claim it to be," the Reincarnation Palace Master said as he drew to a halt several hundred thousand kilometers away from Gu Huojin.

"It's already too late. Both of your companions made breakthroughs to become Dao Ancestors during the course of this battle, yet they're still powerless against me. What makes you think you'll be any different?" Gu Huojin sneered.

The Reincarnation Palace Master offered no response as the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate behind him began to revolve at his behest, and a series of reincarnation runes flew out of it before descending upon him.

As more and more of these reincarnation runes fell upon him, the dark red light emanating from his body grew brighter and brighter, illuminating his emaciated figure to give him the appearance of deity of death.

At the same time, reincarnation law threads began to surge out of his body to connect him to the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate, and six pillars of dark red light immediately erupted out of the reincarnation plate before flowing into his body in reciprocation.

The Reincarnation Palace Master let loose a thunderous roar, and the dark red light around him began to dance like flames, giving off formidable reincarnation law power fluctuations.

Gu Huojin thrust his palms forward upon seeing this, and a chaotic vortex instantly took shape before hurtling toward the Reincarnation Palace Master at an incredible speed.

In response, the Reincarnation Palace Master also thrust his palms forward to release a pillar of dark red light that clashed against the chaotic vortex, and the two were evenly matched as both drew to a halt in mid-air.

Right at this moment, the Devilish Monarch also sprang into action, arriving behind Gu Huojin in the blink of an eye before bringing his palms together, and all of the space within a radius of dozens of kilometers was compressed toward the center.

The compressed space began to creak and groan as it took on a glass-like appearance, and Gu Huojin was immobilized within it.

"Even with the combined might of the three paramount laws, you still can't touch me!" Gu Huojin chortled.

Rays of chaotic light began to surface over his body as he prepared to transform into a chaotic vortex once again to absorb the attacks directed at him, but the Devilish Monarch had other plans.

Bursts of spatial law power fluctuations surged out of his body as an inky black vortex began to take shape behind him, and it began to close in on the pair of wings on his back.

However, he paid no heed to this as he continued to maintain his law power output with all his might.

Meanwhile, the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate behind the Reincarnation Palace Master was revolving faster and faster while also shrinking incessantly in the process, and at the same time, his aura was rapidly elevating.

In the blink of an eye, he fulfilled his destiny, taking the final step on his cultivation journey to become the Reincarnation Dao Ancestor.

Bursts of reincarnation law powers converged from all directions before funneling into the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate, which was revolving at an astonishing speed, having already transformed into a blurry ball of dark red light.

At the same time, Han Li sprang up into the air as he channeled his Heavenly Baleful Purgatory Arts and his true spirit bloodlines with all his might, instantly transforming into a massive devilish deity with twelve true spirit heads and thirty-six arms.

Each arm was wielding an Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, which were being swung rapidly through the air to create bursts of swirling power that came together to form a gargantuan, golden tornado.

His five time law treasures were all revolving around the tornado connected to one another by arcs of golden lightning.

Within the golden tornado was an Almighty Sword Array formed by Han Li's other thirty-six Azure Bamboo Cloudswarm Swords, giving off a terrifying aura.

A hint of wariness surfaced in Gu Huojin's eyes upon seeing this, and he forcibly tore apart the spatial restraints imposed upon him by the Devilish Monarch, following which a beam of chaotic light erupted out of his chest to bolster the chaotic vortex up ahead.

Thanks to this influx of power, the chaotic vortex was able to gain the upper hand over the pillar of reincarnation light released by the Reincarnation Palace Master.

In response, the Reincarnation Palace Master let loose a loud roar, and the ever-shrinking Six Paths Reincarnation Plate behind him completely disintegrated into a ball of pure, dark red energy that flowed into his body, instantly replenishing him to rejuvenate his sunken cheeks and emaciated body.

All of a sudden, his powers were elevated to transcend beyond their former peak, and it was as if he were an almighty deity with full control over the cycle of life and death.

"Gu Huojin, you cannot transcend beyond reincarnation, nor will you ever be able to return to the cycle of reincarnation!" the Reincarnation Palace Master condemned with all his might as his body began to rapidly wither away once again.

This time, he went even further beyond his limits, sacrificing himself altogether as his body disintegrated into a ball of pure reincarnation power, just as the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate had done earlier, then tore its way through the chaotic vortex before plunging straight into Gu Huojin's body.

All of this had taken place in a split second, and there was no time for Gu Huojin to react.

All of a sudden, it was as if the cycle of reincarnation had fallen stagnant for a moment, and all over the living beings under the heavens, regardless of whether they were fleeing for their lives, resigned to their fate, or completely oblivious to the collapse of the Heavenly Dao, every single one of them was momentarily dazed.

It was as if their souls had left their bodies, but this feeling only lasted for a fleeing instant before the cycle of reincarnation returned to normal, and everyone's souls returned to their bodies, with the exception of a single person.

Gu Huojin's soul was still drifting out of his chaotic body.

In this instant, he finally realized what the Reincarnation Palace Master's plan had been, and a horrified look appeared on his face as he frantically tugged on the space before him, trying to return to his body, but a burst of golden light had gotten there before him.

Han Li's five time law treasures had already fused into the golden tornado, transforming it into a giant sword that came crashing down from the heavens with indescribable might.

Immense waves of time law powers came sweeping out of the golden sword, causing everything to fall still in a stationary snapshot in time.

Only the almighty sword that was imbued with the power of Han Li's Heavenly Baleful Purgatory Arts, Great Five Elemental Annihilation Fist, and Almighty Sword Array continued to crash down from above before striking Gu Huojin's soulless body.

A gargantuan rift silently tore its way through the entirety of the Middle Earth Immortal Region, and the expression on the face of Gu Huojin's soul instantly stiffened before it disintegrated, following which his chaotic body also began to dissipate bit by bit.

It was as if the entire world had been robbed of all color and sound, and only after close to a full minute had passed did a ball of dark green light suddenly fly out of Gu Huojin's chaotic body to hover in mid-air.

Immediately thereafter, a string of deafening booms rang out as the almighty golden sword that had claimed Gu Huojin's life finally faded away, and Han Li was revealed, having already reverted back to his human form.

His complexion was deathly pale, and blood was trickling out of all of his orifices, while plumes of black smoke were rising up from his left shoulder.

By the time the black smoke cleared, it was revealed that his entire left arm had already been claimed by the Heavenly Dao.

He raised his only remaining right arm to wipe the blood from his face as his body trembled uncontrollably.

A door of silver light appeared beside him, and Nangong Wan flew out from within. She was immediately dumbstruck by the scenes of unfathomable destruction around her, following which she snapped back to her senses and hurriedly latched onto Han Li's arm to support him.

"Gu Huojin is dead," Han Li declared in an expressionless manner, seemingly feeling no joy at the monumental feat that he had just accomplished.

Chapter 1389: Final Farewell

"Really? That's great!" Nangong Wan exclaimed in an ecstatic manner, then began looking around as if she were searching for something.

Han Li knew what she was looking for, and he sighed in a forlorn manner, "He was assimilated by the Heavenly Dao from excessive usage of reincarnation law powers during the battle."

Nangong Wan shuddered slightly upon hearing this, and a film of tears surfaced over her eyes.

She pressed a finger against her own glabella, then moved her fingertip away to draw out a translucent figure.

It was the final remnant of Gan Rushuang's soul, and it was extremely transparent and feeble, resembling a ghostly flame that could be extinguished at any moment.

Right at this moment, another soul remnant suddenly flew out of a broken object that was hovering nearby.

Han Li was surprised to discover that a corner of the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate had been preserved, and it had been holding a remnant of the Reincarnation Palace Master's soul this entire time.

The soul remnant was just as frail as Gan Rushuang's, and it immediately flew over to join her.

The two of them embraced, then turned to look back at Nangong Wan and Han Li with warm smiles on their faces.

The faint voice of the Reincarnation Palace Master rang out in Han Li's mind: "I have no regrets. Look after Jiuzhen for me..."

Before he had a chance to reply, the two soul remnants had already faded away.

"I will," Han Li answered silently in his heart.

"Is this really a good ending for them?" Nangong Wan asked with a look of sorrow in her eyes as she rested her head on Han Li's shoulder, and Han Li didn't know how to respond.

Right at this moment, his brows suddenly furrowed slightly as he turned to the Devilish Monarch and asked, "Do we really have to do this right now, Fellow Daoist Shi? We've just fought alongside one another as comrades, can we not appreciate this second chance at life that we've been given?"

Nangong Wan hurriedly also turned her gaze to the Devilish Monarch, upon which she discovered that he had already arrived beside the Heaven Controlling Vial and was holding it in his grasp.

"You seem to have misunderstood something, Fellow Daoist Han. I didn't work with you and the Reincarnation Palace Master because I was opposed to his actions. On the contrary, I am very much in approval of his plan, it's just a pity that I didn't think of it first," the Devilish Monarch said, having also already reverted back to his human form.

"You'll have to wait for me for a bit longer," Han Li sighed as he turned to Nangong Wan.

"Alright, be careful," Nangong Wan replied after a brief hesitation.

"I won't be too long," Han Li said as he swept a sleeve through the air to conjure up a door of silver light, sending Nangong Wan back into the Flower Branch domain.

"All of us endure so much hardship and so many tribulations in order to attain true freedom, yet the Heavenly Dao constantly looms over our head, and it's even claimed your left arm. Have you never thought about rebelling against the heavens and transcending beyond it?" the Devilish Monarch asked as he pointed a finger up at the sky.

"Cultivators of our caliber can do anything that we please, as long as we comply with the restrictions of the Heavenly Dao. If everyone strives for power at the expense of the Heavenly Dao, then the entire world would be plunged into chaos. There would be no beauty left in such a world, and what a depressing world that would be," Han Li countered.

"I didn't think someone that has reached your heights would have such a soft and weak heart," the Devilish Monarch sneered.

"Is there no way to resolve this peacefully?" Han Li asked with a smile.

"I'm afraid not. Right now, you are as vulnerable as you'll ever be. If I don't kill you now, I will constantly be burdened with thoughts of what could've been," the Devilish Monarch replied.

As soon as his voice trailed off, he took a backward step, vanishing from the spot amid a burst of spatial fluctuations.

Han Li was already prepared for this, and a burst of time law power fluctuations erupted out of his body, stopping the flow of time within a radius of thousands of kilometers.

Immediately thereafter, he spotted a tiny rift that had appeared in the nearby space, and he lashed out without any hesitation, piercing his sword toward it to send a bolt of golden lightning flying into the rift.

Immediately thereafter, the flow of time resumed as normal, and a resounding boom rang out from within the spatial rift as the surrounding space exploded violently.

Before Han Li had a chance to react, a burst of silver light abruptly descended upon him from above, completely immobilizing him within layers of tremendous spatial law powers.

"And then there was one," the Devilish Monarch chuckled as he made a grab for Han Li's head.

The final attack that Han Li had unleashed to kill Gu Huojin had almost completely exhausted all of his law powers and immortal spiritual power, leaving him powerless to defend himself.

In this dire situation, a massive, golden beetle suddenly appeared before him amid a flash of golden light before crashing headfirst into the Devilish Monarch.

A dull thump rang out as the Devilish Monarch was sent flying back through the air, following which Jin Tong devoured the layers of restrictive spatial law powers around Han Li to free him.

A stunned look appeared on the Devilish Monarch's face as he steadied himself.

He had always known that Han Li had a Gold Devouring Immortal companion, but he hadn't anticipated that it had already become a Dao Ancestor. For whatever reason, this Gold Devouring Immortal hadn't made an appearance at all throughout the entire battle against Gu Huojin, nor had the Reincarnation Palace Master told him about it.

The Devilish Monarch wasn't carrying any severe injuries, but he was also extremely depleted in the wake of the battle against Gu Huojin. In his current state, he was far from optimistic about his chances of securing victory against both Han Li and Jin Tong, but at this point, he had already made an enemy out of Han Li, so if he were to allow Han Li to get away and recover his strength, then he would be in an even more dire situation.

As he scrambled for a way out of this predicament, he unconsciously took a glance at the Heaven Controlling Vial in his hand.

Right as he did so, countless rays of silver light began flowing out of the vial's opening before vanishing into the palm of his hand.

His eyes instantly widened with elation and incredulity as he could feel bursts of tremendous spatial law powers flowing into his body, replenishing his depleted dantian.

"Even the heavens are on my side!" he chortled with glee.

Han Li wasn't surprised nor concerned in the slightest to see this, and at the moment, he was making a rapid string of hand seals with his hand concealed up his sleeve.

Even though he wasn't able to refine the Heaven Controlling Vial earlier, he had established a strong connection with it, allowing him to make use of it even from a distance.

Unbeknownst to the Devilish Monarch, Han Li was currently using the vial to force feed him with spatial law powers, and it didn't take long before he realized Han Li's nefarious plan.

There were wisps of chaotic law powers intermingled in the spatial law powers flowing into his body, and by the time he realized this, it was already too late.

"Han Li, you..."

Those were his final words as his body began to bulge unevenly before being torn to shreds by bursts of chaotic light.

A miniature chariot formed by silver light emerged from the pieces of his body, seated atop which was a silver soul, but before it could flee the scene, it was stopped cold in its tracks by a burst of time law power fluctuations that had surged out of Han Li's body.

"I'm afraid I can't let you get away. This will be our final farewell," Han Li sighed as he strode over to the silver chariot, then erased it from existence alongside the Devilish Monarch's soul with a gentle sweep of his sleeve.

A look of mixed emotions appeared on his face as he surveyed his surroundings, but he quickly composed himself and drew the Heaven Controlling Vial back into his grasp, feeling a sense of comfort and security as he gently stroked the familiar patterns on its surface.

Wisps of time law powers began to flow into his body from the vial, nourishing all of his immortal acupoints and eradicating his fatigue.

He could sense that the chaotic law powers in the surrounding space were gradually receding, while the order was being restored to the Heavenly Dao, and everything was slowly returning to the way that it had once been.

However, the gargantuan spatial rift that had been torn open by his almighty sword displayed no sign of closing.

It seemed to be untouched by the powers of time, space, or reincarnation, and it was most likely going to serve as an eternal reminder of the calamity that had taken place here.

The entire Middle Earth Immortal Region had already been completely destroyed, so there was no way to restore it to its original state, but the immortal region had once been very abundant in the world's origin qi, and that would be replenished once the Heavenly Dao returned to normal.

In another million years or so, all of the scattered particles in the immortal region would most likely reconvene to form a small continent.

All of the other realms and immortal regions impacted by this calamitous disaster were also on the road to recovery.

Chapter 1390: Unmatched Authority

The unrest in all of the immortal regions and the lower realms gradually subsided.

Is it finally over?

Countless living beings across all of the realms and immortal regions were looking up at the gradually clearing skies, feeling as if they had just woken up from some terrible dream.

This was a cataclysmic disaster that had almost destroyed the entire world, but it definitely wasn't the only one in history.

The majority of living beings were forgetful creatures, and as long as a realm wasn't truly destroyed, as long as there were surviving living beings in the realm, then new chapters of history would continue to be written.

In the wake of the calamity, the old equilibrium had been shattered, while a new one was gradually being established.

It was often the case throughout history that the arrival of new eras came in the wake of disasters.

......

In the underworld, Gan Jiuzhen was staring at the boundless river of reincarnation, and all of a sudden, she seemed to have sensed something as tears began streaming down her face.

Right at this moment, a streak of dark red light descended out of the sky before landing in front of her, causing her to reflexively backtrack a few steps.

However, as she caught a clear glimpse of what it was that had landed before her, a myriad of emotions instantly surfaced in her eyes.

The ball of dark red light faded away to reveal the Six Paths Reincarnation Plate, and on its surface was a faint symbol that resembled the face of the Reincarnation Palace Master.

Gan Jiuzhen raised a hand to stroke the symbol on the reincarnation plate, and a determined look appeared on her face as she vowed to herself, "Father, Mother, I will become the Reincarnation Dao Ancestor and resurrect you both..."

......

At this moment, Han Li was standing high up in the sky above the broken Middle Earth Immortal Region, looking straight ahead in silence.

Jin Tong flew over to stand by his side in her human form, and all of a sudden, the space where the chaotic vortex had previously been situated cracked open, following which close a hundred bedraggled figures flew out from within.

The group was led by eight Dao Ancestors, namely Li Yuanjiu, Chi Rong, Chen Ruyan, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun, the rotund woman and the corpse-like man from the Devil Realm, and Bai Ze and the bald man from the primordial land.

The cultivators behind them were split up into three camps, marking their affiliations to the Heavenly Court, the Devil Realm, and the primordial land. There was not a single Gray Realm cultivator to be seen, while True Lord Cang Wu's trio was also absent, and it was clear what fate they had met.

Liu Le'er and Lekima were standing behind Bai Ze and the bald man, while a group of around a dozen Devil Realm cultivators were gathered behind the rotund woman and the corpse-like man, among whom were Shi Pokong, Shi Jingyan, and the late-Great Encompassment Stage devilish prince.

All of them were carrying a multitude of injuries, and it seemed that they had suffered through quite the ordeal.

Han Li wasn't surprised to see them as he had already sensed that they were still alive.

They had been sucked into a spatial storm while the Heaven Controlling Vial was devouring the chaotic vortex, and they had only just managed to free themselves.

No one dared to speak in the wake of the boundless, terrifying aura emanating from Han Li's body.

In the end, it was Bai Ze who took it upon himself to break the silence, and he asked, "What was the outcome of the battle, Fellow Daoist Han?"

"Gu Huojin is dead, and the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array has been vanquished," Han Li replied in a solemn manner.

The primordial and devilish Dao Ancestors heaved a collective sigh of relief upon hearing this, while the cultivators behind them erupted into cheers, while the Heavenly Court cultivators clearly had much more mixed feelings on the matter.

The Primordial Dao Ancestor heaved a forlorn sigh, and a sense of sorrow welled up in his heart as he turned to look back at the small group of surviving Heavenly Court cultivators behind him.

Part of the reason why he had joined the Heavenly Court was due to Gu Huojin's promise to help him overcome the restrictions of the Heavenly Dao, but his loyalty to the Heavenly Court was undeniable, and he had always served with diligence and dedication.

Not long ago, the Heavenly Court had reigned supreme over the entire True Immortal Realm, yet now, this tiny group was all that remained of its core cultivators.

These people had only managed to survive under the combined protection of himself and two other Heavenly Court Dao Ancestors, both of whom had been devoured by the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array.

The Three Thousand Daos Divine Array devoured Dao Ancestors far faster than it did other cultivators, perhaps because Dao Ancestors were closer to the Heavenly Dao.

"Where is the Devilish Monarch?" the rotund woman asked.

"Where is the Reincarnation Palace Master?" Li Yuanjiu asked at the same time.

"Both of them have also met their demise," Han Li replied, offering no further elaboration on the matter.

A contemplative look appeared on Li Yuanjiu's face upon hearing this, as was the case for Chen Ruyan and Chi Rong.

As for the cultivators of the Devil Realm, they were much more surprised than grief-stricken to hear of the Devilish Monarch's demise.

In fact, the devilish princes and princesses present weren't displaying any sorrow whatsoever. If anything, they seemed ecstatic that the throne had finally been vacated.

However, the late-Great Encompassment Stage prince then suddenly put on a grief-stricken facade as he yelled, "Father's death must not go in vain! Gu Huojin may be dead, but his Heavenly Court accomplices still remain! Let's all combine our powers to eradicate the Heavenly Court once and for all!"

His rallying call was immediately met with support from all of the cultivators of the Devil Realm, while Bai Ze and the bald man were also rather tempted by this proposition, but both of them were looking at Han Li.

They knew that he was the most authoritative figure present.

An alarmed look appeared on Dao Ancestor Bai Yun's face as he swept a sleeve through the air to release a flurry of white clouds, which enveloped the Heavenly Court cultivators behind him before he turned to flee the scene.

"You're not going anywhere!" the corpse-like man from the Devil Realm yelled as he set off in pursuit as a streak of yellow light.

He had shared a very close relationship with He Lan, the seductive woman that had perished in the Three Thousand Daos Divine Array, and even though they hadn't become dao partners, the corpse-like man was still extremely resentful to the Heavenly Court for her passing.

He made a grabbing motion in Dao Ancestor Bai Yun's direction, and a massive, withered claw appeared above the latter, giving off bursts of viscous, yellow light and an intensely nauseating stench.

A vast expanse of surrounding space collapsed beneath the massive claw as a yellow spirit domain erupted out of it before rapidly descending upon the Heavenly Court cultivators.

A grim look appeared on Dao Ancestor Bai Yun's face as he stopped in his tracks and prepared for battle, but right at this moment, a streak of golden light appeared between the two of them in an instant.

The giant claw was instantly repelled by the golden light, while the yellow spirit domain disintegrated upon contact, following which Han Li appeared between the two combatants.

"What are you doing, Fellow Daoist Han?" the corpse-like man asked with a surprised expression.

"The True Immortal Realm has just undergone a major ordeal, and it needs to rest and recuperate. Now that Gu Huojin is dead, all past vendettas should be forgotten. From now on, none of the major powers are to seek vengeance or create conflict with others, and that applies doubly so to you Dao Ancestors," Han Li declared in an authoritative manner.

His aura was even more formidable than that of Gu Huojin during his peak as the Time Dao Ancestors, and his voice was heard across the entire True Immortal Realm.

In this instant, all cultivators across all of the immortal regions were struck by the urge to kneel and kowtow in the face of the aura of unmatched authority that had descended upon them, while fearful looks appeared on the faces of everyone in close proximity to Han Li.

"Now that Gu Huojin is dead, our primordial land's vendetta against the Heavenly Court has already been settled. As long as the Heavenly Court doesn't commit any further crimes against our primordial land, I promise that we won't instigate any conflicts," Bai Ze immediately declared.

Li Yuanjiu, Chi Rong, Chen Ruyan, and the rotund woman also quickly accepted this arrangement, while the corpse-like man was staring at Han Li with a look of fear and indignation in his eyes.

"Any objections?" Han Li asked without bothering to even look at the corpse-like man, but his boundless aura abruptly descended upon the latter, causing the space beneath his feet to explode violently.

His expression changed drastically as his entire body began trembling uncontrollably. Unable to bear the weight of Han Li's aura, his legs slowly gave out from under him as he fell to his knees.

"Fellow Daoist Duan Mu means no offense to you, he's merely still grieving over the demise of Fellow Daoist He Lan. Please spare him this once, and we'll do everything you say," the rotund woman hurriedly urged.

Han Li took a glance at her, and his aura slowly receded.

The corpse-like man was panting heavily, and the fear in his eyes had become even more pronounced as he gazed upon Han Li.

"Looks like you already understand," Han Li said in a calm manner as he turned to take a glance at the late-Great Encompassment Stage devilish prince, who instantly stumbled back in retreat as his complexion turned deathly pale.

"I do not wish to kill anyone, but if anyone dares to make any further inflammatory and instigatory remarks like you just did, then this will be their fate!"

Han Li swept a sleeve through the air as he spoke, and dozens of massive, golden vortex instantly appeared in the surrounding space, all of which were giving off extremely fearsome devouring force.

All of the space within a radius of hundreds of thousand of kilometers was shredded with ease before being devoured by the vortexes, and everyone was made to feel like a collection of tiny rafts sailing over a turbulent sea, prone to capsizing at any moment.

Even the likes of Li Yuanjiu and Chen Ruyan were unable to control their bodies, let alone the cultivators of lesser cultivation bases present, and they could sense that the golden vortexes were still only displaying a mere fraction of their power. Otherwise, everyone present would've already been devoured.

Everything within the vortexes was being twisted and warped by tremendous time law powers, and no one was under any illusion that they could possibly survive inside them.

Chapter 1391: Relinquishing the Great Dao

Right at this moment, all of the golden vortexes combined into a single, gargantuan vortex that descended upon everyone, who frantically attempted to resist, but the law powers in their bodies were rendered completely stagnant by the immense waves of time law powers sweeping over them.

Hence, they could only look on in helpless horror, but right as they were about to be devoured by the golden vortex, it abruptly dissipated.

The restrictive time law powers acting upon everyone quickly faded away, while the nearby shattered space also mended itself, and it was as if all of that had been nothing more than a harrowing nightmare.

However, the almighty power of the golden vortex had been emblazoned firmly upon their minds, and it felt to them like the most essential power of the Heavenly Dao.

Even just a casual display of power from Han Li was already beyond what Gu Huojin was capable of at his peak.

They were certain that if they had displayed even the slightest hint of dissent toward Han Li in that moment, then they would've been erased from existence by the almighty power of the Heavenly Dao.

All of the Dao Ancestors turned to Han Li genuine awe and veneration in their eyes.

"You're all free to leave," Han Li declared, and the rotund woman was very relieved to hear this.

She extended a deep bow toward Han Li, then immediately sped away with the Devil Realm cultivators, quickly vanishing out of sight.

The corpse-like man had also departed with them, too afraid to even look in Han Li's direction.

Bai Ze and the bald man also quickly departed with the surviving cultivators of the primordial land, and upon their departure, Liu Le'er took a glance at Han Li, but refrained from approaching him.

Even though the two of them were separated by no more than a thousand feet, it felt like an insurmountable gulf.

Wait for me, Brother Rock! One day, I will stand before you as an equal through my efforts! Liu Le'er vowed to herself as she departed with Bai Ze and the bald man.

In the wake of their departure, Dao Ancestor Bai Yun approached Han Li with the Heavenly Court cultivators, and they extended a collective bow of gratitude toward him.

"Thank you for saving us, Fellow Daoist Han," Dao Ancestor Bai Yun said with a look of genuine gratitude in his eyes.

"I simply didn't want to see any more bloodshed in the wake of such a calamity," Han Li said in a calm manner.

"In any case, I will remember what you did for us today, Fellow Daoist Han. If you need anything from me in the future, feel free to call upon me, and I'll be sure to do everything in my power to repay you," Dao Ancestor Bai Yun said in an earnest manner, then departed with the remaining Heavenly Court cultivators.

"Why are you three still here?" Han Li asked as he turned his gaze to Li Yuanjiu, Chi Rong, and Chen Ruyan.

Li Yuanjiu took a glance at the other two Essential Dao Ancestors, then said, "Now that Gu Huojin is dead, the position of supreme lord of the Heavenly Court is vacant, and I'm sure everyone will agree that no one is more entitled to that position than you. Would you be interested in filling the role? If so, the three of us will lend you our full support."

Han Li raised an eyebrow upon hearing this, and he realized that he had given the three of them some false signals by saving Dao Ancestor Bai Yun.

With that in mind, he declared in a categorical manner, "Don't misunderstand, I have no desire for power."

Li Yuanjiu's trio was very surprised to hear this.

"Many of the True Immortal Realm's Dao Ancestors have perished during this calamity, so all of the immortal regions will inevitably go through a period of turmoil. As Essential Dao Ancestors, the three of you should return to your sects and make preparations to ensure that this period of transition passes as smoothly as possible for the True Immortal Realm at large," Han Li said.

Li Yuanjiu's trio exchanged a glance with one another, and all of them could see their own relief mirrored in each other's eyes.

With that, the three of them departed together, but right as he rose up into the air, Li Yuanjiu seemed to have sensed something, and he turned back to discover Han Li cupping his fist toward him a salute from afar.

Li Yuanjiu faltered slightly upon seeing this, then returned the salute before speeding away as a streak of light, and before long, Han Li was left alone with Jin Tong.

"Why were you in such a hurry to dismiss those people, Fellow Daoist Han?" Jin Tong asked.

Han Li offered no response as he shot up into the air while bringing Jin Tong along with him, and in the blink of an eye, they were already in the Extraheavensphere.

From there, he flew a little deeper into the Extraheavensphere before drawing to a halt, upon which a slight grimace appeared on his face.

"What's wrong?" Jin Tong hurriedly asked.

The space above Han Li began rumbling violently as rays of golden light shone down upon him, and his body was beginning to fade away.

Only after a long while did the rumbling cease, and the golden light faded away, while Han Li's body returned to normal.

"The Heavenly Dao is already beginning to claim your body!" Jin Tong exclaimed with a grim expression.

"I was forced to use too much law powers during the battle against Gu Huojin, and that's left me on the brink of being assimilated by the Heavenly Dao," Han Li explained with a wry smile, and Jin Tong was stunned to hear this.

She had already endured several battles as a Dao Ancestor, so she was also beginning to suffer the effects of Heavenly Dao assimilation, but it was to nowhere near as severe an extent.

"Do you have a way to counteract it?" Jin Tong asked.

Han Li remained silent with tightly furrowed brows.

He had only just become a Dao Ancestor, and he didn't have anything like Gu Huojin's Divine Dao Seal at his disposal, so there really wasn't anything that he could do.

"I have a way to help you escape this predicament," the vial spirit suddenly declared.

"What's your solution, Senior Vial Spirit?" Han Li hurriedly asked.

"Once one becomes a Dao Ancestor, the effects of Heavenly Dao assimilation will become inevitable and irreversible. Gu Huojin's Divine Dao Seal can only delay this process, but it doesn't address the problem at its roots," the vial spirit said.

"Do you have a permanent solution, Senior Vial Spirit?" Han Li asked as his eyes lit up slightly.

"You're very fortunate to have the Heaven Controlling Vial in your possession. The vial was born from chaos, so it can hold any and all law powers. If you want, you can inject your Dao Ancestor law powers into the vial, reverting your cultivation base back to the peak-Great Encompassment Stage, and you'll no longer have to worry about Heavenly Dao assimilation.

“However, the Heaven Controlling Vial has already taken in Gu Huojin's chaotic law powers, so injecting your time law powers into it in addition to that will most likely force it beyond its limits," the vial spirit replied.

"What will happen if its limits are exceeded?" Han Li asked.

"It'll cease to exist, which means that if you do this, then you'll permanently lose the Heaven Controlling Vial, so it's up to you whether you pursue this option or not," the vial spirit replied.

Han Li fell into deep thought upon hearing this.

Now that he had taken Gu Huojin's place as the Time Dao Ancestor, there were no longer any obstacles standing before him in his pursuit of the Great Dao.

He could easily become the foremost figure in the True Immortal Realm if he so wished, enjoying unmatched control over all of its immortal regions and the countless lower realms beneath them.

Wasn't this what he had always aspired for when he had first set foot on the path of cultivation?

However, immediately following this thought came the recollection of the scenes in which the likes of Bone Emperor and other Dao Ancestors had been devoured by the Heavenly Dao, putting him into a state of internal conflict.

The conversation between him and the vial spirit had taken place through voice transmission, so Jin Tong was oblivious to what had been discussed, and she merely thought that Han Li was still thinking of a solution to his predicament.

After a lengthy period of contemplation, Han Li finally made up his mind as he declared, "Senior Vial Spirit, please help me regress my cultivation base to the peak-Great Encompassment Stage. I'm willing to give up the Heaven Controlling Vial."

"Alright, then let's begin," the vial spirit answered, and for some reason, a hint of elation had crept into its voice.

The Heaven Controlling Vial rose up into the air to hover before Han Li at eye level.

Han Li swept a sleeve through the air to conjure up a door of silver light, and Nangong Wan flew out from within.

"I have something to take care of, and I'll need you two to stay far away in the process to ensure your safety," Han Li said in a calm manner.

Jin Tong faltered slightly upon hearing this, but didn't ask any questions as she flew back in retreat with Nangong Wan.

Even though Nangong Wan had been in the Flower Branch domain this entire time, she had been keeping a constant eye on the situation unfolding outside.

She had a feeling that Han Li was about to make a monumental decision, and that left her feeling a little concerned, but she had full confidence in him, so she didn't raise any questions, either.

Han Li pressed a hand against the Heaven Controlling Vial, and the immense time law powers in his body surged into the vial.

A ball of dark green light appeared within the vial, and it was as if it were a bottomless abyss, able to take in boundless time law powers without any trouble.

Han Li raised an eyebrow upon sensing this, and he immediately increased his time law power output, causing the Heaven Controlling Vial to glow even brighter.

Right at this moment, a thick beam of dark green light shot out of the mouth of the vial before vanishing into the space up ahead.

The nearby space split open to reveal a golden space-time passageway, which devoured both Han Li and the Heaven Controlling Vial.

"Don't worry, Fellow Daoist Nangong. With Fellow Daoist Han's powers, I'm sure he'll be able to overcome this problem," Jin Tong reassured.

"I'm not worried. He asked us to wait for him here, so let's wait," Nangong Wan replied with a calm smile, and Jin Tong couldn't help but admire her composure.

Situated within the space-time passageway, there was boundless space-time power raging around Han Li, but all of it was easily kept at bay by the green light emanating from the Heaven Controlling Vial.

"What's going on?"

This bout of space-time transmigration felt different from the past.

"It's fine, the Heaven Controlling Vial has automatically conjured up this space-time passageway in response to your time law powers. I'm now going to take in your Dao Ancestor law powers using the Heaven Controlling Vial. This is the most important part of the process, so don't get distracted!" the vial spirit warned.

Han Li nodded in response as he focused his full attention on channeling his time law powers.

A burst of golden light that was even more radiant than the sun erupted out of his hand before surging into the Heaven Controlling Vial, and a golden line that resembled a crack appeared on its surface.

Han Li's aura was instantly significantly weakened, but at the same time, the ever-present pressure of the Heavenly Dao hanging above his head had also waned slightly.

This was naturally a very encouraging sign of Han Li, and he continued to funnel his Dao Ancestor law powers into the vial.

As more and more golden light surged into the Heaven Controlling Vial from his hand, more and more cracks appeared over its surface, while his aura rapidly declined.

Chapter 1392: Freedom

After an indeterminate period of time, as the final ball of golden light slipped out of Han Li's hand, his aura abruptly declined to the peak-Great Encompassment Stage.

"Thank you, Senior Vial Spirit," Han Li exhaled as he removed his hand from the Heaven Controlling Vial.

The vial spirit offered no response.

Right at this moment, the Heaven Controlling Vial suddenly began to tremble violently, and the dark green light within the vial was also flashing erratically.

Han Li hurriedly sprang back in retreat upon seeing this, and a ring of golden light surged out of his body to ward off the surrounding space-time power.

All of a sudden, the Heaven Controlling Vial exploded violently into countless balls of green light, which converged to form a green-haired child that appeared to have been around seven or eight years of age.

It was very difficult to tell the child's gender from their physical features, and they examined their own body momentarily before bursting into laughter.

"Finally! After all these years, I'm finally free from that accursed vial!"

"You must be Senior Vial Spirit, right? Congratulations on escaping the Heaven Controlling Vial," Han Li said in a calm manner, seemingly completely unsurprised by this turn of events.

"Oh? You already knew about this?" the vial spirit asked.

"I had a feeling that you were plotting something during the lengthy periods of silent cultivation that you underwent, and on top of that, I've become extremely sensitive to the thoughts and feelings of others after mastering the Spirit Refinement Technique. Even though you're not a living being, I was still able to gather some clues during our communications, so I had a rough idea of your intentions," Han Li replied with a faint smile.

"Very impressive," the vial spirit chuckled. "I'm surprised you dared to work with me even after figuring out my plan."

"I knew you were plotting something, but I didn't detect any ill will or animosity from you. On top of that, even though I've regressed back to the Great Encompassment Stage, my understanding of the laws of time hasn't diminished in the slightest, so I'm far from defenseless and vulnerable," Han Li replied with a faint smile.

The vial spirit burst into laughter upon hearing this.

"I should've known not to expect anything less from you, Han Li! While it's true that you've returned to the peak-Great Encompassment Stage, you still have to be careful in your future usage of time law powers.

“On top of that, you can rest assured that I bear no ill will toward you. Instead, I am extremely grateful to you. It was only thanks to your willingness to sacrifice your Dao Ancestor law powers that I was able to escape from the Heaven Controlling Vial."

"There's no need to thank me, this was mutually beneficial for both of us. What are your plans from here onward, Senior?" Han Li asked.

"Now that I've finally been freed from the Heaven Controlling Vial, I'm going to explore the True Immortal Realm, and if possible, I would like to go and take a look beyond the True Immortal Realm," the vial spirit replied in an excited manner.

"Are you referring to the underworld and the Gray Realm?" Han Li asked.

"Your view of the world is too narrow, Fellow Daoist Han. Surely you don't think that the True Immortal, the Gray Realm, the underworld, and the Devil Realm are all that exist of this world," the vial spirit chuckled.

"I know that all of the immortal regions of the True Immortal Realm exist within the primordial land, but I don't know about anything outside of that," Han Li replied.

"The True Immortal Realm, the underworld, and the Gray Realm were all born from the very initial chaotic space, as was the Heaven Controlling Vial. According to the earliest memories stored in the Heaven Controlling Vial, the chaotic space is a boundless place, and it's impossible to know how many realms like the True Immortal Realm it's given rise to.

“How about it, Fellow Daoist Han? Are you interested in exploring this world with me?" the vial spirit proposed.

Han Li's eyes lit up slightly upon hearing this, but he then shook his head as he replied, "I admire your lofty aspirations, but I am truly exhausted after this draining ordeal. On top of that, there are still people awaiting my return, so I won't be able to accompany you on this journey."

"I see. That's fine, to each their own," the vial spirit replied with a hint of disappointment in their voice.

"Senior Vial Spirit, how are we supposed to get back without Heaven Controlling Vial?" Han Li asked.

"That's not a concern. I am the vial spirit, so I possess some of the same abilities as the Heaven Controlling Vial. At the very least, I can take you back without any issues. Having said that, I can sense that there's something that you still want to do. Otherwise, you wouldn't have hesitated for so long when choosing whether to relinquish the Heaven Controlling Vial," the vial spirit said.

An image of Yuan Yao surfaced in Han Li's mind upon hearing this, while the vial spirit waited in silence with a knowing smile.

"There is indeed one more thing that I want to do. Would you be able to help me, Senior?" Han Li asked as he extended a bow the vial spirit.

"You humans are so strange. Why the obsession with love and romance? They couldn't matter less in the grand scheme of things. I can help you fulfill your wish, seeing as you've helped me so much, but I won't get involved in your personal affairs," the vial spirit said, cupped their hands together before their chest to conjure up a ball of green light, within which was a translucent little vial that was very similar to the Heaven Controlling Vial in both appearance and aura.

"This is all that remains of the Heaven Controlling Vial's power. You can use it as a temporary Heaven Controlling Vial and do whatever it is that you need to do," the vial spirit said as they tossed the vial to Han Li.

"Thank you, Senior," Han Li said as he caught the vial with an elated expression.

"Given your current mastery over the laws of time, you should be able to find the right point in time to return to. However, you'll have to act fast because there's not enough power in this vial to allow you to linger in the past for long," the vial spirit said.

"I understand. Thank you, Senior," Han Li replied with a nod, then extended another grateful bow.

"Alright, Fellow Daoist Han, this is where we part ways," the vial spirit said as they waved Han Li farewell, then sped away into the distance.

Han Li was about to wave back, but the vial spirit had already vanished out of sight, leaving him to lower his hand in a sheepish manner.

He turned his gaze to the transparent vial in his hand, then pointed a finger at it, and a beam of golden light shot out of his fingertip and into the vial.

A layer of green light surfaced over the vial, and the nearby space-time power instantly began to ripple, as if it were being manipulated by the vial's power.

Han Li closed his eyes as he sensed the nearby time law power fluctuations through the vial, and it was a feeling that was both familiar and alien at the same time.

Moments later, his eyes sprang open, and the green light emanating from the vial enveloped his entire body as he sped deep into the space-time passageway.

Han Li was completely unaffected by the surrounding space-time power thanks to the green light around him, and he was flying extremely quickly, while the vial was becoming more and more transparent by the second.

A hint of urgency welled up in Han Li's heart upon seeing this, and after flying for a few minutes, he suddenly drew to an abrupt halt.

"This should be about it," he murmured to himself as he swept a sleeve through the air, releasing a burst of dark green light that sliced open the space-time passageway.

A burst of blinding, white light erupted out of the rift that had been sliced into the passageway, and he hurled out from within, upon which he found himself situated in the sky above a vast desert.

The nearby space trembled violently before collapsing in the face of Han Li's almighty aura, and he hurriedly channeled his Myriad Acupoint Tranquility Technique to restrain his aura and law powers to the best of his abilities.

Even though his cultivation base had regressed to the peak-Great Encompassment Stage, his control over his own aura and time law powers had improved significantly.

The nearby space didn't collapse any further, but it was still rippling violently like the surface of a disturbed lake.

Han Li had no time to waste, and he immediately released his spiritual sense, upon which a look of urgency and dismay appeared on his face as he exclaimed, "Shoot! This isn't the Spirit Realm!"

Without the vial spirit's help, his control over space-time transmigration was rather lacking.

The problem was that this was a completely unfamiliar realm to him, and he could sense that the power of the translucent vial in his hand was still seeping away.

All of a sudden, Han Li vanished from the spot amid a flash of golden lightning, then reappeared in a massive, fortress-like structure, residing within which were many scaled beings.

The space around Han Li was still rippling violently, causing the entire fortress to sway and quiver.

All of the scaled beings were greatly alarmed by this, and the ones with the most prominent cultivation bases among them immediately pounced at Han Li, but weren't even able to get close to him.

With no time to waste, Han Li drew the most powerful one of the scaled beings into his grasp before searching their soul.

So this is the Yellow Sand Realm. Thankfully, it's not too far away from the Spirit Realm.

A look of relief appeared on Han Li's face as he tossed the scaled being aside, then vanished from the spot amid another flash of golden lightning.

All of the scaled beings were left to exchange flabbergasted looks with one another, wondering if that bizarre sequence had been a hallucination.

The scaled being that had been briefly abducted by Han Li felt as if they had just brushed shoulders with death, and even though they were unharmed, they were still trembling uncontrollably from lingering fear.

Chapter 1393: No Regrets

Somewhere on the Thunder Continent in the Spirit Realm.

Han Li emerged out of thin air amid a flash of lightning, and his spiritual sense instantly encompassed the entire Spirit Realm with ease.

In the next instant, he vanished from the spot amid another flash of lightning.

......

Deep within the Endless Sea was an island that was only around fifteen kilometers in size, and it was surrounded by ocean as far as the eyes could see in all directions.

At this moment, there was a vast blanket of five-colored tribulation clouds hanging over the island, giving off an incredibly fearsome aura, and hovering beneath the tribulation clouds was none other than Yuan Yao.

Her white robes were flapping audibly in the fierce wind, and she was making a rapid string of hand seals with a solemn look on her face.

There were seventy-two glowing, azure flying swords hovering around her, and the radiant light emanating from them came together to form an azure sword lotus flower that was several acres in size, forming a watertight protective barrier around her.

Additionally, there were several more treasures hovering around her, and there was also a group of several women hovering in mid-air in the distance, observing Yuan Yao from afar.

These women were none other than Nangong Wan, Yan Li, Ice Phoenix, and Silvermoon, all of whom were at the Grand Ascension Stage.

Before long, the blanket of five-colored tribulation clouds had already swelled to several hundred kilometers in size, and all of a sudden, it began to churn and rumble violently.

Yan Li was looking on with a concerned expression, while her hands were unconsciously balled up into tight fists, and her concern was mirrored in the eyes of the women around her as all of them silently prayed for Yuan Yao's safety.

Yuan Yao's brows furrowed slightly as she looked up at the tribulation clouds in the sky, as if she had realized something, and she began making hand seals with even greater urgency, bracing herself for the storm to come.

Lights of different colors began to emanate from the protective treasures around her, illuminating her stunning features, which currently carried a grim yet determined expression.

Right at this moment, a storm of fire descended out of the tribulation clouds, and the nearby air temperature swelled drastically.

The entire surrounding area turned a fiery red color, while all of the vegetation on the island was incinerated, and the ground was reduced to molten lava.

Massive volumes of the nearby seawater was also evaporated, rising up into the air as plumes of white mist, and the surrounding seawater gushed in to fill the void, only to be instantly evaporated as well.

Yuan Yao remained calm and composed, but beads of sweat were beginning to appear on her petite and delicate nose.

She swung her arms through the air, and the azure sword lotus began to revolve around her while releasing countless streaks of azure sword qi to oppose the oncoming firestorm.

However, the firestorm was only becoming more and more ferocious, and after around fifteen minutes, Yuan Yao's complexion was beginning to pale, while her entire body was drenched in sweat, causing her white robes to press tightly against her skin.

The azure sword lotus around her remained as radiant as ever, but upon closer inspection, one would discover that tiny cracks had already begun to appear on some of the flying swords, indicating that they were nearing their limits, and her other protective treasures weren't faring much better.

Right at this moment, the firestorm abruptly ceased, and the scorching heat in the surrounding air quickly dissipated.

It was as if nothing had ever happened.

Yan Li and the others heaved a collective sigh of relief upon seeing this, but the concern in Nangong Wan's eyes only became more pronounced.

Yuan Yao took a moment to catch her breath, then quickly took a blue pill, but before she had a chance to refine the pill, the tribulation clouds up above suddenly converged to form a gargantuan, five-colored vortex, at the center of which was a gaping black hole.

An arc of purple lightning flashed through the whole, following which numerous millstone-sized balls of purple lightning appeared, serving as a precursor to the terrifying lightning tribulation to come.

Countless balls of purple lightning came crashing down upon Yuan Yao, presenting an even more formidable test than the firestorm from earlier.

Yuan Yao gritted her teeth as she made a string of hand seals, injecting her remaining magic power into the sword lotus and her protective treasures.

The azure sword lotus swelled to close to twice its original size while releasing countless streaks of azure sword qi, which intertwined to form a series of sword dragons that rose up toward the descending balls of lightning.

Immediately thereafter, the protective treasures around her also rose up into the sky alongside the azure sword lotus.

A string of violent explosions rang out in rapid succession as the two sides clashed.

The balls of purple lightning were far more formidable than the azure sword lotus and the accompanying protective treasures, and within mere moments, everything was destroyed, while the balls of purple lightning continued to descend toward the defenseless Yuan Yao.

At this point, her magic power reserves had been completely depleted, and a wry smile appeared on her face as she accepted her fate.

Looks like we'll never meet again, Brother Han...

She closed her eyes as she bade farewell to this lifetime.

"Don't give up, Yuan Yao!" Yan Li yelled in despair, while Nangong Wan closed her eyes as a single tear slid down her cheek.

The four women all wanted to help Yuan Yao, but they couldn't even get close to her in the face of such a fearsome heavenly tribulation.

Countless balls of purple lightning crashed down upon Yuan Yao, and the deafening thunderclaps drowned out Yan Li's heartbroken sobs.

The protective spiritual light around Yuan Yao was instantly torn to shreds in a preview of the fate that she was about to suffer.

Right at this moment, an antiquated golden mirror abruptly appeared above her out of thin air, releasing a protective, golden light barrier that encompassed her entire body.

The golden light barrier was able to keep the barrage of purple lightning at bay with ease, saving Yuan Yao from what appeared to have been certain death.

After waiting for a while, Yuan Yao opened her eyes in befuddlement, wondering why the heavenly lightning still hadn't descended upon her, and she was stunned by what she saw.

In her mind, it was surely impossible for there to exist anyone in this realm capable of opposing the might of the heavens.

An indistinct figure appeared nearby amid a burst of spatial fluctuations, and it was none other than Han Li.

Thank heavens I made it in time...

A look of relief appeared on his face as he caught sight of Yuan Yao.

The tribulation clouds in the sky seemed to have been infuriated by his intervention, and they swelled to ten times their original size while releasing an almighty aura that knocked Nangong Wan and the others unconscious, sending them plummeting toward the sea below.

Han Li hurriedly swept a sleeve through the air upon seeing this, conjuring up a gentle bed of golden light that caught them before carrying them to safety.

Immediately thereafter, the tribulation clouds up above began to churn violently, and countless balls of purple lightning that were several times larger than before came crashing down upon the golden light barrier, causing it to ripple violently.

Han Li gave a cold harrumph upon seeing this, then made a hand seal to bolster the golden light barrier, allowing it to keep the might of the heavenly tribulation at bay with ease.

Yuan Yao stared in a slack-jawed manner at the balls of purple lightning that were exploding on the other side of the light barrier, feeling as if she were in a dream.

After a full fifteen minutes, the barrage of purple lightning finally receded, while the five-colored tribulation clouds up above faded away to reveal a long, white rift in the heavens.

A pillar of white light descended from the rift to envelop Yuan Yao, and an ecstatic look appeared on her face as she exclaimed, "I've transcended the heavenly tribulation! But how..."

She quickly turned her gaze to Han Li, then said in a respectful manner, "Thank you for helping me, exalted immortal. May I please know your esteemed name so that I can repay you in the future?"

Han Li offered no response as a faint smile appeared on his face.

Right at this moment, a burst of tremendous suction force acted upon Yuan Yao, and she was sucked into the white rift above by the pillar of white light.

Han Li heaved a faint sigh of relief, then turned his gaze to the small vial in his hand.

At this point, it was already close to completely transparent, clearly indicating that it didn't have much power left.

All of a sudden, a thought occurred to him, and he returned to the space-time passageway using the power of the vial before flying even deeper into the boundless expanse of space and time.

Moments later, he tore his way out of the space-time passageway once again, and this time, he appeared in the sky above a murky sea.

Chapter 1394: Li Feiyu

Han Li stood in mid-air with his hands clasped behind his back and a reminiscent look in his eyes.

The gentle sea breeze was caressing his cheeks, bringing with it the damp and salty scent of the sea.

This place was the Endless Sea near the Heavenly South Region, where he and Violet Spirit had arrived after emerging from the belly of a Rahu.

The spiritual qi here was very sparse, but Han Li's soul felt very comfortable and at ease here, as if it had returned to a familiar embrace after years of wandering and hardships.

This was a sense of security on the spiritual level, and it couldn't be compared with anything else.

Han Li took a few deep breaths, but didn't linger here for long before vanishing from the spot, following which he appeared above a mountain range.

It wasn't a particularly large mountain range, and his gaze was focused on an area formed by around a dozen connected mountains of different sizes.

The area had been claimed by a mortal sect, namely the Seven Mysteries Sect, the origin place of his cultivation journey.

In a small valley near the disciple cabins of the Seven Mysteries Sect, a black-robed young boy was diligently practicing his saber techniques.

The boy was none other than Li Feiyu.

With what little power of the Heaven Controlling Vial that remained, Han Li had decided to go back and pay his childhood friend a final visit.

Li Feiyu's robes were soaked with sweat, and his saber-wielding arm was red and swollen, but he gritted his teeth through the pain and continued to train without rest.

Han Li gave a nod of approval upon seeing this. Li Feiyu's immaculate dedication to his training had always been the primary reason why his saber techniques had been so outstanding.

Meanwhile, the Heaven Controlling Vial was becoming more and more transparent, indicating that its power was quickly running out.

Han Li pointed a finger in Li Feiyu's direction, and a streak of black light shot out of his fingertip before vanishing into the latter's glabella.

Li Feiyu remained oblivious as he continued to train diligently.

A faint smile appeared on Han Li's face, and he was just about to return to reality when something suddenly caught his attention.

A dark-skinned young boy was making his way out of the God Hand Valley with a dazed look on his face, seemingly absentmindedly thinking about something.

It was none other than a young Han Li.

As he followed the young boy with his gaze, Han Li noticed that the Heaven Controlling Vial was laying on the ground not far away, waiting to be discovered.

However, if the boy were to continue on his current trajectory, then he was going to walk right past it.

In a split-second decision, Han Li gave the Heaven Controlling Vial a slight nudge from afar, and it discreetly moved several inches to the left.

"Ouch!" the young Han Li exclaimed as he fell to the ground while clutching at his own foot.

A faint smile appeared on Han Li's face upon seeing this.

Right at this moment, what little remained of the Heaven Controlling Vial's power was finally exhausted, and it faded into nothingness.

A space-time passageway appeared behind Han Li, and he offered no resistance, allowing it to suck him in.

Meanwhile, both Nangong Wan and Jin Tong were waiting in the Extraheavensphere with agitated looks on their faces.

All of a sudden, a space-time passageway appeared nearby, and Han Li flew out from within.

Nangong Wan and Jin Tong immediately approached him with ecstatic expressions.

......

Countless millennia flew by in the blink of an eye.

In the Black Soil Immortal Region, there were hundreds of glowing ascension arrays on an ascension platform, beside each of which stood a guiding cultivator.

The Black Soil Immortal Region was connected to countless lower realms, and occasionally, an ascended cultivator would appear in one of the arrays before being led to a dense cluster of nearby buildings by the guiding cultivators.

Right at his moment, a black-robed young man appeared within one of the ascension arrays amid a flash of blinding radiance.

Half of his body was charred black, and he was currently unconscious, clearly indicating that he had undergone a very rough tribulation transcendence.

Even in his unconscious state, he was still clutching tightly onto the black saber in his hand, and it was as if it were an extension of his body.

The black saber seemed to have been an Essential Immortal Treasure, and even though it was currently riddled with cracks, it was still giving off astonishing saber intent.

The guiding cultivator standing beside this array was a white-haired, middle-aged man with an abnormally elderly appearance.

He swept a sleeve through the air to release a burst of white light, which descended upon the black-robed young man, and the latter's injuries quickly healed, following which he returned to consciousness.

As soon as he woke up, he immediately turned his gaze to the black saber in his hand, upon which a pained look appeared in his eyes.

"My name is Gao Sheng, welcome to the Black Soil Immortal Region," the white-haired man said with a smile.

"My name is Li Feiyu, and I come from the North Wind Realm," the black-robed young man replied as he looked around with an amazed expression.

Gao Sheng faltered slightly upon hearing this name, and noticing the change in his expression, Li Feiyu asked, "Is there a problem?"

"Not at all, it's just that you share the same name as a renowned and almighty figure of our True Immortal Realm," Gao Sheng explained with a smile.

"That's quite the coincidence," Li Feiyu remarked as he raised an eyebrow.

Gao Sheng resisted the urge to conduct divination on the young man as he smiled and said, "You're in luck, Fellow Daoist Li. The Black Soil Immortal Region is one of the most prosperous immortal regions of our True Immortal Realm, and it's home to the True Mantra Sect, the number one sect of the True Immortal Realm.

“I am currently serving as a guiding envoy for the True Mantra Sect, and our sect welcomes all ascended cultivators like yourself. Would you be interested in joining our sect?"

"I've only just ascended to the True Immortal Realm, and I don't know anything about this place, so I don't want to join any sects just yet. May I trouble you to tell me some basic information about the True Immortal Realm first, Senior Gao?" Li Feiyu asked.

"Of course. The True Immortal Realm is a boundless place comprising thousands of known immortal regions, one of which is the Black Soil Immortal Region. All immortal regions encompass vast territories, and the average immortal generally spends one's entire life in a single immortal region. In terms of cultivation base, the sequence goes True Immortal, Golden Immortal, High Zenith, Great Encompassment, and Dao Ancestor, in ascending order.

“Generally, it takes millions, perhaps even tens of millions of years to progress from one stage to another, and Heavenly Lord Han of our True Mantra Sect is a Great Encompassment cultivator, also the undisputed most powerful cultivator of the True Immortal Realm. He's the one that I mentioned that shares the same name with you," Gao Sheng said with a hint of reverence, intermingled with some other emotions.

"Heavenly Lord Han? Didn't you just tell me that that senior's name is Li Feiyu?" Li Feiyu asked.

"Back when Heavenly Lord Han first ascended to the Immortal Realm, he used the alias of Li Feiyu for a very long time, so technically, Li Feiyu is his second name," Gao Sheng explained.

"I see. May I ask Heavenly Lord Han's full name?" Li Feiyu asked in a curious manner.

"That would be surname Han, given name Li," Gao Sheng replied.

"Han Li..." Li Feiyu murmured to himself with a contemplative expression.

For some reason, the name had struck him with a sense of familiarity.

"Hush! Heavenly Lord Han is an extremely revered figure in the True Immortal Realm, so do not refer to him directly by name. You could get in big trouble if you're overheard by the wrong people!" Gao Sheng hurriedly cautioned.

"Thank you for the warning, Senior Gao" Li Feiyu replied as he hurriedly looked around, only allowing himself a sigh of relief upon confirming that no one had been eavesdropping on their conversation.

"It's fine, just make sure to keep that in mind," Gao Sheng said.

"Senior Gao, if this Heavenly Lord Han is only a Great Encompassment cultivator, then how is the most powerful cultivator in the True Immortal Realm? Didn't you just say that there are Dao Ancestors above Great Encompassment cultivators?" Li Feiyu asked.

For some reason, he felt very eager to learn more about this Heavenly Lord Han.

"That's a long story. Heavenly Lord Han is the most legendary figure in the history of our True Immortal Realm, and I can tell you stories of his feats for three days and three nights and still only cover the tip of the iceberg! For now, let's head to the ascension palace to have your identity registered," Gao Sheng replied with a smile.

Li Feiyu raised no objections to this, and he was led to the cluster of palaces in the distance by Gao Sheng.

......

Inside a valley in the Black Soil Immortal Region, there was a small stream flowing through lush, serene forest.

Deep within the valley were several bamboo pavilions, outside of which was a pergola with several figures seated under it. One of them was none other than Han Li, giving off the aura of a mortal with no cultivation base to speak of, and nestled up against his side was the white-robed Nangong Wan.

A burst of tremendous reincarnation law power fluctuations was emanating from her body, and she had reached the peak-High Zenith Stage.

An adorable little girl with her hair arranged into braids was running around them in a slightly unsteady fashion, chasing after several intricately crafted wooden cats and dogs. The wooden cats and dogs were darting around as if they were living beings, and the little girl was thoroughly entertained.

There were two more people under the pergola, namely Daoist Xie and Violet Spirit, playing a game of go on a stone table, while Han Li and Nangong Wan observed.

At this moment, Daoist Xie was seated on a wheelchair, and he was in a similar state to the past Chen Tuan, with half of his body fading into the nearby space, but he didn't seem bothered by this at all.

He was placing his stones down with immense speed and conviction, and his black stones had already taken up a large area at the center of the board.

Violet Spirit was wearing a purple dress, and her cultivation base had reached the mid-Great Encompassment Stage.

Her white stones were also holding their own, staking a firm claim over the four corners of the board to encircle the black stones at the center.

Right at this moment, Han Li suddenly turned to a certain direction as a faint smile appeared on his face.

"Did something happen?" Nangong Wan asked.

"The reincarnation of a past acquaintance of mine has just ascended to the Black Soil Immortal Region," Han Li replied.

"Should I notify Sister Yuan Yao to look after them?" Nangong Wan asked.

"There's no need for that," Han Li replied with a shake of his head. "He was a self-dependent person who didn't like to accept help from others in his previous life, and it looks like he's the same in this lifetime as well. Perhaps we will be fated to meet in the future. If not, then I'll simply let him be."

Right at this moment, the clear sky suddenly darkened as the Black Soil Immortal Region welcomed a rare bout of snowfall.

Han Li stood peacefully in the snow, but not a single snowflake fell upon him.

He cast his gaze through the layers of space up ahead, and he was able to see the entirety of the Black Soil Immortal Region and several of the nearby immortal regions.

Moments later, he closed his eyes as he exhaled, and the nearby snowflakes were blown away like fluttering feathers.